{
  "BT1-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate in battles against Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you declared an attack against your opponent, this card's effect doesn't activate, even if they use another Digimon to block it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if it is being given \uff1cPiercing\uff1e by the effect of an Option card or Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect apply if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it doesn't specify \"in the breeding area,\" the effect doesn't check the breeding area. Thus, it can't meet the requirements of this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved in the breeding area during the current turn, does that meet the requirements of \"If you've digivolved this turn\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved during the current turn using the effect of [BT1-078 Jagamon], that meet the requirements of \"If you've digivolved this turn\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this Digimon's effect to add Tamer cards to my hand that aren't red?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You reveal as many cards as possible from your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when I have 4 or fewer cards in your deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this Digimon's effect count cards that have \"Agumon\" in their card names, even if it's not a perfect match?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"Your recycle bin\" is another word for \"your trash\" -- it's where cards go when they're deleted or trashed.",
      "question": "Q: What does \"your recycle bin\" refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It lasts until the end of the turn you activated it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How long does the 2000 DP boost from this card's inherited effect last?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the +2000 DP boost ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's inherited effect to boost its DP. Later, this digivolution card is trashed. Does the DP boost go away?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If your opponent doesn't block, the effect doesn't activate.  Regardless of what the target of attack is, the effect activates when a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks an opponent's Digimon and has its attack target changed to a blocking opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when attacking an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as it does not specify \"for the turn\" it loses the boost as soon as the inherited effect was lost.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If after activating this effect, the Digimon is hit by \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e so that it becomes this card again. Does the Digimon keep the boost if it digivolves into a new Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give one of my other Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e. If this Digimon is then removed from my battle area later in the turn, does the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e effect also go away?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this Digimon's effect to target [Birdramon] itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give one of my other Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves, does it retain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When your memory drops to 2 or less, it loses the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card's effect, preventing you from performing the second check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 3 memory, and use this card's effect to gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and attack my opponent. During the check, [ST2-13 Hammer Spark] is flipped over, and its -2 memory security effect reduces my memory to 1. Can I perform a second check?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3 on your opponent's side. Since it's the end of the turn, you then lose an additional 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on your opponent's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If I then announce that I'm passing, how much memory do I lose?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If your opponent doesn't block, the effect doesn't activate. Regardless of what the target of attack is, the effect activates when a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks an opponent's Digimon and has its attack target changed to a blocking opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when attacking an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has used an Option card or other effect to give one of their Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect to delete that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the security effect didn't activate, the card goes to the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card performs a security check, flipping over an Option card with a security effect. What happens to the Option card if its effect didn't activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, after all effects and attacks resolve, it becomes your turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, a Digimon with this digivolution card is deleted, and this card's inherited effect moves the memory gauge to 1 on my side. Is it now my turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Turns only switch after all attacks and effects activate and finish, so it becomes your turn after the \uff1cPiercing\uff1e check is performed and the attack finishes.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon with this digivolution card is deleted after blocking an opponent's Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. As a result, I gain 1 memory, moving the memory gauge to 1 on my side. Does my opponent's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It ends as soon as your opponent no longer has any Digimon with no digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my turn, all of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards are deleted. What happens to this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have a Digimon with this inherited effect, your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards can't block this Digimon's attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"This Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards.\" How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, after all effects and attacks resolve, it becomes your turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is deleted during my opponent's turn. Its effect moves the memory gauge to 1 on my side. Is it now my turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect can only be activated after declaring an attack, before your opponent's reaction timing window.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect after I attack with it and resolve all battles and checks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect can only be activated after the attack declaration and before the counter timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect after I attack with it and resolve all battles and checks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect is voluntary.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to use this card's effect when I attack with it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3 on your opponent's side. Since it's the end of the turn, you then lose an additional 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on your opponent's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If I then announce that I'm passing, how much memory do I lose?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you only gain 1 memory, regardless of how many Digimon your opponent has with no digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to gain 1 memory for each Digimon my opponent has with no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's Japanese name (\u30ed\u30fc\u30c0\u30fc\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) has \"Leomon\" (\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Leomon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards, nothing happens.",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards? "
    }
  ],
  "BT1-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digi-Egg cards aren't Digimon cards, so they can't be played with this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digi-Egg in its digivolution cards to my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a separate Digimon, and enters play unsuspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I suspend this card as I declare its attack. If I use its effect to play a Digimon card from its digivolution cards, does that Digimon enter play suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a separate Digimon, and doesn't receive any effects that currently apply to the original Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card from its digivolution cards, does that Digimon carry over any effects currently applied to this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, does that effect activate as the Digimon enters play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It activates immediately after the card enters play. Even if there are other [When Attacking] and \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects waiting to be activated, the [On Play] effect was just triggered, so it activates first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, when does that effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card. Can it attack this turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as you are able to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has a level 4 or lower Digimon card in its digivolution cards, do I have to activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use [BT1-056 Petermon]'s effect to play this Digimon. Can it attack this turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. When you do, reveal as many cards from your deck as is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when I have 3 or fewer cards in my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if multiple Digimon are deleted at the same time, you can only draw 1 card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Two of my opponent's Digimon reach zero DP and are deleted simultaneously. Can I draw 2 cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the deletion of multiple Digimon using [BT2-041 ShineGreymon]'s skill is treated as occurring at the same timing, so you only draw 1 card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use BT2-041 [ShineGreymon]'s [When Digivolving] effect to delete 2 or more of my opponent's Digimon simultaneously. Does this mean I can draw 2 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use an effect to play a Digimon while this Digimon is suspended. Can I trigger \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, moving a Digimon between areas is different from playing it, so you can't draw a card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my breeding phase, I move a level 3 Digimon from my breeding area to my battle area. Can I draw a card off this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs, and the attack ends. If there are other When Attacking effects, \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects, and/or effects activated at blocker timing, they activate, and then the attack ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon, then use this Digimon's effect to reduce the opponent's Digimon to 0 DP. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect has already activated, so the -2000 DP lasts until the end of the turn. [1]",
      "question": "Q: After I use this Digimon's effect to give an opponent's Digimon -2000 DP, my memory drops to 2 or less. Does my opponent's Digimon revert to its original DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You can only play 1 copy from either your hand or trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's effect to play [BT1-047 Tinkermon], can I play 1 each from my hand and trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to play a Digimon card. Can it attack this turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"Your recycle bin\" is another word for \"your trash\" -- it's where cards go when they're deleted or trashed.",
      "question": "Q: What does \"your recycle bin\" refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3 on your opponent's side. Since it's the end of the turn, you then lose an additional 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on your opponent's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If I then announce that I'm passing, how much memory do I lose?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Because the effect grants +1000 DP for every 3 security cards you have, no DP bonus is granted when you have 2 or fewer security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 or fewer security cards left. What happens to this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Choose as many Digimon as you can. The only time you can choose 1 Digimon is when your opponent only has 1 Digimon in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to only choose 1 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give 1 Digimon -6000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It only grants \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, no matter how many security cards you have.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 6 security cards. Does this card's effect give this Digimon <Security Attack +2>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: [When Attacking] happens before \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. So you cannot negate the block, but you can prevent it from suspending itself to block. (See more in Attack Resolution)",
      "question": "Q: My opponent declares a block with one of their Digimon. Can I use this card's inherited effect to suspend that Digimon, negating the block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to add a level 4 Digimon card that isn't green to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have 2 or less memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to add a level 5+ Digimon card that isn't green to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect has already activated, so you lose 3 memory at end of turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If this Digimon is deleted as a result of the attack, do I still lose 3 memory at end of turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Announcing the pass moves the memory counter to 3 on your opponent's side. Since it's the end of the turn, you then lose an additional 3 memory, moving the memory counter to 6 on your opponent's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and gain 3 memory from the card's attack effect. If I then announce that I'm passing, how much memory do I lose?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you only gain 1 memory, no matter how many suspended Digimon your opponent has.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 4 suspended Digimon. Does this card's inherited effect gain me 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't activate during battles with Security Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate during battles with my opponent's Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates when your opponent's Digimon is attacked and deleted during the block, even if it wasn't the target of attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate during battles where my opponent blocks the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the card text says \"you can,\" so you can choose not to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal a green level 6 Digimon card with this card's effect, do I have to digivolve into it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 2 or more green level 6 Digimon cards with this card's effect. Can I choose which card to digivolve into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Even if you meet the digivolution requirements, this card's effect only allows you to digivolve into green level 6 Digimon cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I reveal a level 6 Digimon card that isn't green with this card's effect. Can I digivolve into that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. When you do, reveal as many cards from your deck as is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when there are 2 or fewer cards in my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it becomes your opponent's turn after the attack ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I lose 3 memory from this card's effect, causing the memory gauge to move to 1 or greater on my opponent's side. Does it become my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to use it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's End of Attack effect when I attack with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate it. The effect of [End of Attack] effect can be resolved even if no battle occurs. (See more in Attack Resolution)",
      "question": "Q: My [BT1-081 HerculesKabuterimon] attacks a Digimon and the attack target gets deleted by a card effect before the battle occurs. Does the [End of Attack] still activate even if no battle occurred?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who controls this card chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the Digimon to suspend with this card's skill?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.  If your opponent attacks you with a Digimon, if this Digimon is suspended, its effect can be activated at counter timing even if it it was unsuspended when the attack was declared.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon that has a When Attacking effect that suspends an opponent's Digimon, and uses it to suspend one of my unsuspended Digimon. When they do, does this card's effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This Digimon's [Opponent's Turn] effect triggers at counter timing, before a block can be declared with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e at blocker timing. So, if this Digimon is not suspended during the counter timing, you can't activate this Digimon's [Opponent's Turn] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and is currently unsuspended when my opponent attacks with a Digimon. If I suspend this Digimon to block the opponent's Digimon, can I activate this card's effect to suspend one of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can digivolve into this card from a red or blue level 6 Digimon by paying its digivolve cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How can I digivolve into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The chosen Digimon and all Digimon with the same name as that Digimon are deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's When Digivolving effect to choose one of my opponent's Digimon. Is that Digimon deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Just [Greymon]. Only Digimon with names that completely match the specified name are deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I choose [Greymon] with this card's When Digivolving effect while my opponent has a [Greymon], [MetalGreymon], and [WarGreymon] in play. Are all of them deleted, or just [Greymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The card numbers may be different, but the names match. All of your opponent's [MetalGreymon] cards are deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has [ST1-09 MetalGreymon], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], and [BT1-114 MetalGreymon] in play in their battle area. I use this card's When Digivolving effect to choose [ST1-09 MetalGreymon]. Are all of my opponent's [MetalGreymon] cards deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack with this Digimon when it has a level 6 Digimon card in its digivolution cards, do I always have to activate this card's When Attacking effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to return a level 6 digivolution card to my hand but choose to not unsuspend this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4 memory and above.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I activate their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Each card's effect activates individually: \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e gets applied twice, allowing you to check two extra cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have two copies of this card in my battle area, does my Digimon with 4 or more digivolution cards gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e twice?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your Digimon loses \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, and the second check isn't performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give one of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, which I use to attack my opponent. The card revealed from the first check has a security effect that reduces my Digimon's digivolution cards to 3 or fewer. Does it still have \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4 memory and above.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I activate their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Unless otherwise specified, cards don't lose effects when suspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect activate if it's suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT3-040 Shakkoumon]'s effect allows it to be played as a Blue Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I play [BT3-040 Shakkoumon], does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4 memory and above.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I activate their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It allows you to look at all of the cards in your security stack without revealing them to your opponent. You then pick one of those cards, reveal it, and add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's On Play effect says \"Look at your security stack.\" What does this mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Shuffle your deck without triggering <Recovery +1 (Deck)>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I use this card's On Play effect to add a card from my security stack to my hand that isn't yellow?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Like Main effects on Option cards, you can activate these effects at any time during your main phase. However, you can't activate them to interrupt an attack or another effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What timing does [Main] occur at?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's Main effect if I have a level 5 or higher green Digimon in my Breeding Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can resolve their effects in any order. For example, if you're starting the turn at 1 memory, you can resolve this card's effect first to go up to 3 memory, then activate [ST2-12 Matt Ishida]'s effect to go to 4 memory and above.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and [ST2-12 Matt Ishida] in play. How do I activate their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Like Main effects on Option cards, you can activate these effects at any time during your main phase. However, you can't activate them to interrupt an attack or another effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What timing does [Main] occur at?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's Main effect if I have a level 5 or higher green Digimon in my Breeding Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Unless otherwise specified, cards don't lose their effects when suspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's Start of Your Turn effect activate if it is suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Hatching Digimon and moving them to the battle area doesn't count as playing them, so you can attack with them immediately.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my breeding phase, I hatch a level 2 Digimon from my Digi-Egg deck. I then digivolve that Digimon into a level 3 Digimon during my main phase. If I use this card's effect to move that Digimon to my battle area, can I attack with it immediately?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: While it is possible, this can only be done if you have a Level 2 Digimon in your Breeding Area. If you have a Digimon that can be moved out from the Breeding Area it must be moved out. If you have no Digimon in your Breeding Area and cards in your Digi-Egg deck, you must hatch.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to suspend this tamer with its [Main] effect and not use its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When you pass the turn the memory counter is set to 3 and \"end of turn\" effects will now resolve giving your opponent 2 additional memory and moving the memory counter to 5. (See more in End of Turn Procedures)",
      "question": "Q: I pass turn after using [BT1-090 Gravity Crush]. How much memory does my opponent have?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You have to both draw 2 cards and give a Digimon +2000 DP if possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to only trigger \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e or give one of my Digimon +2000 DP? Do I have to do both?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You have to give the Digimon both +2000 DP and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e if possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to give one of my Digimon only +2000 DP or \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e? Do I have to do both?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has used an Option card or other effect to give one of their Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect to delete that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give one of my originally unsuspended Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Nothing happens, but the game still treats it as if you used the Option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I activate this card's effect against a Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect when my opponent's Digimon has no digivolution cards. If that Digimon later gains digivolution cards, can it attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Nothing happens, but the game still treats it as if you used the Option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when I use this card while I have 1 or fewer cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you would draw 1. Cards turned over by the security check are not included in the number of security cards.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have 4 security cards. My opponent attacks me and I flip [BT1-102 Blade of the True] as the security check. Do I draw 2 cards with the [Security] effect because it is still in the security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of my Digimon digivolves after I use this card, does that Digimon still receive this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After activating this card's effect, I use [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]'s effect to move a Digimon from my breeding area to my battle area. Does this card's effect also apply to that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs, and the attack ends. If there are other When Attacking effects, \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects, and/or effects activated at counter timing, they activate, and then the attack ends. If it's then blocked at blocker timing, start a battle with the blocking Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon with a Digimon that's gained the When Attacking effect from this card. The When Attacking effect reduces my opponent's Digimon to 0 DP, deleting it. What happens next?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play this card, then play a Digimon. Does it receive this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use 2 copies of this card. When I attack with a Digimon, can I activate its When Attacking effect twice in a single attack, giving an opponent's Digimon -4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still use BanchoStingmon's effect if the attack target's DP decreases before BanchoStingmon's effect activates as long as it was 12000 DP when it was targeted for the attack.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have activated [BT1-104 Golden Ripper] and attack with [BT3-058 BanchoStingmon]. If I use this card's effect to decrease the attack of the attack target from 12000 DP to 10000 DP before I use BanchoStingmon's effect, can I give it +7000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The DP value printed on a card is its original DP. This card's effect temporarily allows you to treat the DP value printed on an opponent's Digimon as if it were 3000.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"original DP\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, when a Digimon's DP becomes 0, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to change the original DP of an opponent's Digimon to 3000. I then use [ST3-11 Seraphimon]'s effect to give an opponent's Digimon -4000 DP. If the opponent's Digimon drops to 0 DP, is it deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, effects that increase or decrease DP work as normal, raising the Digimon's DP to 6000.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect has set a Digimon's original DP to 3000. If [ST1-13 Shadow Wing] is used to give that Digimon +3000 DP, is its DP now 6000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, its original DP becomes 3000. 3000 DP and 1000 DP (from the effect) add up to 4000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect on a Digimon that's already getting +1000 DP from an effect, does its DP become 3000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Even after digivolving, the Digimon's DP is treated as 3000 until the end of the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon while this card's effect is active. What happens to the Digimon's DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect that was used last takes precedence.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I set a Digimon's original DP with this card, and then use another card to set its original DP again. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect prevents the reduction of DP. But it does not prevent its original DP from being set to another number.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use [BT1-105 Blast Fire] to decrease the DP of a Digimon with \"DP cannot be reduced\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Level 2 Digimon has no DP and so its DP can't be changed and it will still be trashed.[4]",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's effect to set my opponent's Digimon's DP to 3000 and it gets \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e and becomes a Level 2 Digimon with no DP. Does this card's effect set the Level 2 Digimon's DP to 3000 and stop it from being trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they continue by checking the card that was added to your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 card in my security stack. My opponent attacks me with a Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, and flips over this card during the security check. Its <Recovery +1 (Deck)> activates, adding a card to my empty security stack. Does my opponent continue the security check?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolution costs can't be reduced to less than zero. You can digivolve the card for free, but you can't gain memory with effects that reduce digivolution costs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a level 6 Digimon with a digivolution cost of 3, and use this card's effect to reduce that cost by 4, to -1. Can I digivolve into that Digimon by gaining a memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Since the card doesn't specify breeding areas, the effect doesn't apply to Digimon there.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does activating this card's effect also reduce the digivolution cost of cards in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, can I reduce the digivolution cost of my level 5 green Digimon digivolving to level 6 when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if your opponent's Digimon has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, it can't be suspended with this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses an Option card or other effect to give one of their Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's security effect to suspend that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can either suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon, regardless of DP, or 2 of your opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or less. You can't mix and match.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend both 1 of my opponent's Digimon, and 2 of my opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's effect allows you to pick 1 Digimon and suspend it, regardless of DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or less, and no other Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect has no limit to the number of times it can be used. As long as you keep deleting your opponent's Digimon, you can keep using the effect to unsuspend this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. Can I unsuspend it over and over again every time I use it to delete an opponent's Digimon in battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn't activate in battles with Security Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. If it deletes an opponent's Security Digimon in battle, can I unsuspend it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if your Digimon deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives, you can unsuspend it, even if the opposing Digimon had \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. I attack with it, and my opponent blocks it. If my Digimon deletes the opponent's blocking Digimon and survives, can I unsuspend it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can only unsuspend the Digimon with this effect if it deletes the Digimon it's currently attacking. Other Digimon don't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I've given one of my Digimon this card's effect. I attack an opponent's Digimon with it, and an effect causes one of my opponent's other Digimon to be deleted during the battle. Do I still get to unsuspend my attacking Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-113": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on one of my opponent's Digimon, which they then digivolve. Can it now attack and block?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's security effect only affects Digimon. Your opponent's Tamers unsuspend as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's security effect also prevent my opponent's suspended Tamers from unsuspending during their unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-114": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have less than 5 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT1-115": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. This card's When Attacking effect doesn't depend upon the color of your Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's When Attacking effect activate when I have a Tamer that isn't blue in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. No matter how many blue Tamers you have in play, the effect only grants +1000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 blue Tamers in play. During my turn, does this card's inherited effect grant +2000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot because it was already used. [Once Per Turn] effects are per card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: After unsuspending itself with its [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] effect, I digivolve into a new Digimon and attack with it. The security check reveals a card that \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e it back into [BT1-115 Veedramon]. Can I use the [Once Per Turn] effect of Veedramon again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can use the [Once Per Turn] effect of the new [BT1-115 Veedramon] again. [Once Per Turn] effects are per card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: After unsuspending itself with its [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] effect, it got \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e into a level 3. I evolve it back into [BT1-115 Veedramon]. Can I use its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  A red 2-color card isn't considered a \"non-red card.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect give this card +1000 DP when it has a red 2-color card as a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an effect suspends one of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even when this card is trashed from digivolution cards by my own effect and not my opponent's?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it true that both the Digimon card and the Tamer card must have the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait in order for this card's effect to be able to add them to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait or a Tamer card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a Digimon card or a Tamer card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card and 1 Tamer card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 3 cards. If both Digimon and Tamer cards with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [End of Attack] effect by not performing \"placing all digivolution cards from under this Digimon under 1 of your Tamers\", thus preventing this Digimon from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate unless you can perform \"placing all digivolution cards from under this Digimon under 1 of your Tamers.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [End of Attack] effect if this Digimon doesn't have any digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [End of Attack] effect, can I unsuspend a different Tamer than the Tamer under which I placed the digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if multiple Tamers suspend at the same time, this effect will only give +2000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If more than 1 of my Tamers suspend at the same time, does this card's \"+2000 DP\" effect activate multiple times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if the memory gauge is now at 1 or greater on your opponent's side, you can activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon with [Gammamon] and a [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect into this card. Can I activate the [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card's [All Turns] effect and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If this card is added to digivolution cards by [BT8-084 Kimeramon]'s [When Digivolving] effect, you get [BT8-013 BetelGammamon]'s \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card, but the time to trigger \uff1cBlitz\uff1e has already passed, so \uff1cBlitz\uff1e doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a [BT8-013 BetelGammamon] into a [BT8-084 Kimeramon] and place this card as one of [BT8-084 Kimeramon]'s digivolution cards with its [When Digivolving] effect. Can I now activate [BT8-013 BetelGammamon]'s [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card's inherited effect and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you gain all the effects from every applicable card, even if there are multiple of them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple digivolution cards with [Gammamon], does this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect give me all of their effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect don't affect the inherited effects of digivolution cards with [Gammamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect allow me to activate the inherited effect of a digivolution card with [Gammamon] as an effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's effect and inherited effect mean that this Digimon gains [BT8-008 Gammamon]'s effects twice, so \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e is activated twice and you draw a total of 2 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Due to an effect, this Digimon has another [BT10-011 Canoweissmon] and a [BT8-008 Gammamon] under it as its digivolution cards. If I play a red Tamer, how exactly does [BT8-008 Gammamon]'s \"When you play a red Tamer, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e (Draw 1 card from your deck)\" effect work in this situation?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they only get +2000 DP from this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a [Jesmon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards, and one of my Digimon has [Sistermon]. Do my Digimon get +4000 DP from this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. However, Digimon affected by this effect still can't ignore the rule \"Digimon can't attack on the turn that they were played\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Digivolving] effect reads \"all of your Digimon may also attack unsuspended Digimon and get +2000 DP.\" Does this also affect my Digimon that enter the battle area in the same turn after I've digivolved into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose one or the other.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a [Kiriha Aonuma] in play, do I get to choose either \"Reveal 4 cards from the top of your deck. Add 2 cards with [Blue Flare] in their traits among them to your hand. Place the rest at the bottom of your deck in any order\" or \"return 1 [MetalGreymon] from your trash to your hand\" for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 card with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait is among the 4 revealed cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right. \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e does not activate if you have 7 or more cards in your hand after drawing the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: In order to \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e from this card's [When Digivolving] effect, do I need to have 6 or fewer cards in my hand after drawing the digivolution bonus card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect target the opponent's Digimon that don't have digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. As long as the number of digivolution cards that Digimon had was less than or equal to this Digimon's at the time this effect was activated, this effect stays and it can't attack or block?even if it later gains more digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon was targeted by this card's [On Play] effect, and after that it gained more digivolution cards than this Digimon has, can it now attack and block again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you choose to play cards with the [When Attacking] effect, you must play as many cards as possible?so if cards of both levels are in the digivolution cards, you can't play just 1 of them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has both level 3 and level 4 Digimon cards in its digivolution cards, can I choose to play just 1 of them with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. As long as it was level 5 or lower when this effect was activated, the effect remains and it still has <Security Attack -1>?even if it later becomes level 6 or higher.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon is targeted by this card's [On Play] effect. If it later becomes level 6 or above, does it lose the <Security Attack -1> gained from this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either an Option card with [Plug-In] or a yellow Tamer is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include either an Option card with [Plug-In] or a yellow Tamer, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Option card [...] and 1 yellow Tamer among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both an Option card with [Plug-In] and a yellow Tamer are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the Option card you use has a cost of 2 or more, this card's inherited effect activates regardless of the actual cost paid. However, if some effect (like [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]'s \"Reduce the memory cost of this card in your hand by 1 for each yellow Tamer you have in play\" effect) reduces the Option card's actual cost instead of just the cost you pay when using it, then this card's inherited effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate an effect that reduces the cost of an Option card with a cost of 2 or more and I only pay a cost of 1, or if I do not pay the cost at all by activating an effect that allows me to use an Option card without paying the cost, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect only activates if you use an Option card from your hand or by activating an effect that specifies that you \"use\" an Option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate a \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect on an Option card with a cost of 2 or more that was already placed in the battle area, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there's no target for the Option card when I use an Option card with a cost of 2 or more, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they get -2000 DP even when checked by some other Digimon than the one that has this in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While this card is in the digivolution cards of a Digimon with [Shoutmon], do my opponent's Security Digimon get -2000 DP from this card's inherited effect even when they are checked by some other Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -5000 DP for the turn\" effect and the \"gain 2 memory\" effect when activating this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: [BT9-103 Kongou]'s effect prevents cards from being added to your security stack, so the card is placed in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect and use an Option card while my opponent has activated [BT9-103 Kongou]'s effect, what happens when that Option card's effect has finished activating?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You place this card in your battle area. You can't trash it due to the Option card's own effect, so \"Place the Option card used with this effect on top of your security stack face down instead of placing it in your trash\" doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect to use an Option card that has a \"Then, place this card in your battle area\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect of this card has already activated, so you still place [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] on top of your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect to use [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] and choose this card itself as the target, so I place this card on top of my security stack face down. Does this card's effect still place [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] on top of my security stack after it has finished activating, even though this card has now been removed from the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, all of your opponent's Digimon with either <Security Attack +X> or <Security Attack -X> are affected by \"can't attack this Digimon and can't activate [When Attacking] and [When Digivolving] effects.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"can't attack this Digimon and can't activate [When Attacking] and [When Digivolving] effects\" in this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect apply to opponent's Digimon with <Security Attack +X> as well as those with <Security Attack -X>?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it has \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e as soon as the digivolution is complete, so this card's effect prevents the [When Digivolving] effect from activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play, and I digivolve one of my Digimon into a Digimon card that has \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and a [When Digivolving] effect. Does that Digimon activate its [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to Digimon affected by <Security Attack +> or <Security Attack -> effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of Digimon does this effect's \"Digimon with <Security Attack>\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, <Security Attack> is not canceled even if a Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and <Security Attack -1>. The Digimon is considered to have <Security Attack>, so the effect applies to this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon has both \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and <Security Attack -1> so the values cancel each other out, is the Digimon treated as not having <Security Attack>, and is it unaffected by \"Digimon with <Security Attack> can't attack this Digimon and can't activate [When Attacking] and [When Digivolving] effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. [BT9-015 MetalGreymon (X Antibody)] gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from the [When Digivolving] effect, so after that effect has activated, this card then prevents further [When Attacking] and [When Digivolving] effects from activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolved one of my [MetalGreymon] into [BT9-015 MetalGreymon (X Antibody)]. It gets <Security Attack+1> and +3000 DP with its [When Digivolving] effect, but does that effect activate when my opponent has this Digimon in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has a <Security Attack> effect that is only active when certain conditions are met, such as \"While this Digimon has X or more digivolution cards, it gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e,\" does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect apply when these conditions aren't met?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues. This effect doesn't end or cancel an attack if the attacking Digimon gains <Security Attack> after the attack has been declared. It prevents Digimon with <Security Attack> from declaring the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. One of my Digimon that doesn't have <Security Attack> attacks it, and then the attacking Digimon gains <Security Attack> from a [When Attacking] effect or an effect such as \"when one of your Digimon attacks\".  What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"When... attacks\" effects are not [When Attacking] effects, so this card's effect can't stop them from activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon with <Security Attack> attacks, does this card's effect stop \"when this Digimon attacks\" effects of those Digimon, such as \uff1cRaid\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect add cards that have the trait [Ancient Plant] or [Carnivorous Plant], etc.?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as at least 1 card with [Vegetation] or [Plant] in one of its traits or with the [Fairy]\u00a0trait is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include 1 card with [Vegetation] or [Plant] in one of its traits or with the [Fairy]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect does not feature language that would make it optional, so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with [Vegetation] or [Plant] in one of its traits and a card with [Fairy] in one of its traits are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the other at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The Digimon is suspended by <Digisorption> before the digivolution is complete, so the inherited effect cannot be triggered yet.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve this card into a card that has <Digisorption> in my hand, and suspend 1 of my Digimon with the <Digisorption> effect. Can I activate this card's inherited effect and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to do so.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is suspended, can it itself become the target when its [Opponent's Turn] effect switches the target of an opponent's Digimon's attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect triggers in the reaction step of the attack, so you would switch the attack target after the effect of the opponent's [BT9-055 GrandisKuwagamon] has activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my opponent's Digimon attacks and activates its [When Attacking] effect to digivolve into [BT9-055 GrandisKuwagamon].  After the [When Digivolving] effect switches the target of the attack to one of my suspended Digimon, can I then switch the target of the attack again to another suspended Digimon with this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend this card itself to activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, suspending to declare an attack is not the same as being suspended by an effect even when attacking via \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, so the inherited effect does not activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if 1 of my Digimon attacks with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and I suspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon and one of my other Digimon with [Vegetation], [Plant], or [Fairy] in one of its traits are deleted at the same time during the opponent's turn, does the [On Deletion] effect gained from this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a suspended Digimon with [Vegetation], [Plant], or [Fairy] in one of its traits, can I choose to suspend this Digimon itself with this card's [When Digivolving], gain 2 memory, then unsuspend this Digimon and gain \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 suspended Digimon, does this Digimon gain +4000 DP and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e twice?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this Digimon counts if it's suspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card itself count as a suspended Digimon for this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: BT10-058[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the cards that weren't added to my hand from among the cards revealed by this card\u2019s effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include 1 card that is either black with [Knightmon] or 1 card with the [Twilight]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 2 cards [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. However, if you have a black card with [Knightmon] and the [Twilight]\u00a0trait among the revealed cards and there are no other cards with [Knightmon], you can treat that card as your card with the [Twilight]\u00a0trait and add it to your hand. Any other cards that have the [Twilight]\u00a0trait will then be returned to the bottom of your deck. In such a case, it can be possible to add just 1 of the cards.[2]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If 2 cards that are either black with [Knightmon] and/or the [Twilight]\u00a0trait are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent does not have any Digimon in play so there is no target for \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards), can I still place this card under 1 of my Digimon that has the [Legend-Arms]/[Xros Heart]\u00a0trait when activating this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play this card while DigiXrosing with 2 cards, but there are no cards with [Knightmon] in their name, [DeadlyAxemon], or [Nene Amano] among the cards revealed by the [On Play] effect. Does the \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 4 or less\" effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] names.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon would be deleted, if neither [SkullKnightmon] or [DeadlyAxemon] is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, can I still return 1 level 4 or lower black Digimon card from this Digimon's digivolution cards to my hand when activating this card's [All Turns]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Its original DP is restored by \"can't [...] reduce their DP,\" and it additionally gets +2000 DP from this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Digivolving] effect reads \"all of your Digimon get +2000 DP and your opponent's effects can't return them to hands or decks or reduce their DP.\" If one of my Digimon's DP is reduced before this effect activates, what happens to that Digimon's DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it still unsuspends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [DarkKnightmon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon's digivolution cards but I can't delete a Tamer because neither I nor my opponent have any, does this card's [When Digivolving] effect unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [DarkKnightmon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon's digivolution cards but only I have a Tamer, can I choose to not delete my Tamer with this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Only if it has 3 digivolution cards, but the check will ignore the [On Play].",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has [BT5-014 OmniShoutmon], does this Digimon gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This card's [Opponent's Turn] effect triggers in the counter timing of the attack after [When Attacking] effects have already activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon attacks, can I delete that Digimon with this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect before its [When Attacking] effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can activate.  This card's [On Play] effect activates \uff1cBlitz\uff1e if there are 3 or more digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has 4 or more digivolution cards when I play this card, does \uff1cBlitz\uff1e activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You didn't have 10 cards in your trash until after the deletion already took place, so this Digimon's inherited effect could not be active at the time of the deletion.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 9 cards in my trash and a Digimon with this card as a digivolution card is deleted in battle. The deleted cards, including this one, are sent to my trash, and now I have over 10 cards in my trash. Does \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e in this card's inherited effects activate and delete my opponent's Digimon it battled?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with the [Bagra Army]\u00a0trait or a [Yuu Amano] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include 1 card with the [Bagra Army]\u00a0trait or a [Yuu Amano], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with the [Bagra Army]\u00a0trait and a [Yuu Amano] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only trash cards equal to the number of cards added by one effect. Even if they were triggered at the same time, different effects are still separate from each other, and you can only activate this effect for one of them, so in this case you can count only one of the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and only 1 card in your opponent's hand will be trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my opponent's Digimon attacks, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e activates twice from both a [When Attacking] effect and an inherited effect, and their hand increases by 2 cards. Will this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect trash 2 of my opponent's cards in their hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. This card's effect trashes the number of cards that were drawn. In the example given in the question, after trashing 2 cards from their hand, your opponent would trash an additional 2 cards, for a total of 4 cards trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate after an effect that adds and trashes cards in your opponent's hand so that the result is net 0 total cards gained, like \"\uff1cDraw 2\uff1e. Then, trash 2 cards in your hand\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card was trashed from my hand by one of my effects during my turn. Can I use this card's effect to digivolve one of my Digimon into this card from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 9 cards in my trash when this Digimon is deleted. If this results in my having 10 cards in my trash, does this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate when an opponent's effect trashes one of my Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do, trash as many of this card's digivolution cards as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A \"trash 2 digivolution cards\" effect activates on 1 of my Digimon with 2 or more digivolution cards when this Digimon has only 1 digivolution card. Can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do, trash the total number of digivolution cards that would have been trashed from each of the Digimon that you replaced with this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a \"trash 1 digivolution card\" effect activates on 2 of my Digimon, can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect and trash just this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Trash 2 cards. If this card has 1 or fewer digivolution cards, trash as many as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a \"Trash 2 digivolution cards\" effect activates on 1 of my Digimon with only 1 digivolution card, can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect and trash this Digimon's digivolution cards, and if so, how many do I trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do while this Digimon has no digivolution cards, digivolution cards will not be trashed. If there are effects that activate when digivolution cards are trashed, such as \"By trashing a digivolution card,\" the effect will not activate because digivolution cards were not trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A \"trash digivolution cards\" effect targets one of my Digimon when this Digimon has 0 digivolution cards. Can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. If you can trash the number of digivolution cards specified by the effect from this Digimon, your Digimon with 0 digivolution cards can indeed activate such an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible for one of my Digimon with 0 digivolution cards to activate an effect that reads \"By trashing X of this Digimon's digivolution cards\" by way of activating this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect and trashing those cards from this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you trash 1 digivolution card for each of your Digimon, you do not have to trash your other Digimon's digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates a \"Trash the bottom digivolution card of all of your opponent's Digimon\" effect. Can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to trash just this 1 Digimon's digivolution cards without trashing my other Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this effect chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses which of my opponent's security cards is trashed by this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate it. When a revealed card is trashed from the deck or security stack, it is not considered to be trashed from the deck or security stack, but it is considered that a card was removed from the security stack, so [BT4-097 Kari Kamiya]'s effect can be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My security cards were revealed due to the [When Digivolving] effect of this opponent's card, and 1 of them was trashed. Can I treat this as \"when a card is removed from your security stack\" and activate [BT4-097 Kari Kamiya]'s effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When you play a Digimon card with DigiXros requirements, normally you can only DigiXros with Digimon from your hand or battle area. However, this effect also allows you to DigiXros with Digimon cards placed under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"by suspending this Tamer, you may place cards from under your Tamers as digivolution cards for a DigiXros\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect also allow me to DigiXros with cards placed under a Tamer other than this Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect also allow me to DigiXros using the digivolution cards of a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect reads \"when you would play 1 Digimon with DigiXros requirements\", so if you play 2 or more Digimon cards at the same time, the effect cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 2 or more Digimon cards with DigiXros requirements at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This card's effect can be activated when you would play 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements only.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements and 1 card without DigiXros requirements at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When you play a Digimon card with DigiXros requirements, normally you can only DigiXros with Digimon from your hand or battle area. However, this effect also allows you to DigiXros with Digimon cards placed under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"by suspending this Tamer, you may place cards from under your Tamers as digivolution cards for a DigiXros\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect also allow me to DigiXros with cards placed under a Tamer other than this Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect also allow me to DigiXros with the digivolution cards of a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect reads \"when you would play 1 Digimon with DigiXros requirements\", so if you play 2 or more Digimon cards at the same time, the effect cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 2 or more Digimon cards with DigiXros requirements at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This card's effect can be activated when you would play 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements only.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements and 1 card without DigiXros requirements at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect play a [Dorulumon] card from the digivolution cards of a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect play a [Ballistamon] card from the digivolution cards of a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You place them at the bottom of your deck in any order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the cards that weren't added to my hand from among the cards revealed by this card\u2019s effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play a Digimon and want to place cards under it with DigiXros, can this card's [Your Turn] effect also place purple cards from under my Tamers in that Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect reads \"when you would play 1 level 4 or higher Digimon with [Bagra Army] in one of its traits\", so if you play 2 or more Digimon cards at the same time, the effect cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 2 or more level 4 Digimon cards with [Bagra Army] in its traits at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This card's effect can be activated when you would play 1 level 4 Digimon cards with [Bagra Army] in its traits only.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 1 level 4 Digimon cards with [Bagra Army] in its traits and 1 Digimon card without it at the same time, can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Taiki Kudo] is among the cards revealed by this card's [Security] effect, can it be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can play [Taiki Kudo] even if there isn't a Digimon card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there is no Digimon card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait among the three revealed cards, can I still play [Taiki Kudo] from among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you perform any of this effect you must perform as much of it as possible, so if both a Digimon card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait and a [Taiki Kudo] are among the 3 cards revealed, you must perform both \"add [...] to your hand\" and \"play 1 [Taiki Kudo],\" or you must choose to perform neither.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [Security] effect reveals 3 cards. If both a Digimon card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait and a [Taiki Kudo] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only activate the effect that adds the Digimon to my hand and not play [Taiki Kudo], or the other way around?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Kiriha Aonuma] is among the cards revealed by this card's effect, can it be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add 1 card if only 1 card is revealed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect add fewer than 2 cards to my hand if it reveals fewer than 2 cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait among the 6 revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. For this card's effect you reveal cards, add 2 cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait among them to your hand, then play 1 [Kiriha Aonuma] among them. Therefore, if there are 2 or fewer cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait including [Kiriha Aonuma] among the revealed cards, you can't play [Kiriha Aonuma] because you would have to add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there aren't 2 other Digimon cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait among the six revealed cards, can I still play [Kiriha Aonuma] from among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you perform any of this effect you must perform as much of it as possible, so if both cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait and a [Kiriha Aonuma] are among the 3 cards revealed, you must perform both \"add [...] to your hand\" and \"play 1 [Kiriha Aonuma],\" or you must choose to perform neither.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 6 cards. If both cards with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait and a [Kiriha Aonuma] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only activate the effect that adds the cards to my hand and not play [Kiriha Aonuma], or the other way around?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place this card in my battle area even if I don't have a [Pulsemon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have exactly 3 security cards. Do I activate both this card's \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -12000 DP\" effect and \"place 1 of your opponent's Digimon face down on top of their security stack\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's considered to have 3 cards. Cards revealed by a security check are not considered part of your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent checked my security when I had 4 security cards, and this card was flipped over. This card's [Security] effect activates, but is my security stack considered to have 3 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After suspending 1 of my opponent's Digimon with this card's [Main] effect, can I return some other Digimon than the one I suspended to the bottom of their deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the \"can't be deleted by your opponent's effects\" part of this card's effect still applies whether the target of the option is now a Tamer or a Digimon.",
      "question": "Q: If I use this option on a Digimon which is later de-digivolved into a Tamer, will my opponent be able to delete that Tamer with an effect on their turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Trashing revealed cards from your deck does not count as \"trashed from your deck.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is trashed by a \"Reveal the top X cards of your deck. [...] Trash the rest\" effect, can I return it to my hand with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Because [Jesmon GX]'s [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking] effects cannot be activated due to your opponent's [BT10-042 Venusmon], even this card can't activate those effects in these circumstances.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a [Jesmon GX]  that has <Security Attack> in play, while my opponent has a [BT10-042 Venusmon] in play. If I use this card and target my [Jesmon GX], can this card's effect activate [Jesmon GX]'s [When Digivolving] effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When you would DigiXros, this effect allows you to replace 1 of the cards in that Digimon's DigiXros requirements. For example, when you would play a card with [Shoutmon X4] \u00d7 [Beelzemon] in its DigiXros requirements, you may place this Digimon for the DigiXros instead of [Shoutmon X4] or [Beelzemon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"When you would DigiXros this turn, this Digimon may replace 1 of the DigiXros requirements\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This card can only replace 1 card in the DigiXros requirements when DigiXrosing, not add to the DigiXros requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When DigiXrosing, can I place all of the cards listed in the DigiXros requirements in the digivolution cards, then additionally DigiXros this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Mamemon] name.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [Shoutmon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Shoutmon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT10-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It activates immediately after you place the card with [Royal Knight] in its traits and a play cost of 13 or less as the bottom digivolution card. The placed card's [When Digivolving] effect activates as part of this card's effect, and after its processing has completed, you can declare an attack for this card's \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Digivolving] effect reads \"You may place 1 card with [Royal Knight] in its traits and a play cost of 13 or less from your hand or trash under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution card. Activate 1 of that card's [When Digivolving] effects as an effect of this Digimon.\" At what timing does that [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc] is treated as a card played by this card's [When Digivolving] effect, so it is triggered at the same time as the [When Attacking] effect that was triggered by the attack declaration for \uff1cBlitz\uff1e. The player may choose the activation order for this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect and [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc]'s [On Play] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Digivolving] effect placed a [BT10-016 Jesmon (X Antibody)] as a digivolution card, then that card's [When Digivolving] effect played a [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc], then I activated \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in this card's [When Digivolving] effect to attack. When does [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc]'s [On Play] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc]'s [On Play] effect is triggered, but it doesn't activate because the card is deleted before it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Digivolving] effect placed a [BT10-016 Jesmon (X Antibody)] as a digivolution card, then that card's [When Digivolving] effect played a [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc], then I activated \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in this card's [When Digivolving] effect to attack, and when the [When Attacking] effect deleted one of my opponent's Digimon, my [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc] was deleted by the [On Deletion] effect of the opponent's Digimon. [BT6-082 Sistermon Blanc]'s [On Play] effect hasn't activated yet, so does it activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both this Digimon with [Greymon] and an opponent's Digimon are deleted at the same time, will this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even when a card is trashed from my hand by my my opponent's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It doesn't activate in such cases because [BT7-112 Susanoomon] is trashed by the rules, not an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used [BT7-112 Susanoomon]'s effect to return 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait to the bottom of my deck, then I chose to trash [BT7-112 Susanoomon] instead of digivolving it.  Does this card's inherited effect still activate in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if it does not have the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait, you can add 1 red Tamer card to your hand. However, you can't add a red Digimon card to your hand if it doesn't have the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the red Tamer cards among the cards revealed from my deck do not have the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait, does that mean I can't add any cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a red Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait or a red Tamer card is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a red Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait or a red Tamer card, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 red Digimon card [...] and 1 red Tamer card among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 3 cards. If both a red Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait and a red Tamer card are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and my red Tamer are deleted at the same time, does the \"gain 1 memory\" effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Blocking causes the attack target to be switched, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and my opponent blocks, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Shoutmon] and [Starmons] names.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"This card/Digimon is also treated as if its name is [Shoutmon] and [Starmons]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Shoutmon] and [Starmons].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Blocking causes the attack target to be switched, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and my opponent blocks, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 card with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait or [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait is among the revealed cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. This effect is triggered \"When a card is removed from your opponent's security stack,\" so even when you check multiple cards in your opponent's security stack, it is triggered upon the first check, then you choose whether to activate it or not. Also, this is a [Once Per Turn] effect, so if you activate this effect when a card is removed from their security stack upon the first check, you can't activate the effect again upon the next check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [My Turn] effect allow this card's [On Deletion] effect to be activated twice when I use one of my Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e to check 2 cards in my opponent's security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Other than [Sea Animal], all traits with [Avian], [Bird], [Beast], [Animal] or [Sovereign] are applicable regardless of other words or pluralizations.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"with [Avian], [Bird], [Beast], [Animal] or [Sovereign] in one of its traits (other than [Sea Animal])\" mean that all traits with the [Avian], [Bird], [Beast], [Animal] or [Sovereign] text other than [Sea Animal] are included regardless of other words or pluralizations?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that you can use this card's [On Deletion] effect to play \"1 red Digimon with [Avian], [Bird], [Beast], [Animal] or [Sovereign] in one of its traits (other than [Sea Animal]), and 3000 DP or less,\" and if you have a red Tamer when this effect is activated, you add 2000 to the maximum DP for the \"3000 DP or less\" restriction. For example, you can play 1 Digimon card with 5000 DP or less if you have 1 red Tamer, and you can play 1 Digimon card with 7000 DP or less if you have 2 red Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"For each red Tamer you have in play, add 2000 to the maximum DP of the card you can play by this effect\" on this card mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. It only affects the [On Deletion] effect on this card itself.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \"For each red Tamer you have in play, add 2000 to the maximum DP of the card you can play by this effect\" effect to add 2000 to the maximum DP of my Digimon played with effects other than this card's effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Blocking causes the attack target to be switched, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack my opponent using this Digimon and my opponent blocks, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [OmniShoutmon] and [ZeigGreymon] names.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [OmniShoutmon] and [ZeigGreymon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [OmniShoutmon] and [ZeigGreymon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with [Gaogamon] or a blue Tamer card is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards revealed only include either a Digimon card with [Gaogamon] or a blue Tamer card, can I still add a card to my hand using this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card [...] and 1 blue Tamer card among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both a Digimon card with [Gaogamon] and a blue Tamer are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand and trash the remaining card using this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with [Veedramon] or a blue Tamer card is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards revealed only include either a Digimon card with [Veedramon] or a blue Tamer card, can I still add a card to my hand using this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card [...] and 1 blue Tamer card among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If both a Digimon card with [Veedramon] and a blue Tamer are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is considered to be activating a Tamer's card effect.",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's effect to activate an [On Play] effect, does that count as activating a Digimon's card effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [MetalGreymon] and [Cyberdramon] names.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [MetalGreymon] and [Cyberdramon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [MetalGreymon] and [Cyberdramon].\")"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \"If [Cyberdramon] is in this Digimon's digivolution cards\" effect if it has another copy of this card in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since the card was not revealed by a security check, its [Security] effect can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the [Security] effect of the card added to the hand with this card's \"your opponent adds the top card of their security stack to their hand\" effect be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon can't attack players, so it will attack one of your opponent's Digimon. The attack won't be performed in cases where your opponent doesn't have any Digimon that can be attack targets, such as when your opponent doesn't have any suspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this Digimon is affected by an effect that forces an attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card and one of my purple Digimon or Tamers are deleted at the same time, removing all my purple cards from the battle area, does this card's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] to prevent itself from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.  Until the processing for the 1st activation has resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each immediate-type effect.  In your case, until the deletion of the 1st only [Sukamon] A is resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each \"when [...] would\" effect, therefore the effect that has already activated for [Sukamon] A can't be activated again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have [Sukamon] A and [Sukamon] B with this card in their digivolution cards in the battle area.  When [Sukamon] A would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] B using this card's inherited effect.  On the other hand, when [Sukamon] B would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] A using this card's inherited effect.  At such times, can [Sukamon] A activate this card's inherited effect again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] to prevent itself from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.  Until the processing for the 1st activation has resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each immediate-type effect.  In your case, until the deletion of the 1st aonly [Sukamon] A is resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each \"when [...] would\" effect, therefore the effect that has already activated for [Sukamon] A can't be activated again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have [Sukamon] A and [Sukamon] B with this card in their digivolution cards in the battle area.  When [Sukamon] A would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] B using this card's inherited effect.  On the other hand, when [Sukamon] B would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] A using this card's inherited effect.  At such times, can [Sukamon] A activate this card's inherited effect again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You may look at all the cards in your security stack without revealing them to your opponent.  Then, choose 1 card to add to your hand, reveal only that card to your opponent and add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"You may search your security stack\" mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] to prevent itself from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.  Until the processing for the 1st activation has resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each immediate-type effect.  In your case, until the deletion of the 1st only [Sukamon] A is resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each \"when [...] would\" effect, therefore the effect that has already activated for [Sukamon] A can't be activated again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have [Sukamon] A and [Sukamon] B with this card in their digivolution cards in the battle area.  When [Sukamon] A would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] B using this card's inherited effect.  On the other hand, when [Sukamon] B would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] A using this card's inherited effect.  At such times, can [Sukamon] A activate this card's inherited effect again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon will be changed to a white Digimon with an original name of [Sukamon], but it does not lose the \"also treated as\" effect, so it is also treated as the name or color from that effect as well as a white [Sukamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect activates on an opponent's Digimon with a \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [XX]\" or \"This Digimon is also treated as [another color]\" effect, what happens to my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The name of the cards [ST12-13 Sistermon Ciel] and [BT6-084 Sistermon Ciel] is also treated as [Sistermon Noir], and the name of the card [BT7-083 Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)] is also treated as [Sistermon Noir (Awakened)], but this is a game rule and not an effect, so if this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is activated in one of those cards, its name will be changed to [Sukamon] and its name will no longer be treated as [Sistermon Noir] or [Sistermon Noir (Awakened)].[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is activated on an my opponent's [ST12-13 Sistermon Ciel], [BT6-084 Sistermon Ciel] or [BT7-083 Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)], what happens to that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It remains as a white Digimon with 3000 DP and an original name of [Sukamon]. The gained effect is carried over even if the Digimon digivolves or one or more of its top cards are trashed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect activates for a Digimon with \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [XX]\" or \"(Rule) Name: Treated as having [XX]\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can the digivolution card's inherited effect cause the opponent's \"Sukamon\" to be deleted and not itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated. Until the first occurrence of the first process is resolved, all \"interrupting and activating effects\" can be activated only once each. In this situation, until the first \"Sukamon\" A deletion is resolved, each \"When\" effect can only be activated once, so \"Sukamon\" A that has already been activated cannot be activated again.[4]",
      "question": "Q: There are \"Sukamon\" A and \"Sukamon\" B in the Battle Area, both of which have this card as their digivolution card. When \"Sukamon\" A was about to delete, it tried to delete \"Scamon\" B by the digivolved effect of this card. On the other hand, when \"Sukamon\" B is deleted, you tried to delete \"Scamon\" A by the digivolved effect of this card. In this case, can \"Sukamon\" A activate this card's digivolution effect again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect changes the original name of one opponent's Digimon to \"Sukamon\", its original color to white, and its original DP to 3000.[5]",
      "question": "Q: \"Change an opponent's Digimon to its original name \"Sukamon\", White, DP 3000.\" What is the effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The information of the card you have is also changed by <Rules>. For example, the original name of \"BT15-035 Gelemon\" is \"Gelemon/Numemon\" by <Overflow X>, but if the information of the original card is changed by this effect, the original name will be \"Sukamon\" only.[5]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a card such as \"BT15-035 Geremon\", which has card information in <Overflow X>, is changed to the original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 by the effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The information on the card obtained by the effect remains the same. For example, if the information on the original card EX1-005 Tyrannomon is changed, the original color will be white and the color will be white and green because the effect of EX1-005 Tyrannomon also treats it as green.[5]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to a card such as \"EX1-005 Tyrannomon\" that has been given card information by the effect of this card, but is changed to the original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 by the effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The card also retains its original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP 3000. The effect given is carried over even if that one digivolved or the stacked cards are trashed.[5]",
      "question": "Q: If a card whose original name is changed to \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 is digivolved or stacked cards are trashed by <De-Digivolve>, what happens to the card's information?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The original name \"Sukamon\" - White - remains changed to DP3000, but the information on the card that it originally did not have cannot be changed. If the card becomes a tamer or a Digitama card and does not originally have DP, it will remain without DP.[5]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a card with the original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 is stacked cards are trashed by <De-Digivolve>, etc. and become tamers or Digitama cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose any number as long as the total play costs add up to 7 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: From the cards revealed with this card's effect, can I choose cards whose total play costs add up to less than 7 on purpose?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. This effect is activated every time a security card is checked.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon with <Security Attack+1> would check 2 security cards, can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -4000 DP\" twice?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also includes the [Leomon] name.  This card can be chosen for text that specifies cards with [Leomon].  This card can't be chosen for text that specifies cards with the name [Leomon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"Treat this card/Digimon as if it also has [Leomon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Leomon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, for each green or black Tamer you have in play, this effect suspends 1 of your opponent's Digimon, but only 1 of your opponent's suspended Digimon can't unsuspend during your opponent's next unsuspend phase. You can choose from your opponent's already suspended Digimon for the target Digimon in addition to the Digimon suspended by this card\u2019s effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card\u2019s effect when I have 2 green or black Tamer cards, do 2 of my opponent's Digimon suspend and then can't unsuspend during my opponent's next unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose any of the cards as long as the total play costs add up to 10 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I intentionally choose cards with lower costs from among the cards revealed by this card\u2019s effect so that the total play costs add up to less than 10?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. A 2-color Tamer still counts as 1 Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to reveal 2 cards from the top of my deck when I have a green and black 2-color Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to trash 3 cards in my hand even when my opponent has 2 or fewer Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. A 2-color Tamer still counts as 1 Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to reduce the digivolution cost by 2 when I have a green and black 2-color Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can place 1 [Vemmon] as a digivolution card even when none of those cards are among the revealed cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are no [Snatchmon], [Destromon], [Galactimon], or [Fusionize] among the cards revealed by this card's effect, can I place 1 [Vemmon] under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a specific rule that allows you to include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"You can include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck\" has been changed to \"(Rule) You can include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with [Greymon] or a black Tamer card is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards revealed only include either a Digimon card with [Greymon] or a black Tamer, can I still add a card to my hand using this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] and 1 black Tamer card among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both a Digimon card with [Greymon] and a black Tamer are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck using this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Numemon] name.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [Numemon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Numemon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 4-5 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"When a Digimon becomes unsuspended\" inherited effect activate even when my opponent's Digimon becomes unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [DarkKnightmon] and [Tuwarmon] names.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"This card/Digimon is also treated as [DarkKnightmon] and [Tuwarmon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [DarkKnightmon] and [Tuwarmon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add 1 card with the [Cyborg]/[Machine]\u00a0trait to your hand or place it under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution card even when no [Analogman] is among the revealed cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there is no [Analogman] among the cards revealed by this card's effect, can I add 1 card with the [Cyborg]/[Machine]\u00a0trait to my hand or place it under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there's no [Machinedramon] in my hand, can I place 1 of my [Analogman] at the bottom of its owner's deck with this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.   If Digimon did not have the highest DP when the attack was declared, this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon without the highest DP attacks, and by using a [When Attacking] effect to increase its DP, it becomes the Digimon with the highest DP. In such cases, can the target of the attack be switched to this Digimon with this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"When a Digimon becomes unsuspended\" effect activate even when my opponent's Digimon becomes unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon card with DigiXros requirements is played by an effect and this card is placed in the digivolution cards by a DigiXros, does this card's inherited effect activate when a Digimon card with this card in its digivolution cards is played by an effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If its DP is reduced to 0 and it is deleted when played, you can't activate the [On Play] effect. Also, the \"By deleting this Digimon\" condition is not fulfilled when this Digimon is deleted by another effect or rule.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card was played, an already activated DP-reducing effect reduced this card's DP to 0 and deleted it. In such cases, can I activate the [On Play] effect by considering the \"By deleting this Digimon\" condition to be fulfilled?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is not deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an effect would delete this Digimon and one of my [Yuu Amano] cards at the same time, does this card\u2019s effect prevent my [Yuu Amano] card from being deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return the trashed card from my trash to my hand if 1 [Mirei Mikagura] or 1 card with the [Angel], [Archangel], or [Fallen Angel]\u00a0trait is trashed from my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's effect, can a blue level 3 Digimon card be played from one of my purple Digimon's digivolution cards, or a purple level 3 Digimon card be played from one of my blue Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. Since this card was not a digivolution card when [EX3-023 Plesiomon]'s effect played a level 4 Digimon card from digivolution cards, its inherited effect can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: [EX3-023 Plesiomon]'s [When Digivolving] effect plays a level 4 Digimon card from digivolution cards and places this card under it as a digivolution card from the hand. At this timing, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.  In addition to Digimon from the hand or battle area, you may also place cards from the trash as digivolution cards for a DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"When you would play this card, you can also place cards from your trash in digivolution cards for a DigiXros\" mean that you can place cards from your hand, batle area and trash as digivolution cards for a DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If there are 2 or more cards that can be targeted in your trash, you must either play 2 of them or none.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is played by DigiXrosing, if there's 2 or more purple level 4 or lower Digimon cards or level 4 or lower Digimon cards with the [Xros Heart]\u00a0trait, can I play only 1 instead?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No you can't.  First you must add 1 or 2 cards with [Bagra Army] in one of their traits from your trash to your hand, and then place 1 or 2 cards with the [Bagra Army]\u00a0trait under one of your Tamers. If you don't add cards to your hand, you can't place cards under your Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [On Play] effect, can I place cards under 1 of my Tamers if I didn't add cards with [Bagra Army] in one of their traits from the trash to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, if my opponent has 2 or more Digimon in play, does this card's effect to look at your opponent's hand and trash 1 card in it activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, a Digimon's digivolution cards are trashed when it is placed as another Digimon's digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I perform \"place 1 of your opponent's Digimon under 1 of your opponent's other Digimon as its bottom digivolution card\" in this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect, are the digivolution cards that were under my opponent's Digimon placed along with that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Other than [Sea Animal], all traits with [Avian], [Bird], [Beast], [Animal] or [Sovereign] are applicable regardless of other words or pluralizations.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"with [Avian], [Bird], [Beast], [Animal] or [Sovereign] in one of its traits (other than [Sea Animal])\" mean that all traits with the [Avian], [Bird], [Beast], [Animal] or [Sovereign] text other than [Sea Animal] are included regardless of other words or pluralizations?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate if it becomes your opponent's turn before your main phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect if an effect at the start of my turn or during my unsuspend phase or breeding phase causes the memory counter to move to my opponent's side and it becomes my opponent's turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate if it becomes your opponent's turn before your main phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect if an effect at the start of my turn or during my unsuspend phase or breeding phase causes the memory counter to move to my opponent's side and it becomes my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if your opponent declared an attack against you when declaring their attack target, you can still switch the attack target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon attacks me directly, and activates the effect of \uff1cRaid\uff1e to switch the attack to a Digimon. In such cases, can I still switch the attack target with this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't affected.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon is affected by this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" effect. Is it affected by the [Security] effect of my opponent's Option cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" effect expires while the effect of [EX1-068 Ice Wall!] is still active, so that Digimon will have [EX1-068 Ice Wall!]'s \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses [EX1-068 Ice Wall!] while one of my Digimon is affected by this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" effect. If it becomes my next turn and this card's effect expires, will that Digimon have the \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since that Digimon isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards anymore, [EX1-068 Ice Wall!]'s \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses [EX1-068 Ice Wall!] and I activate this card's \"isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" effect on one of my Digimon that has \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\". What happens with the \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect means that, if one of your Digimon digivolves into [Angewomon], you may play [LadyDevimon] from your hand without paying the cost, or if one of your Digimon digivolves into [LadyDevimon], you may play [Angewomon] from your hand without paying the cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [Your Turn] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play [Angewomon] if one of my Digimon digivolves into [Angewomon], or [LadyDevimon] if one of my Digimon digivolves into [LadyDevimon] with this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate if it becomes your opponent's turn before your main phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect if an effect at the start of my turn or during my unsuspend phase or breeding phase causes the memory counter to move to my opponent's side and it becomes my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When you play a Digimon card with DigiXros requirements, normally you can only DigiXros with Digimon from your hand or battle area. However, this effect also allows you to DigiXros with Digimon cards placed under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"by suspending this Tamer, you may place cards from under your Tamers as digivolution cards for a DigiXros\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect also allow me to DigiXros with cards placed under a Tamer other than this Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect also allow me to DigiXros using the digivolution cards of a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since this card's effect reads \"When you would play 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements\", if you would play 2 or more Digimon cards at the same time, you can't activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when I would play 2 or more Digimon with DigiXros requirements with an effect at the same time?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No you can't.  This effect can only be activated when you would play 1 Digimon card with DigiXros conditions.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when I play 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements and other Digimon cards without DigiXros requirements with an effect at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect will activate since a Digimon with [Seadramon] was played earlier.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't have any Digimon with [Seadramon], and use this card's effect to play a Digimon card Seadramon] in its name from the digivolution cards of one of my blue Digimon, does the effect to \"return 1 of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon to the bottom of its owner's deck\" activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The effect reads \"Suspend 2 of your opponent's Digimon\", so suspend 2 as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend only 1 of my opponent's Digimon, or none of their Digimon, if I use this card's effect while they have 2 or more Digimon that can be suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No you can't[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack one of my opponent's unsuspended Digimon with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place 1 [Vemmon] under one of my Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's effect even if there's no [Destromon] or [Galacticmon] in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose cards so that the combined play cost is lower than the play cost of 1 of my Digimon with [Greymon] in their name on purpose with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with one of my Digimon with [Greymon] that is suspended or was played this turn with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the [When Attacking] effect of my Digimon with [Greymon] activates when it attacks with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's effect only allows you to attack a player.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack one of my opponent's Digimon instead of a player with one of my Digimon with [Greymon] that has the effect \"This Digimon can also attack your opponent's unsuspended Digimon\" with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If a Digimon is placed in the digivolved source of another Digimon, the digivolved card it had will be trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"place an opponent's Digimon under another opponent's Digimon's Digimon\" inherited effect also place the Digivolution card owned by the opponent's Digimon being placed under the Digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) is not considered an effect where a Digimon would leave the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect and place 4 [Vemmon] at the bottom of their owners' decks to prevent it from leaving the battle area when this Digimon is affected by a \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"When this Digimon would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate it when this Digimon is affected by effect that moves it to one of those areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect and place 4 [Vemmon] at the bottom of their owners' decks to prevent it from leaving the battle area when this Digimon is returned to my deck or placed in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate if it becomes your opponent's turn before your main phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect if an effect at the start of my turn or during my unsuspend phase or breeding phase causes the memory counter to move to my opponent's side and it becomes my opponent's turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT11-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can. In such cases, even if there's no [When Digivolving] effect to target with this effect, this card still becomes suspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon with [Veedramon] without a [When Digivolving] effect becomes suspended, can I suspend this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with [Veedramon] attacks and becomes suspended. After that, it digivolves into a different Digimon with the [When Attacking] effect of [BT9-109 X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. If the card it digivolved into has a [When Digivolving], if I suspend this card with this card's [All Turns] effect, can I activate the [When Digivolving] effect of the card it digivolved into?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Digivolution into [BT9-017 Gallantmon (X Antibody)] is possible. Digivolution into [BT5-081 ChaosGallantmon] isn't possible because the digivolution requirements aren't met. [EX2-073 Gallantmon Crimson Mode] is level 7, so digivolution isn't possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect doesn't delete any of my opponent's Digimon, does the effect let it digivolve into [BT5-081 ChaosGallantmon], [BT9-017 Gallantmon (X Antibody)], or [EX2-073 Gallantmon Crimson Mode]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks and is deleted in a battle during that attack, does this card's [End of Attack] inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with [Imperialdramon] or the [Free]\u00a0trait, or a Tamer card with [Davis Motomiya] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed by this card's effect only include 1 Digimon card with [Imperialdramon] or the [Free]\u00a0trait, or 1 Tamer card with [Davis Motomiya] among them, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] and 1 Tamer card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed by this card's effect include both a Digimon card with [Imperialdramon] or the [Free]\u00a0trait, and a Tamer card with [Davis Motomiya] among them, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand and return the rest to the bottom of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's a Tamer card with [Davis Motomiya], so you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 3 cards. If a [BT8-088 Davis Motomiya & Ken Ichijoji] is among the cards revealed, can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a Tamer card in its digivolution cards, does that Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this card's effect causes a Tamer card to end up in its digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve onto a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack during the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Digimon cannot attack on the turn they were played, and because the Tamer was played that turn, the restriction still applies to the Digimon that digivolved onto it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: On the turn I have played a Tamer, I digivolve it into this Digimon. During that same turn, can this Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a Tamer card in its digivolution cards, does that Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this card's effect causes a Tamer card to end up in its digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve onto a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack during the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Digimon cannot attack on the turn they were played, and because the Tamer was played that turn, the restriction still applies to the Digimon that digivolved onto it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: On the turn I have played a Tamer, I digivolve it into this Digimon. During that same turn, can this Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate when my opponent's Digimon activates <Digi-Burst>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They're trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's effect places 1 of my other blue Digimon as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card, what happens to that Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It's not being trashed by the effect, it's being trashed because of the rules, so [BT9-109 X Antibody] does still get trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's effect places 1 of my other blue Digimon as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card, if that Digimon has [BT9-109 X Antibody] in its digivolution cards, what happens to that card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. This effect reads \"While it has 2 or more colors in its digivolution cards, it gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and \uff1cBlocker\uff1e,\" so the gained effect doesn't change even if there are 3 or more colors in the digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When there are 3 or more colors in this card's digivolution cards, does it gain <Security Attack +2> from its [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with [Greymon] or [Marcus Damon] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include a Digimon card with [Greymon] or [Marcus Damon], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card [...] and 1 [Marcus Damon] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a Digimon card with [Greymon] and [Marcus Damon] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the other cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to Digimon affected by <Security Attack +> or <Security Attack -> effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of Digimon does this effect's \"Digimon with <Security Attack>\" refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to Digimon affected by <Security Attack +> or <Security Attack -> effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of Digimon does this effect's \"Digimon with <Security Attack>\" refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Tamers cannot attack, so a [Marcus Damon] Tamer in the battle area can't attack. However, if an effect such as the one on [BT12-092 Marcus Damon] causes it to be treated as a Digimon, then it is able to attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can my [Marcus Damon] Tamer, that gains +3000 DP and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card's [Your Turn] effect, attack as just a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, effects that target Digimon can't target a [Marcus Damon] that's just a Tamer in the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an effect that targets Digimon with 3000 DP or less is activated, can a [Marcus Damon] that gains +3000 DP from this card's [Your Turn] effect be chosen as a target for that effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect is not an effect with a set duration such as \"for the turn,\" so the effect is lost unless the Digimon's name is still [Marcus Damon] after digivolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My [Marcus Damon] digivolved into a Digimon with a \"you may digivolve as if your Tamer is a level 3 Digimon\" effect. In such cases, what happens to the +3000 DP/\uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e that [Marcus Damon] gained from this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamers can't have DP, so it's not treated as a Tamer with 3000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is a [Marcus Damon] that gained +3000 DP by this card's [Your Turn] effect treated as a Tamer with 3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to Digimon affected by <Security Attack +> or <Security Attack -> effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of Digimon does this effect's \"Digimon with <Security Attack>\" refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Imperialdramon] or the [Free]\u00a0trait or a card with [Ken Ichijoji] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed by this card's effect only include a Digimon card with [Imperialdramon] or the [Free]\u00a0trait, or a Tamer card with [Ken Ichijoji] among them, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] and 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed by this card's effect include both a Digimon card with [Imperialdramon] or the [Free]\u00a0trait, and a Tamer card with [Ken Ichijoji] among them, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand and return the others to the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The condition for this card's [On Play] effect is \"By revealing up to 3 Tamer cards in your hand and placing them at the bottom of your deck in any order,\" and you can't perform only a part of it. If you reveal 3 Tamer cards from your hand, you must return all of them to the bottom of your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [On Play] effect, can I reveal 3 Tamer cards from my hand but not return them to the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: There is no target for the attack, so the effect ends without an attack being performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to this card's [When Digivolving] effect if my opponent doesn't have any Digimon that can be attacked?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: There is no target for the attack, so the effect ends without an attack being performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to this card's [When Digivolving] effect if my opponent doesn't have any Digimon that can be attacked?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Count the total number of you and your opponent's suspended Digimon and suspended Tamers, then gain 1 memory for every 2. For example, if you have 1 suspended Digimon and 1 suspended Tamer while your opponent has 2 suspended Digimon, the total would be 4 and you gain 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I count \"for every 2 suspended Digimon and/or Tamers, gain 1 memory\" for this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right. Other [BT12-057 Quartzmon]'s [Other than this Digimon or all Digimon and Tamers don't unsuspend.]'s effect will also activate, so if there's more than 1 of this Digimon in play, none of them will be able to unsuspended during the unsuspend phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 or more of this Digimon in the battle area, or if me and my opponent have 1 or more each, does this Digimon itself become unable to unsuspend during the unsuspend phase because of this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it unsuspends. DNA Digivolution treats unsuspended Digimon because of the DNA Digivolution as new Digimon in the battle area. This card's effect does not affect it since it's not treated as a suspended Digimon becoming unsuspended[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, and 2 suspended Digimon perform DNA Digivolution, will that Digimon unsuspend?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's right. Even with the \"Unsuspend this...\" effect, they don't unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, do other Digimon or Tamers with effects such as \uff1cReboot\uff1e or \"Unsuspend this...\" become unable to unsuspend?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with [Greymon] or 1 Tamer card with [Tai Kamiya] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include a Digimon card with [Greymon] or 1 Tamer card with [Tai Kamiya], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card [...] and 1 Tamer card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a Digimon card with [Greymon] and a Tamer card with [Tai Kamiya] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and return the other cards to the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, those are Tamer cards with [Tai Kamiya], so you can add one to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If [BT5-093 Tai Kamiya & Matt Ishida], [BT9-084 Tai Kamiya & Kari Kamiya], or [P-012 Tai Kamiya (V-Tamer)] is one of the cards revealed, can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a Tamer card in its digivolution cards, does that Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this card's effect causes a Tamer card to end up in its digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve onto a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack during the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Digimon cannot attack on the turn they were played, and because the Tamer was played that turn, the restriction still applies to the Digimon that digivolved onto it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: On the turn I have played a Tamer, I digivolve it into this Digimon. During that same turn, can this Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, in such cases the \"can't attack\" effect prevents making the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose an opponent's Digimon with a \"can't attack\" effect as the target when I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the start of your opponent's main phase, the effects gained from this card's effect are triggered at the same time, and your opponent determines which one activates first. After effects such as [When Attacking] have activated, and before the counter timing occurs, it is time to activate the effect of the 2nd Digimon that was pending activation. However, since the 1st Digimon is already attacking, the effect ends without an attack made. As a result, only the Digimon whose effect was activated first can attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates twice and 2 of my opponent's Digimon gain the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can still choose a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" Digimon as a target for the effect. As soon as it becomes your opponent's turn, that opposing Digimon loses the \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect and is affected by this card's effect. As a result, the attack occurs at the start of the main phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated on an opponent's Digimon with an \"[Opponent's Turn] This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a Tamer card in its digivolution cards, does that Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this card's effect causes a Tamer card to end up in its digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve onto a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack during the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Digimon cannot attack on the turn they were played, and because the Tamer was played that turn, the restriction still applies to the Digimon that digivolved onto it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: On the turn I have played a Tamer, I digivolve it into this Digimon. During that same turn, can this Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, blocking causes the attack target to switch, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks my opponent, then my opponent blocks. Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate even when the attack whose target is switched was made by one of my other Digimon or an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, blocking causes the attack target to switch, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacks my opponent, then my opponent blocks. Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate even when the attack whose target is switched was made by one of my other Digimon or an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards revealed by this card's effect include a Digimon card with a play cost of 7 or more that could be reduced to 6 or less by another effect, can I play that card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. [1]",
      "question": "Q: \"This Digimon has [EX3-013 Chaosdramon] in its digivolution cards. and then an effect attempts to delete it. Is it possible to first activate this card's \"\"When this Digimon would be deleted, trash the top card of your opponent's security stack\"\" effect, trashing a security card from the opponent's security stack, and then activate [EX3-13 Chaosdramon]'s \"\"you may trash 2 level 5 cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards to prevent it from leaving play\"\" effect and prevent the deletion?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. This card's \"\"This Digimon gains all effects of [Machinedramon] and [Chaosdramon] cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards\"\" effect is an [All Turns] effect, so it is active as soon as the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, the [When Digivolving] effect is gained and triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card digivolves from [EX3-013 Chaosdramon], it gains all of the effects of the [Chaosdramon] in its digivolution cards. Does that mean [EX3-013 Chaosdramon]'s [On Play][When Digivolving] effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If [Wizardmon] or [X Antibody] are in the digivolution cards, this Digimon gains \uff1cBlocker\uff1e instead. You can't activate \"\"Trash the top 2 cards of your deck\"\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate \"Trash the top 2 cards of your deck.\" of this card's [When Digivolving] effect if [Wizardmon] or [X Antibody] are in its digivolution cards when digivolving into this card\u00a0?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 2-3 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You count each of your Tamers with different colors. If you have a 2-color Tamer card, it counts as 1 Tamer with a different color as long as 1 of the colors is different from your other Tamers. For example, if you have 1 red Tamer, 1 blue/yellow Tamer, and 1 red/yellow Tamer, you can count them as 1 red Tamer, 1 blue Tamer, and 1 yellow Tamer for a total of 3.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"For each Tamer you have in play with a different color\" condition in this card's [When Digivolving] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack even when suspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has 4 or more digivolution cards, does its [End of Your Turn] effect allow it to attack even if it is suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No you can't. A Digimon with the \"isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect can be selected as the destination of the Digimon that would be placed as a digivolution card, but in that case it can't be placed as the Digimon isn't affected by the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to place 1 of my opponent's Digimon as a digivolution card of another of their Digimon with the \"isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect has already activated, so even without [Sparrowmon] in the digivolution cards, the effect will continue until the end of your opponent's turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"I activated this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect and all of my Digimon gained \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and can't be returned to hands or decks. If [Sparrowmon] is then trashed from this card's digivolution cards, what happens to the effects that my Digimon gained?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT12-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If the DP is not 10000 or more when the effect activates, you can't gain 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacked the player while it had 10000 DP, then a security check was performed. If the [Security] effect on the flipped card reduces the DP to 9000 or less, do I still activate this card's \"gain 2 memory\" inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When this Digimon checks an opponent's security\" is triggered when the Digimon with the effect makes a security check on the opponent due to attacking them or after \uff1cPiercing\uff1e, for example. \"When a card is removed from your opponent's security stack\" does trigger from security checks, but it also triggers when security cards are removed for other reasons, such as effects that trash the opponent's security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How is the \"When this Digimon checks an opponent's security\" effect gained from this card's inherited effect different from \"When a card is removed from your opponent's security stack\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect activates after [Security] effects but before battling against the Security Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card as a digivolution card attacks a player and is deleted in battle against a Security Digimon. At that moment, can I activate this card's inherited effect to gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In such cases, the cards placed in [Guilmon]'s digivolution cards stay there.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After I activate this card's [Main] effect and place [Growlmon] and [WarGrowlmon] in my [Guilmon]'s digivolution cards. Can I choose to not digivolve it into [Gallantmon] in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my [Guilmon] to a [Gallantmon] in my hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon other than this card's is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect when I attack with a 2-color green/blue (in that specific order) Digimon or with a Digimon that is blue and green because of an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Since this card's effect specifies \"one of your 2-color blue and green Digimon\", you can't activate this card's [Your Turn] effect if your Digimon has 3 or more colors, even if those colors include blue and green.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card's [Your Turn] effect when my 3-color Digimon with blue and green attacks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Tamer can perform attacks just like Digimon, and it can also be affected by effects that target Digimon. It can also be deleted in battle with a Digimon or Security Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect allows this Tamer to be treated as a Digimon. What does this mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect has this card also be treated as a Digimon, does this card get deleted when an opponent's effect reduces its DP to 0?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is met. If this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect is activated, this card is treated as both a Digimon and a Tamer, so the \"When this Tamer becomes suspended\" condition is considered to be met when this card is suspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect has this card also be treated as a Digimon and then this card is suspended, does that meet the \"When this Tamer becomes suspended\" condition in this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's not. This card's effect has the Tamer be treated as a Digimon. As soon as it is placed in another Digimon's digivolution cards, it is treated as just a Tamer card and any activated effects are lost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect has this card also be treated as a Digimon and then this Digimon is placed in another Digimon's digivolution cards by a \"place 1 Digimon as another Digimon's digivolution card\" effect, is this card treated as \"a Digimon card in digivolution cards\" during that turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with \uff1cSave\uff1e in its text or a card with the [Hunter]\u00a0trait is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [On Play] effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include a Digimon card with \uff1cSave\uff1e in its text or a card with the [Hunter]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card [...] and 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [On Play] effect reveals 3 cards. If both a Digimon card with \uff1cSave\uff1e in its text and a card with the [Hunter]\u00a0trait are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. This card's effect doesn't let you attack with a Digimon that's in a state where it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Main] effect let me attack with a suspended Digimon or with a Digimon that was played that turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to attack, does the attacking Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. This card's effect doesn't let you attack with a Digimon that's in a state where it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Main] effect let me attack with a Digimon that was played that turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to attack, does the attacking Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They're trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to place a blue Digimon as the bottom digivolution card of another Digimon, what happens to that Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It's not being trashed by the effect, it's being trashed because of the rules, so [BT9-109 X Antibody] does still get trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to place a blue Digimon as the bottom digivolution card of another Digimon, what happens if that Digimon has [BT9-109 X Antibody] in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a 2-color yellow/red Tamer, can I count it as 2 Tamers for this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: 3 of your opponent's Digimon get -4000 DP. This card's effect only targets 3 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a 2-color yellow/red Tamer, does this card's [Main] effect give 6 of my opponent's Digimon -2000 DP for the turn or 3 of my opponent's Digimon -4000 DP for the turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, in such cases you win the game.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon attacks my opponent who has 1 security card, and I've used this card so its [Main] effect has given an opponent's Digimon the [On Deletion] effect, then delete that Digimon with a [When Attacking] effect, do I win the game by trashing the security card before the check and making it so I am attacking an opponent with 0 security cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't unsuspend. This card reads \"Your opponent's cards don't unsuspend during their next unsuspend phase,\" and this also affects cards that were later played or moved to the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent played a suspended Digimon by an effect after I activated this card's [Main] effect. Does my opponent's Digimon unsuspend in my opponent's next unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, in such cases the \"can't attack\" effect prevents making the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose an opponent's Digimon with a \"can't attack\" effect as the target when I activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the start of your opponent's main phase, the effects gained from this card's effect are triggered at the same time, and your opponent determines which one activates first. After effects such as [When Attacking] have activated, and before the counter timing occurs, it is time to activate the effect of the 2nd Digimon that was pending activation. However, since the 1st Digimon is already attacking, the effect ends without an attack made. As a result, only the Digimon whose effect was activated first can attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's effect activates twice and 2 of my opponent's Digimon gain the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can still choose a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" Digimon as a target for the effect. As soon as it becomes your opponent's turn, that opposing Digimon loses the \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect and is affected by this card's effect. As a result, the attack occurs at the start of the main phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's effect is activated on an opponent's Digimon with an \"[Opponent's Turn] This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When this card is in your trash, the effect can activate when one of your Digimon digivolves into [Beelzemon (X Antibody)]. [Trash] means that the card needs to be in your trash for the effect to activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When exactly is the timing for \"[Trash] [Your Turn]\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When activating the effect from your trash, it's not considered to be using an Option card, so there are no color requirements and no cost to be paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the color requirements and cost when I activate this card's [Trash] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Activating an effect from your trash isn't considered to be using an Option card, so they don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Are \"when using an Option card\" effects triggered if I activate this card's [Trash] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT12-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. The effect only allows you to place a [Shoutmon] from the battle area in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When playing this card, can the [Shoutmon] I place in its digivolution cards for its effect come from my hand, breeding area, or trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They're trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I activate the \"When this card would be played\" effect and place [Shoutmon] in this card's digivolution cards, what happens to [Shoutmon]'s digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It's not being trashed by the effect, it's being trashed because of the rules, so [BT9-109 X Antibody] does still get trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's effect places [Shoutmon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards, what happens if [Shoutmon] has [BT9-109 X Antibody] in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. DigiXros is performed after all \"\"would be played\"\" effects have activated. Therefore, you must first place [Shoutmon] in its digivolution cards for the effect and then place cards under the [Shoutmon] digivolution card for the DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I activate the \"When this card would be played\" effect and place [Shoutmon] in this card's digivolution cards, can I first place cards for DigiXros and only then place [Shoutmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: [Shoutmon]'s digivolution cards are trashed when I place it in this Digimon's digivolution cards for the \"When this card would be played\" effect. Can I DigiXros with those trashed cards and place them in this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that you can DigiXros with as many cards as you like, as long as all the cards have the [Xros Heart]/[Blue Flare]\u00a0trait and different card numbers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"\u221e Digimon cards w/[Xros Heart]/[Blue Flare]\u00a0trait & different card numbers\" in this card's DigiXros requirements mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's not DigiXros if you don't place any cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's DigiXros requirements say \"\u221e Digimon cards,\" but is it still considered DigiXros if I place 0 cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. A [Shoutmon] placed as a digivolution card for this card's \"\"When you would play this card\"\" effect is not treated as placed by the DigiXros, so it is not included in this card's \"\"different card numbers\"\" DigiXros condition.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I place [Shoutmon] as a digivolution card for this card's \"When you would play this card\" effect, can I place another card with the same number as that [Shoutmon] as a digivolution card under this Digimon for this card's DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"While my opponent has no suspended Digimon, I attack with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards, then my opponent's Digimon blocks and suspends.  Does this card's inherited effect activate upon the battle with the opponent's Digimon that blocked?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT13-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You can't delete an opponent's Digimon, but you can trash a card in your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] inherited effect to trash 1 card in my hand even if my opponent has no level 3 Digimon when the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards is deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: That's correct, such digivolutions are also not possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Breeding] [Your Turn] effect also prevent my Digimon from DNA digivolving or burst digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't be digivolved.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st [Breeding] [Your Turn] effect allow my Tamers to digivolve using a \"you may digivolve as if your Tamer is a level 3 Digimon\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can be digivolved.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st [Breeding] [Your Turn] effect allow my Tamers to digivolve using digivolution requirements for digivolving from Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect additionally increases the numerical value of the play cost reduction in \"when a [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait Digimon card would be played, you may reduce the play cost by 4\" in this carad's 2nd [Breeding] [Your Turn] effect.  For example, if this Digimon has 1 digivolution card, the numerical value of the play cost reduction will be 5.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"further reduce it by 1 for each of this Digimon's digivolution cards\" in this card's 2nd [Breeding] [Your Turn] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must perform as much of the processing as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not reveal the top card of my Digi-Egg deck and not place my [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait Digimon as this Digimon's bottom digivolution cards for this card's [Breeding] [Start of Your Main Phase]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated the effect chooses the order of the bottom digivolution cards that are placed.  Note that the cards placed by this effect must be placed under any already placed digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If multiple cards are placed as the bottom digivolution cards for this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, what order are the cards placed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't processed.  \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) is processed when a card is sent from the area or from under a card to another area.  In this case, \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) isn't processed because a card from the area is placed under another card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to place a BT17-078 [Omnimon ACE] under this card as a digivolution card, is BT17-078 [Omnimon ACE] processed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't be reduced. [BT8-071 Psychemon]'s effect does not target Digimon, so even if your opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] is in the breeding area, its effect to reduce play costs can't be activated.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can the play cost of a Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait be reduced due to the [Your Turn] effect of my opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] if [BT8-071 Psychemon] is in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, using and activating [BT10-110 Seiken Meppa]'s [Main] effect does not cause a card to be \"placed\" in the Battle Area, so this card's inherited effect does not trigger.[4]",
      "question": "Q: Does using [BT10-110 Seiken Meppa] trigger this card's inherited effect to gain memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The DP is overwritten by the effect that activated afterward, therefore the card is treated as a Digimon with 3000 DP.  The \uff1cRush\uff1e gained from [BT13-020 ShineGreymon: Burst Mode]'s effect remains because it isn't overwritten by anything.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's effect activates for my [Marcus Damon] that's treated as a 12000 DP Digimon with \uff1cRush\uff1e due to [BT13-020 ShineGreymon: Burst Mode]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Marcus Damon] is treated as a Digimon by this card's effect and then its DP is reduced to 0 by an effect, is it deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player chooses the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I play a Digimon with [Sistermon], which effect activates first, that Digimon's [On Play] effect or this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to return my [Kristy Damon] to my hand even if I don't have a [Garudamon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means you can look at all of the cards in your security stack, without revealing them to your opponent. If a card that can be played by the effect is among them, you may reveal that card and play it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"You may search your security stack\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: <Security +1 (Deck)> doesn't occur. Shuffle your security stack, and the effect ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens for this card's effect if there are no cards in my security stack that I can play or want to play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Your Digimon with [Sistermon] was played before the inherited effect could activate by digivolving this Digimon, therefore the inherited effect isn't triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"I play a Digimon with [Sistermon] and use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve this Digimon into [SaviorHuckmon] in my hand.   Can I gain 1 memory from this card's inherited effect at this time?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player chooses the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I play a Digimon with [Sistermon], which effect activates first, that Digimon's [On Play] effect or this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my red or yellow [Marcus Damon] is deleted, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to place the deleted [Marcus Damon] card from my trash on top of my security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player chooses the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I play a Digimon with [Sistermon], which effect activates first, that Digimon's [On Play] effect or this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Marcus Damon] is treated as a Digimon by this card's effect and then its DP is reduced to 0 by an effect, is it deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect to play [BT5-111 Omnimon X Anti-body], [BT10-068 Gankoomon (X Antibody)], and [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)] from the digivolution cards of my Digimon in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Marcus Damon] is treated as a Digimon by this card's effect and then its DP is reduced to 0 by an effect, is it deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only return your own Tamer to the hand for Burst Digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return an opponent's Tamer to its owner's hand for this card's Burst Digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: In addition to \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, this effect prevents the attack target from being switched due to effects such as \"you may switch the target of attack to this Digimon.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: How is the \"this Digimon's attack target can't be switched\" effect on this card different from \"This Digimon can't be blocked\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect only targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 total cards consisting of Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait and/or blue Tamers, can I use this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect to trash the top 2 digivolution cards of 2 different opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate when this card itself is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player chooses the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is played, in what order does its [On Play][When Digivolving] effect and [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only return your own Tamer to the hand for Burst Digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return an opponent's Tamer to its owner's hand for this card's Burst Digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this card's effect. The player chooses the cards in their opponent's hand until there are only 8 left and the order they are returned to the deck before returning them to the bottom of the deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the cards in my opponent's hand to return to the deck with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  After your opponent activates this effect, they select cards without looking at them, therefore they can't check the cards before they are returned to the bottom of the deck. However, the owner of the returned cards may look at them before returning them to the bottom of the deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [When Attacking] effect to return cards from my hand to the bottom of my deck, can I check what cards I am returning to my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks. For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's inherited effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's inherited effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's inherited effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's inherited effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"When this Digimon would leave the battle area\" does not trigger for DNA Digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attempt to DNA digivolve this Digimon and another Digimon, can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect to prevent the digivolution?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If the total cards in both players' security stacks is 6 or less, you must perform the rest of the effect to the best of your ability.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not use this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect to reveal 1 card from my hand if I don't have any yellow cards or I don't want to add cards to my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You place it on top of your security stack because the card's colors include yellow. You can't return it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect to reveal a 2-color yellow card from my hand, do I place it on top of my security stack or return it to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards when my opponent has just 1 Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, and my opponent's Digimon blocks. If this means my opponent no longer has any unsuspended Digimon, does this card's inherited effect give my Digimon +1000 DP upon a battle?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose different Digimon for the Digimon to suspend and the Digimon that doesn't unsuspend until the end of my opponent's turn for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, this effect only prevents the target Digimon from unsuspending until the end of your opponent's turn. It doesn't suspend the target Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose one of my opponent's unsuspended Digimon for \"until the end of your opponent's turn, 1 of your opponent's Digimon doesn't unsuspend\" in this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose a Digimon other than a Digimon with 7000 DP or less when choosing the Digimon that doesn't unsuspend until the end of my opponent's turn for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card\u2019s inherited effect activates first. After trashing the top card of your opponent's security stack, perform the security check for \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which comes first, trashing the top card of my opponent's security stack from this card's inherited effect or the security check from the \uff1cPiercing\uff1e effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect is a [Once Per Turn] effect, therefore it can't activate again during the same turn that it activated for [When Digivolving], even if the timings are different.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving][Main] effect both for a digivolution into this card and for the main phase in the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving][Main] effect to play a card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait, can I activate both this card's effect and my [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6]'s effect to reduce the play cost according to each respective effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.  Note that this effect applies to \"\"all of your Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait and all your green Digimon,\"\" therefore any applicable Digimon that are placed in the battle area after this effect activates will also receive \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I play a card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait or a green Digimon card, does this card's [All Turns] effect also give \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to that played Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon or Tamers even when this Digimon was originally unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. A single suspended Digimon or Tamer will count as long as the total suspended cards is 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does my opponent have to have a combination of 2 suspended Digimon or a combination of 2 suspended Tamers in order for them to count toward \"every 2 of your opponent's suspended Digimon and Tamers\" in this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only return your own Tamer to the hand for Burst Digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return an opponent's Tamer to its owner's hand for this card's Burst Digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it includes this card itself.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"Digimon card with [Chessmon] in your trash\" in this card's [On Deletion] effect also include this card itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] to prevent itself from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.  Until the processing for the 1st activation has resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each immediate-type effect.  In your case, until the deletion of the 1st only [Sukamon] A is resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each \"when [...] would\" effect, therefore the effect that has already activated for [Sukamon] A can't be activated again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have [Sukamon] A and [Sukamon] B with this card in their digivolution cards in the battle area.  When [Sukamon] A would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] B using this card's inheriated effect.  On the other hand, when [Sukamon] B would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] A using this card's inherited effect.  At such times, can [Sukamon] A activate this card's inherited effect again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect delete an opponent's [Sukamon] to prevent itself from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.  Until the processing for the 1st activation has resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each immediate-type effect.  In your case, until the deletion of the 1st only [Sukamon] A is resolved, only 1 activation is possible for each \"when [...] would\" effect, therefore the effect that has already activated for [Sukamon] A can't be activated again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have [Sukamon] A and [Sukamon] B with this card in their digivolution cards in the battle area.  When [Sukamon] A would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] B using this card's inherited effect.  On the other hand, when [Sukamon] B would be deleted, I attempted to delete [Sukamon] A using this card's inherited effect.  At such times, can [Sukamon] A activate this card's inherited effect again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [All Turns] effect is triggered when one of your Digimon with [Chessmon] is deleted, therefore it won't trigger if such a Digimon isn't deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an effect such as \uff1cDecoy (nocategory)\uff1e (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) prevents deletion when this suspended Digimon would be deleted, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to unsuspend this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent activated this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect, my Digimon with a play cost of 9 or less digivolved in my next turn and became a Digimon with a play cost of 10 or more. Can I attack with this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack has already been declared, so the attack will continue.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with a play cost of 9 or less attacked a player, digivolved using a [When Attacking] effect, and became a Digimon with a play cost of 10 or more in a state where this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect was activated for my opponent. What happens to the attack in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when one of my opponent's Digimon with [Etemon] is deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be blocked.  \uff1cBlocker\uff1e is an effect that allows for the Digimon to block, so it isn't affected by \"\"isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\"\" effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks when this card's [On Play][When Attacking] effect prevents it from being affected by the effects of my opponent's Digimon, can it be blocked by my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't have to choose an opponent's Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to choose an opponent's Digimon for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't attack using a Digimon that can't attack.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose an opponent's Digimon that can't attack for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect, does my opponent attack with that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, your opponent can't attack using that Digimon. A new attack declaration can't be made during an attack.  In such cases, even if you choose an opponent's Digimon for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect when there is already an attacking Digimon, your opponent can't attack with the chosen Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon is attacking using an effect at the end of their turn.  If I choose an opponent's Digimon for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect, does my opponent attack with that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose a Digimon that isn't affected by effects for this and have it attack.  Such Digimon aren't affected by effects, but they can be chosen.  In addition, \"your opponent attacks with the chosen Digimon\" in this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect affects a player, therefore your opponent must attack with the chosen Digimon if it can attack.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose a Digimon that isn't affected by effects for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect and have it attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I or my opponent choose the card to be trashed from their hand when I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It activates because the Digimon is deleted by the \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e effect, not by battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e on a battled opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes it can. Placing a card in digivolution cards isn't digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon can't Digivolve, but can it be placed in another Digimon's digivolution cards by a card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to return this card itself from my trash to the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I only have 2 cards with [Gizmon] including this card in my trash, can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to return those 2 cards to the bottom of my deck but not play [Gizmon: AT] from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I or my opponent choose the card to be trashed from their hand when I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It activates because the Digimon is deleted by the \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e effect, not by battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e on a battled opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes it can. Placing a card in digivolution cards isn't digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon can't Digivolve, but can it be placed in another Digimon's digivolution cards by a card effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to return this card itself from my trash to the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I only have 2 cards with [Gizmon] including this card in my trash, can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to return those 2 cards to the bottom of my deck but not play [Gizmon: XT] from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It activates because the Digimon is deleted by the \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e effect, not by battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e on a battled opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the 2 cards you add to your hand are cards that fulfill either of the conditions: a card with [Lucemon] or a card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait. Therefore, in addition to the combinations from your question, you can also add 1 card with [Lucemon] and 1 card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to choose 2 cards with [Lucemon] or 2 cards with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait among the revealed cards to add to my hand for this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 card with [Lucemon] or the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait is among the 5 revealed cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect triggers simultaneously with your opponent's [End of Your Turn] effects, therefore your opponent's [End of Your Turn] effects and any derived effects will activate first because your opponent is the turn player.[1]",
      "question": "Q: At what timing do I play [Ravemon] from my trash at the end of my opponent's turn for this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  At the end of your turn, [BT13-092 Ravemon: Burst Mode] is still placed, so this card's [End of Your Turn] effect isn't triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card Burst Digivolved into [BT13-092 Ravemon: Burst Mode]. At the end of my turn, the [BT13-092 Ravemon: Burst Mode] that was placed for the Burst Digivolve is trashed, but then can I activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect can only be used to search your opponent's hand for the card you choose to trash from their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to look at the card that my opponent adds to their hand from their security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [When Attacking] effect reads \"\"your opponent's Digimon that share a name with the returned card,\"\" therefore if you return your opponent's [Greymon] to their deck, you can only delete your opponent's Digimon with the [Greymon] name.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to return my opponent's [Greymon] to the bottom of their deck from their trash, can I delete my opponent's cards such as [MetalGreymon] and [WarGreymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to return my opponent's card with \"This card/Digimon is also treated as [XX]\" to the bottom of their deck from their trash, can I delete both my opponent's Digimon with the same name as that card and my opponent's Digimon with the [XX] name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since the card was not revealed by a security check, its [Security] effect can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the card that my opponent adds to their hand from their security stack by this card's [When Digivolving] effect has a [Security] effect, does that effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The cards in your hand count as private information, so you don't have to place that card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait in my hand, do I have to place it under my [Yggdrasill_7D6] in the breeding area as its bottom digivolution card for this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have [Agumon] or [Greymon] but my opponent has no Digimon when this Tamer becomes suspended, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to gain 1 memory without 1 of my opponent's Digimon getting -3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I played a blue Digimon, its DP became 0 by an opponent's effect that had already activated, so the Digimon was deleted at the same time it was played. Does this Tamer's [All Turns] effect still trigger in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must draw 1 card from your deck if possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to draw 1 card from my deck when my opponent activates this Tamer card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means if the total sum of cards in your security stack and the cards in your opponent's security stack is 6 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"If the total cards in both players' security stacks is 6 or less\" mean 6 or less cards in either me or my opponent's security stacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. A card revealed from your security stack and then trashed isn't considered \"When this card is trashed from a security stack.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is revealed from my security stack and trashed by [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)]'s effect, does this card's \u201cWhen this card is trashed from a security stack by an effect\u201d effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means if the total sum of cards in your security stack and the cards in your opponent's security stack is 6 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"If the total cards in both players' security stacks is 6 or less\" mean 6 or less cards in either me or my opponent's security stacks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The order of the colors doesn't matter, so the effect will activate for either yellow and black or black and yellow.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card's [All Turns] effect when I play a 2-color yellow and black Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I played a 2-color black and yellow Digimon, its DP became 0 by an opponent's effect that had already activated, so the Digimon was deleted at the same time it was played. Does this Tamer's [All Turns] effect still trigger in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this card's effect.  This card's effect gives you 1 memory and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e if the opponent player doesn't trash 1 Tamer card or Option card from their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player gains 1 memory and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e from this card\u2019s [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate when either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon is played by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. DigiXros itself is not an effect, so the effect doesn't activate for a card played by a DigiXros as a main phase action.  The effect will activate if a DigiXros is performed when a Digimon is played by an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate when a Digimon is played by a DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that uses this card gains memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player gains memory from this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's effect activates before the security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Digimon attacks a player and this card is trashed from the security stack by a [When Attacking] effect, which comes first, the security check from the attack or this card's \u201cWhen this card is trashed from a security stack by an effect\u201d effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means if the total sum of cards in your security stack and the cards in your opponent's security stack is 6 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"If the total cards in both players' security stacks is 6 or less\" mean 6 or less cards in either me or my opponent's security stacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Digimon's security check is zero. No checks are performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon attacks a player and this card is trashed from the security stack by a [When Attacking] effect. If this card's [Main] effect gives all of my opponent's Digimon <Security Attack -1> and the attacking Digimon now has a security check number of 0, is a security check performed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It activates because \"When this card is trashed from a security stack by an effect\" isn't a [Security] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Main] effect activate if this card is trashed from the security stack when my opponent has activated a \"your opponent doesn't activate [Security] effects\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. A card revealed from your security stack and then trashed isn't considered \"When this card is trashed from a security stack.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is revealed from my security stack and trashed by [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)]'s effect, does this card's \u201cWhen this card is trashed from a security stack by an effect\u201d effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. A card doesn't have cards stacked under it if it doesn't have digivolution cards, therefore you can't use this card's effect to return the card to your hand, and the effect that unsuspends all of your Digimon doesn't activate, either.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to return my [Leopardmon: Leopard Mode] without digivolution cards to my hand and unsuspend all of my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, a level 2 Digimon doesn't have DP, so it will be trashed by the rules after effect activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to return my [Leopardmon: Leopard Mode] with only a level 2 Digi-Egg card in its digivolution cards to my hand and unsuspend all of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't affected by [Security] effects, either.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon is affected by this card's \"This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" effect. Is it affected by the [Security] effect of my opponent's Option cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't.  The \"When this Digimon is suspended, delete all of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost less than or equal to this Digimon\" effect from this card is a Digimon effect. It isn't considered to be an Option card effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can \"isn't affected by your opponent's Option cards\" effects prevent the \"When this Digimon is suspended, delete all of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost less than or equal to this Digimon\" effect given to an opponent's Digimon by this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can't ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve a Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements or special digivolution requirements into [Belphemon: Sleep Mode] from your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve any 1 of my Digimon into a [Belphemon: Sleep Mode] from my trash without paying the cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means every 5 cards in yours and your opponent's trashes combined.  For example, if you have 12 cards in your trash and your opponent has 8 cards in theirs, that makes a total of 20 cards, so the play cost is reduced by 8.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"for every 5 cards in both players' trash\" mean for every 5 cards in either mine or my opponent's trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 6000 DP or less\" becomes \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 7000 DP or less,\" but 13000 DP isn't the maximum for \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 13000 DP or more,\" therefore it isn't affected and remains as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 13000 DP or more.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an \"Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect has activated, does this card's [On Play][When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect become \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 7000 DP or less. If no Digimon was deleted by this effect, delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 14000 DP or more\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT13-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect plays 1 of each Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait and different names from among the digivolution cards.  For example, if the target digivolution cards are [Omnimon], [Alphamon], [Alphamon], [Gallantmon], and [Gallantmon (X Antibody)], you would leave 1 [Alphamon] since it has the same name, then play[Omnimon], [Alphamon], [Gallantmon], and [Gallantmon (X Antibody)].  Note that the [Omnimon] where this effect activated isn't a digivolution card, therefore you can use this effect to play 1 [Omnimon] from among the target cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"you may play 1 of each Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait and a different name from the digivolution cards of Digimon in the breeding area without paying the costs\" in this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect mean that I can play a Digimon card with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait without the name [Omnimon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must play all of the Digimon that you can play or play no Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect to play Digimon, can I choose just the cards I want to play from among the cards I can play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cards are also trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect reads \"trash your Digimon in the breeding area\" for when a Digimon is played by this effect, but what happens to the remaining digivolution cards under this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's processed.  \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) is processed when a card is sent from the area or from under a card to another area.  In this case, \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) is processed because a card is placed in the trash from under another card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Play] effect to trash a BT13-007 [King Drasil_7D6] with a BT17-078 [Omnimon ACE] in its digivolution cards. Is BT17-078 [Omnimon ACE]'s \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) processed at such times?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Digimon in the Breeding Area cannot be targeted by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the inherited effect of this card allow a Digimon in the Breeding Area to digivolved to a Digimon card with \"Monster Type\"/\"SoC\" on the trait that was trashed from the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon card with the [Dark Animal]/[SoC]\u00a0trait is trashed from my hand, can I use this card's inherited effect to digivolve into that card regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must pay the digivolution cost.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to digivolve without paying the digivolution cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to digivolve into [Greymon] in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Such effects can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect allow activation of effects that reduce play costs when Digimon are played other than by an effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution cost is reduced by 1. This effect continues until the end of the turn, therefore the digivolution cost will be reduced by 1 for every digivolution that occurs during that time and meets the requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into a Digimon that meets the requirements and then digivolving into another Digimon that meets the requirements in the same turn, can this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] reduce the digivolution cost by 1 again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This card's inherited effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to attack using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards even when it's suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Because the turn didn't switch the first time the turn ended, the [Once Per Turn] restriction still applies. In addition, the [Once Per Turn] restriction doesn't reset even for digivolutions. Therefore, you can't use this card's inherited effect to attack twice.[1]",
      "question": "Q: At the end of my turn, I used this inherited effect to attack, then an effect changed my memory to 0 or more and my turn continued. After that, if a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards digivolved and the end of my turn came again while it was unsuspended, can I use this inherited effect to attack again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. At the end of your turn, the inherited effects on these cards activate, the activation order is decided, and then the attack occurs for the 1st Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. After activation of effects that are triggered upon attack declaration such as [When Attacking] effects and \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects but before the counter timing, the next activation would occur for the other inherited effect that was pending activation, but because the 1st Digimon is still attacking, you can't make a new attack declaration, and the 2nd activation fails.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 Digimon with this card in their digivolution cards, can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack using these 2 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can't be played. If your opponent has this Digimon, \"While your opponent has 1 or more memory\" from your opponent's perspective means while you have 1 or more memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent me from playing a Digimon card with 6000 DP or less when my opponent has this Digimon while I have 1 or more memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can't be played. [1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent playing a Digimon card with 6000 DP or less even from effects that play a card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can't be played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also prevent playing a token that is treated as a Digimon card with 6000 DP or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can't be played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon card with an original DP of 6000 or less and its DP would increase to more than 6000 by an effect upon playing it into the battle area, does this card's [All Turns] effect allow that card to be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be played. At the timing of the play declaration, if \"While your opponent has 1 or more memory\" from your opponent's perspective applies (in other words, if you have 1 or more memory), this card's [All Turns] effect doesn't allow you to play such Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect allow me to play a Digimon card with 6000 DP or less if paying the play cost would cause the memory to change to 0 or 1 or more on my opponent's side when my opponent has this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. You aren't allowed to declare playing a 6000 DP or lower Digimon card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has this Digimon, does this card's [All Turns] effect allow me to just pay the play cost for a Digimon card with 6000 DP or less without playing it while I have 1 memory or more?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens are special cards that some effects put into play to represent Digimon or Tamers. This card's effect, for example, plays tokens that are treated as Digimon named [Amon of Crimson Flame] and [Umon of Blue Thunder]. For a more detailed explanation of how tokens work, check the official rule manual.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What's a token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't. The [Amon of Crimson Flame] and [Umon of Blue Thunder] tokens played by this card's effect can't become targets for effects with requirements related to play cost or level because these tokens don't have a play cost or level.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can [Amon of Crimson Flame] and [Umon of Blue Thunder] tokens played by this card's effect become targets for \"Digimon with play costs of X or less\" effects or \"level X or higher/lower Digimon\" effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if you have only 1 [Amon of Crimson Flame] or [Umon of Blue Thunder] token, it will be deleted and <Recovery +1 (Deck)> will activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [All Turns] effect activate <Recovery +1 (Deck)> and delete my [Amon of Crimson Flame] or [Umon of Blue Thunder] when I only have one or the other?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only activates once. No matter how many [Amon of Crimson Flame] and/or [Umon of Blue Thunder] you delete at one time with this effect, <Recovery +1 (Deck)> will only activate once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [All Turns] effect deletes 2 of my [Amon of Crimson Flame] and/or [Umon of Blue Thunder], does <Recovery +1 (Deck)> activate twice?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"When [...] would [...] leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"This Digimon can't be blocked\" in this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate even when my opponent can't trash a digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it. This card\u2019s inherited effect reads \"When this Digimon would be deleted,\" so it interrupts the deletion when it activates. Therefore, the [Gomamon] with the [On Deletion] effect is removed from the digivolution cards before the [On Deletion] effect can be triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have both this card and another [Gomamon] with an [On Deletion] inherited effect in the digivolution cards of the same one of my Digimon. When that Digimon is deleted, can I activate this card's inherited effect, play the other [Gomamon] from the digivolution cards, and activate that [On Deletion] inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. If the number of digivolution cards under the target opponent's Digimon is less than or equal to those of this Digimon or the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards at the timing when this effect activates, the target Digimon can't attack until the effect ends at the end of your opponent's turn, even if the number of its digivolution cards later increases.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the digivolution cards under the target opponent's Digimon increase to become more than those under this Digimon after this card's [When Attacking] effect/inherited effect activate, can my opponent's Digimon now attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect trash 1 digivolution card each from 2 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect trash 1 digivolution card each from 2 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must return your level 3 Digimon to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also return my level 3 Digimon to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it prevents that deletion.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent deletion even when I lose a battle with my opponent's Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted. \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e is deletion by an effect, not by battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] delete this Digimon when my opponent's Digimon activates \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e after battling this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect trash 1 digivolution card each from 3 of my opponent's Digimon or trash 2 digivolution cards from 1 of their Digimon and 1 digivolution card from another?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect unsuspend this Digimon when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can return your Digimon of any level to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect return any level Digimon when it returns my Digimon to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect return my Digimon to the hand even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck instead of the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by returning 1 of your Digimon to the hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to return my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] from the battle area to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] is a Digimon without a level, therefore your opponent can't return a Digimon to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to return my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] from the battle area to the hand, what happens for \"return 1 of your opponent's Digimon whose level is less than or equal to the returned Digimon's level to the hand\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your token is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be removed from the game instead of being returned to the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by returning 1 of your Digimon to the hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to return my token that was played as a Digimon from the battle area to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't add a card to the hand because you have 0 cards in your security stack, but you may perform \"place 1 card with [Sukamon] from your hand on top of your security stack.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s effect work if it activates when I have 0 cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, there are no requirements for the card you add to your hand with this effect, so you don't have to reveal it to your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] effect to add 1 card from my security stack to the hand, do I have to reveal the added card to my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to digivolve it into a yellow Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait in my security stack, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use an effect that digivolves my Digimon to digivolve this card into a security card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. <Recovery +1 (Deck)> added a card to your security, so you gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon in play with this card in its digivolution cards. [BT1-087 T.K. Takaishi]\u2019s effect adds a yellow card from my security stack to my hand, and <Recovery +1 (Deck)> adds a card to my security stack. The number of cards in my security stack ultimately remained the same, but can I still gain 1 memory from this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they trigger simultaneously.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to digivolve from a security card, then place a card from my hand at the bottom of the security stack.  Do \"when a card is added to the security stack\" and \"when a card is removed from the security stack\" effects trigger simultaneously at such times?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you have 6 or more cards, they get -1000 DP for each security card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] give 1 of my opponent's Digimon -1000 DP for each card in my security stack even if I have 6 or more cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. The effect only targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] give 2 of my opponent's Digimon -1000 DP each when I have 2 cards in my security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a [Security] effect, so it happens before the battle.  The battle with your Security Digimon happens after the activation of [On Play] effects on played Digimon or \"When you play a Digimon\" effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this cards [Security] effect play 1 level 6 Digimon card with [Etemon] from my hand before or after the battle with my Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. A card was added to your security stack with <Recovery +1 (Deck)>, therefore 1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -7000 DP and this Digimon gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: [BT1-087 T.K. Takaishi]\u2019s effect adds a yellow card from my security stack to my hand, and <Recovery +1 (Deck)> adds a card to my security stack. The number of cards in my security stack ultimately remained the same, but does 1 of my opponent's Digimon still get -7000 DP and does this Digimon still gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card\u2019s effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect suspend my Digimon even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't unsuspend. This card's effect targets \"all of your opponent's Digimon,\" therefore even your opponent's Digimon that later had their DP reduced to 5000 DP or less don't unsuspend.  On the other hand, even if one of your opponent's Digimon has 5000 DP or less upon activation, that Digimon will unsuspend if its DP later increases to 6000 DP or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has 6000 DP or more when this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates, then its DP is reduced to 5000 or less by an effect, does that Digimon unsuspend during the unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This card's [When Attacking] effect is an effect that activates before your opponent blocks, therefore the activation timing has already passed by the time of the block timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacked the opponent player and was blocked by an opponent's Digimon that has more DP than this Digimon. Can I use this card's effect to digivolve into a level 6 Digimon card with [Leomon] in my hand, ignoring its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. Only when this Digimon attacked a Digimon with higher DP at the time of the attack declaration can this card's [When Attacking] effect digivolve into a level 6 Digimon card with [Leomon] in your hand, ignoring its digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon gained \uff1cRush\uff1e, it attacked the opponent player, and I used the \uff1cRush\uff1e effect to switch the target of attack to an opponent's Digimon with higher DP than this Digimon. In such cases, can this card's [When Attacking] effect digivolve into a level 6 Digimon card with [Leomon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you add as many as possible to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I still add to the hand with this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect if I only reveal 1 green Digimon card among the top 5 cards of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that treats it as a card that has [Leomon]. This is a rule and not an effect, therefore this card is treated as having [Leomon] when the card is in your hand, breeding area, or any other area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"(Rule) Name: Treated as having [Leomon]\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. This card's name is treated as having [Leomon], but it is not treated as [Leomon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be selected as the target of an effect that targets exactly [Leomon] due to the text \"(Rule) Name: Treated as having [Leomon]\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect unsuspend this Digimon even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. At the end of your turn, these cards' [End of Your Turn] effects trigger at the same time, the activation order is decided, and then the attack occurs for the 1st Digimon. After activation of effects that are triggered upon attack declaration such as [When Attacking] effects and \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects but before the counter timing, the activation would next occur for the other [End of Your Turn] effect that was pending activation, but because the 1st Digimon is still attacking, you can't make a new attack declaration, and the 2nd effect activation fails.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 copies of this Digimon, can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack using these 2 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack even when this Digimon is suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of the cards revealed from my deck by this card's [On Play] effect is a Tamer card or Option card with the [D-Brigade]/[DigiPolice]\u00a0trait, can I add that card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. This effect can interrupt the removal of a card from the battle area, therefore by deleting 1 of your other Digimon with the [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait, this card will be prevented from being placed in your other Digimon's digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect activate when an opponent's effect would place a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards in another of my Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"When [...] would [...] leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that treats it as a card that has the [Commandramon] name. This is a rule and not an effect, therefore this card is treated as having the [Commandramon] name when the card is in your hand, breeding area, or any other area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Commandramon]\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be selected as the target of an effect that targets exactly [Commandramon] due to the text \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Commandramon]\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of the cards revealed from my deck by this card's [When Attacking] effect is a Tamer card with the [D-Brigade]/[DigiPolice]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 3 or less, can I play that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"When [...] would [...] leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this effect chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the card to return from my opponent\u2019s trash to the deck by this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents deletion when this Digimon is the target of an effect with \"delete\" in its card text. Deletion will still occur if you lose a battle, both players lose a battle, or if this Digimon's DP is reduced to 0.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [All Turns] effect reads \"This Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent's effects.\" How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add 1 card or play it even if only 1 card is revealed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed with this card's [On Deletion] effect don't include both a card with [Monzaemon] and a Digimon card with [Numemon], am I allowed to play one of the cards or add it to my hand, or do both cards have to be present?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. You must play or add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the 3 cards revealed from my deck with this card's [On Deletion] effect include both a card with [Monzaemon] and a Digimon card with [Numemon], am I allowed to add just one card to my hand or play it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of the cards revealed from my deck by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is a Tamer card with the [D-Brigade]/[DigiPolice]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 4 or less, can I play that card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) activates 3 times, not \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 3 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards).  The difference is that \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 3 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) allows you to trash 1 to 3 cards, but \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) trashes 1 card three times, meaning that you always trash 3 cards (or until there are no more digivolution cards or until the Digimon is reduced to level 3).[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent reveals 3 Digimon cards from their deck by this card's effect, does it \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 3 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) 1 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this effect chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card\u2019s effect returns revealed cards to my opponent's deck, which player decides the order the cards are placed in and whether the cards are placed on the top or bottom of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If the chosen card has a play cost of 5, choose a number of your opponent's Digimon whose total play cost add up to 5 or less and delete them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the card chosen with this card's effect has a play cost of 5, can it delete up to 5 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this effect chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card\u2019s effect returns revealed cards to my opponent's deck, which player decides the order the cards are placed in and whether the cards are placed on the top or bottom of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of the cards revealed from my deck by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect is a Tamer card with the [D-Brigade]/[DigiPolice]\u00a0trait, can I play that card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't return a card from your trash to the hand, but you must perform \"trash 1 card in your hand.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens for this effect if I don't have a purple Digimon card with the [Dark Animal]\u00a0trait in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card isn't in the battle area upon the timing when it's trashed, so the [Your Turn] effect doesn't trigger and you don't gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect to gain 1 memory when [EX5-062 Anubismon]'s [When Digivolving] effect trashes this card in my hand and plays it from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain 1 memory. The effect reads \"By...\" Therefore, the rest of the effect won't activate if you don't trash a card in your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't trash 1 card in my hand, do I gain 1 memory from this card's [When Attacking] effect when [Eiji Nagasumi] is still in this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the the trashed card is public information. \"Trash [...] without looking\" means that you must choose a card to trash from your opponent's hand without looking at the front of the cards in their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is the card trashed by this card's [On Deletion] effect also private information?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it deletes this Digimon. However, this effect reads \"By trashing 1 card in your hand,\" therefore you can choose to not activate the effect by not trashing a card in your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect delete this Digimon when I only have this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to trash 1 card in my hand even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You must activate \"Delete this Digimon and \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e.\" \"Then, you may return 1 [Loogamon] from your trash to the hand\" uses \"you may return,\" therefore it is optional.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally, the turn will end and switch when the memory moves to 1 or more on your opponent's side. But while this effect is activated, the turn won't end unless the memory moves to 3 or more on your opponent's side. Your turn will continue when your opponent's memory is at 1 or 2.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [Your Turn] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only applies during your turn. Your opponent's turn continues until the memory moves to 1 or more from your perspective.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the memory moves to 2 or less on my opponent's side during my opponent's turn, does the turn switch to my turn with this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your turn continues.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The memory moved to 3 or more on my opponent's side and the turn ended while this card's [Your Turn] effect was activated. If the memory moves to 1 or 2 on my opponent's side due to an [End of Your Turn] effect, does my turn continue?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. \uff1cBlitz\uff1e still requires the memory to be at 1 or more on your opponent's side for attacking.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the memory moves to 3 or more on my opponent's side while this card's [Your Turn] effect is activated, does \uff1cBlitz\uff1e allow for attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect is a \"You may play\" effect, but it doesn't include \"up to,\" therefore you must choose to either play no cards or as many as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to play just 2 of the target cards from my trash when [Eiji Nagasumi] is in this Digimon's digivolution cards and I have 3 or more level 4 or lower cards with the [Dark Animal]/[SoC]\u00a0trait in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The memory will move to 3 on your opponent's side, and the turn will end if there are no other effects pending activation, etc.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I declare a \"pass\" when I have this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After activation of the [Security] effect on the card revealed by the security check. If the card is a Digimon card, then the timing will come before the battle with the Security Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When is the activation timing for this card's [Your Turn] effect when a player is attacked and a security check is performed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Play] effect to return 1 card from my security stack to the hand, then I placed 1 yellow card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait from my hand at the bottom of my security stack. At such times, is a card considered to be added to my security stack, allowing this card's [Your Turn] effect to activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, there are no requirements for the card you return to your hand with this effect, so you don't have to reveal it to your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] effect to return 1 card from my security stack to the hand, do I have to reveal the returned card to my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect even when an opponent's effect suspends an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add just 1 card to your hand when only 1 or the other is revealed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal with this card's [On Play] effect don't contain both a level 3 Digimon card and a non-white Tamer card, do I still get to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the cards revealed from my deck with this card's [On Play] effect contain both a level 3 Digimon card and a non-white Tamer card, am I allowed to add just one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can't move level 2 Digimon or cards like [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] because cards without DP can't be moved to the battle area. It can move [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] because it has DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect move a level 2 Digimon or cards like [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] or [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to move a Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area during the counter timing, can I then <Blast Digivolve> that Digimon into a Digimon ACE card in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If you have a Digimon with [Greymon], delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with the lowest DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have a Digimon with [Greymon] and my opponent has 1 Digimon with 6000 DP and 1 with 4000 DP, can I choose the target to delete with this card's effect from these 2 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. This effect reads \"may digivolve into [WarGreymon] in your hand,\" therefore you can choose to not digivolve after placing [Greymon] and [MetalGreymon] from your trash under [Agumon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to place 1 [Greymon] and 1 [MetalGreymon] from my trash under [Agumon] but choose to not digivolve into [WarGreymon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. If the number of digivolution cards under the opponent's Digimon targeted by this effect is less than or equal to those of your chosen Digimon at the timing when this card's effect activates, the effect will continue, even if the target's number of digivolution cards later increases.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon was targeted by this card's effect, then it digivolved and now has more digivolution cards than my chosen Digimon. Can my opponent's Digimon now attack and block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to digivolve it into a yellow Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait in my security stack, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You place it after shuffling.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's effect to digivolve a security card and I have a Tamer with [T.K. Takaishi], do I place 1 card in my security stack for <Recovery +1 (Deck)> before or after I shuffle my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Since you have 3 cards in your security stack [BT8-024 Angemon]'s effect will trigger, but effects that add or remove cards from the security stack aren't allowed while looking at a security stack, so the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to digivolve my [BT8-024 Angemon] into a level 5 yellow Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait in my security stack when my security stack has 4 cards. Can I activate my [BT8-024 Angemon]'s [Your Turn] effect to <Recovery +1 (Deck)> if it were to digivolve when my security stack has 3 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect delete 1 of my [Angemon] even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. If you have a Tamer with [Mimi Tachikawa] at the timing when this effect activates, your opponent's Digimon that was affected by the \"doesn't unsuspend\" effect doesn't unsuspend even if your Tamer with [Mimi Tachikawa] is later removed from the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card when I had a Tamer with [Mimi Tachikawa]. If my Tamer with [Mimi Tachikawa] is removed from the battle area by an effect after activating this card, can my opponent's Digimon that was affected by the \"doesn't unsuspend\" effect now unsuspend?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect digivolve any level Digimon into a Digimon card with [Sukamon] in my hand as long as it is a non-white Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. This effect doesn't target Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect digivolve a Digimon in the breeding area into a Digimon card with [Sukamon] in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that treats it as a card that has [Sukamon]. This is a rule and not an effect, therefore this card is treated as having [Sukamon] when the card is in your hand, trash, or any other area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Sukamon]\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. This card's name is treated as having [Sukamon], but it is not treated as [Sukamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be selected as the target of an effect that targets exactly [Sukamon] due to the text \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Sukamon]\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. This card is an Option card, therefore it can't become a target for an effect that targets Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card become a target for effects that activate for Digimon with [Sukamon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It changes into a white card with 3000 DP and an original name of [Sukamon]. In addition, it is also treated as the Digimon whose name is specified in (or specified to be included in) \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [XX]\" or \"(Rule) Name: Treated as having [XX].\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when this card's [Security] effect activates for a Digimon with \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [XX]\" or \"(Rule) Name: Treated as having [XX]\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It remains as a white Digimon with 3000 DP and an original name of [Sukamon]. The gained effect is carried over even if the Digimon digivolves or one or more of its top cards are trashed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If a card has changed to a white Digimon with 3000 DP and an original name of [Sukamon], then it digivolves or its top card is trashed by a \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e effect, what happens to that card's information?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can the effect of this card evolve from any Digimon of any Lv. to a Digimon card with \"Sukamon\" in its name in my hand, as long as it is not white?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Digimon in the Breeding Area are not targeted for the effect.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can the effect of this card evolve from a Digimon in the Breeding Area to a Digimon card with \"Sukamon\" in its name in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that also treats this card as containing \"Sukamon\" in its name. Since it is a rule, not an effect, this card will also be treated as containing \"Sukamon\" in its name, whether in hand, trash, or elsewhere.[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card's <Overflow X> name: \"Also treats as containing 'Sukamon'.\" What does this mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card is also treated as containing \"Sukamon\" in its name, but is not considered a \"Sukamon\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: <Overflow X> name: \"Also treated as containing 'Sukamon'.\" can I select \"Sukamon\" as the target of an effect that targets only \"Sukamon\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. This card is an option card, so it cannot be targeted by effects that target Digimon.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card targeted for the effect it activates on Digimon with \"Sukamon\" in its name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect changes the original name of one opponent's Digimon to \"Sukamon\", its original color to white, and its original DP to 3000.[4]",
      "question": "Q: \"Change an opponent's Digimon to its original name \"Sukamon\", White, DP 3000.\" What is the effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The information of the card you have is also changed by <Rules>. For example, the original name of \"BT15-035 Gelemon\" is \"Gelemon/Numemon\" by <Overflow X>, but if the information of the original card is changed by this effect, the original name will be \"Sukamon\" only.[4]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a card such as \"BT15-035 Geremon\", which has card information in <Overflow X>, is changed to the original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 by the effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The information on the card obtained by the effect remains the same. For example, if the information on the original card EX1-005 Tyrannomon is changed, the original color will be white and the color will be white and green because the effect of EX1-005 Tyrannomon also treats it as green.[4]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to a card such as \"EX1-005 Tyrannomon\" that has been given card information by the effect of this card, but is changed to the original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 by the effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The card also retains its original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP 3000. The effect given is carried over even if that one digivolved or the stacked cards are trashed.[4]",
      "question": "Q: If a card whose original name is changed to \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 is digivolved or stacked cards are trashed by <De-Digivolve>, what happens to the card's information?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The original name \"Sukamon\" - White - remains changed to DP3000, but the information on the card that it originally did not have cannot be changed. If the card becomes a tamer or a Digitama card and does not originally have DP, it will remain without DP.[4]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a card with the original name \"Sukamon\", white, DP3000 is stacked cards are trashed by <De-Digivolve>, etc. and become tamers or Digitama cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect return the target cards to the top of the deck even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While I have a Tamer with [Tai Kamiya] and my opponent has a Digimon with 10000 DP or more, can I use an effect that digivolves my Digimon to digivolve my [Agumon] in the battle area into this card in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT14-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect delete this Digimon even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You can't hatch a new Digi-Egg when you have another Digimon in your breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to hatch in my breeding area when I have a Digimon in my breeding area and a Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to place this card in my security stack when I have a Digimon in my breeding area and a Tamer, even if I can't hatch in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't have to place it. If there are requirements for the target card and that card is in a private area, performing the action is optional.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a yellow card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait in my hand when this card's inherited effect activates, do I have to place it at the bottom of my security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon's effect gave me \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and trashed 1 card in my hand. The number of cards in my hand was the same before and after the effect activated, so does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to attack using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards even when it's suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  At the end of your turn, the inherited effects on these cards activate, the activation order is decided, and then the attack occurs for the 1st Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. After activation of effects that are triggered upon attack declaration such as [When Attacking] effects and \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects but before the counter timing, the next activation would occur for the other inherited effect that was pending activation, but because the 1st Digimon is still attacking, you can't make a new attack declaration, and the 2nd Digimon's effect activation fails.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 Digimon with this card in their digivolution cards, can I use this card's inherited effect to attack using these 2 Digimon at the end of my turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.  This card's effect activates before your opponent blocks, therefore it can't be canceled even if a block is performed after activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My red Digimon attacked the opponent player and was blocked by an opponent's Digimon. Does this Digimon's effect activate in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.  This card's effect activates before your opponent blocks, therefore it can't be canceled even if a block is performed after activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon attacked the opponent player and was blocked by an opponent's Digimon. Does this Digimon's effect activate in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include only either a Digimon card or a Tamer card with the [SoC]\u00a0trait, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If the Tamer card doesn't have the [SoC]\u00a0trait, you can't add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Tamer card revealed for this card's [On Play] effect doesn't have the [SoC]\u00a0trait, does that mean I can't add it to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards revealed for this card's [On Play] effect include both a Digimon card and Tamer card with the [SoC]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to attack even when this Digimon is suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated this card's effect and paid 2 cost. This moved the memory to 1 or more on my opponent\u2019s side. Can this Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e isn't negated.  Even if the memory moves to 1 or more on your opponent's side, while this effect is activating or if there are any effects that are pending activation, the end of turn timing doesn't come until they finish activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this effect moved the memory to 1 or more on my opponent\u2019s side, is the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e gained for the turn negated for attacks with this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that the condition for \"if your opponent has 4 or less memory\" is fulfilled when the memory is at 1 through 10 on your side, 0, or 1 through 4 on your opponent's side at the timing when this effect activates.  Similarly, the condition for \"if they have 4 or more\" is fulfilled when the memory is at 4 through 10 on your opponent's side at the timing when this effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do this card's \"if your opponent has 4 or less memory\" and \"if they have 4 or more\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has 4 memory when this effect activates, do both the effect where 1 of my opponent's Digimon with 8000 DP or more can't attack until the end of their turn and the effect where I delete 1 of their Digimon with 6000 DP or less activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that the condition is fulfilled when the memory is at 4 through 10 on your opponent's side at the timing when this effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"if your opponent has 4 or more memory\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that the condition is fulfilled when the memory is at 1 through 4 on your side, 0, or 1 through 10 on your opponent's side at the timing when this effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"if you have 4 or less memory\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect activate when my opponent has no Digimon in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  If the number of digivolution cards under the target opponent's Digimon is less than or equal to those of the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards at the timing when this effect activates, the target Digimon can't attack until the effect ends at the end of your opponent's turn, even if the number of its digivolution cards later increases.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the digivolution cards under the target opponent's Digimon increase to become more than those under this Digimon after this card's inherited effect activates, can my opponent's Digimon now attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect activate when my opponent has no Digimon in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e, then I had 5 or more cards in your hand and trashed 1 card in my hand. The number of cards in my hand was the same before and after the effect activated, so does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 level 6 or higher card is among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn\u2019t activate for Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't referenced by effects, so they don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when a Digimon is played\" effects trigger for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It can't attack because the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies to Digimon played into the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area, and another effect moved the memory to 0 or more, and my turn continued.  If the Digimon that was played into the breeding area is then moved to the battle area by an effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area when it's affected by a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect activate when my opponent has no Digimon in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  It won't activate because the trigger timing for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect has already passed when [BT15-052 Puppetmon], [BT15-066 Machinedramon], or [BT15-079 Piedmon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect is used to play this card, so it won't trigger until the end of your opponent's next turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT15-052 Puppetmon], [BT15-066 Machinedramon], or [BT15-079 Piedmon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect to play this card from my hand, does this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I had 3 security cards at the start of my main phase, I used this card's effect to return 1 card from my security stack to the hand which reduced my security stack to 2 cards. Does this card's \"you may place 1 yellow Digimon card with the [Vaccine]\u00a0trait from your hand at the top or bottom of your security stack\" effect still activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that treats it as a card that has the [Numemon] name.  This is a rule and not an effect, therefore this card is treated as having the [Numemon] name when the card is in your hand, breeding area, or any other area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Numemon]\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be selected as the target of an effect that targets exactly [Numemon] due to the text \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Numemon]\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t. This card is in the trash upon the timing when a card is removed from your security stack, so the [All Turns] effect doesn't trigger and you don't gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate if this card itself is removed from your security stack when its effect trashes it from the security stack and plays it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. The timing when this card is played into the battle area and the timing when a card is removed from your security stack are the same, so the [All Turns] effect triggers and you gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate when this card in my security stack is played into the battle area by an effect that plays a Digimon card from the security stack, such as [BT15-092 Revelation of Light]'s [Main] effect or [ST10-06 Mastemon]'s [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent loses 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card\u2019s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates on an opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less, then its DP is reduced to 0 and it's deleted, does the \"[On Deletion] Lose 1 memory\" effect given to my opponent's Digimon at the same time cause my opponent to lose 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they activate.  This card's \"This Digimon gains all effects of cards with [Gammamon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards\" effect is an [All Turns] effect, so it will activate as soon as the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, [When Evolving] effects are gained and will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card, do the [When Digivolving] effects on digivolution cards with [Gammamon] activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if the memory gauge is now at 1 or greater on your opponent's side, you can activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e .[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon with [Gammamon] and a [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect into this card. Can I activate the [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card's [All Turns] effect and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect don't affect the inherited effects of digivolution cards with [Gammamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect allow me to activate the inherited effect of a digivolution card with [Gammamon] as an effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The effect only targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 Digimon in play. Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to give -2000 DP each to 2 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It's no longer affected by your opponent's effects as soon as it's suspended, so it can now unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is unsuspended, then it's suspended by an opponent's \"Suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon. That Digimon can't unsuspend during your opponent's next unsuspend phase\" effect, are effects that prevent unsuspending during the unsuspend phase negated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon when it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It's no longer affected by your opponent's effects as soon as it's suspended, so it can now unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is unsuspended, then it's suspended by an opponent's \"Suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon. That Digimon can't unsuspend during your opponent's next unsuspend phase\" effect, are effects that prevent unsuspending during the unsuspend phase negated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon when it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 level 6 or higher card is among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn\u2019t activate for Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't referenced by effects, so they don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when a Digimon is played\" effects trigger for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It can't attack because the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies to Digimon played into the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area, and another effect moved the memory to 0 or more, and my turn continued.  If the Digimon that was played into the breeding area is then moved to the battle area by an effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area when it's affected by a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.  It won't activate because the trigger timing for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect has already passed when [BT15-031 MetalSeadramon], [BT15-066 Machinedramon], or [BT15-079 Piedmon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect is used to play this card, so it won't trigger until the end of your opponent's next turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT15-031 MetalSeadramon], [BT15-066 Machinedramon], or [BT15-079 Piedmon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect to play this card from my hand, does this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve into a 2-color Digimon that includes white?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It's no longer affected by your opponent's effects as soon as it's suspended, so it can now unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is unsuspended, then it's suspended by an opponent's \"Suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon. That Digimon can't unsuspend during your opponent's next unsuspend phase\" effect, are effects that prevent unsuspending during the unsuspend phase negated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon when it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. You must suspend as many as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect suspend just 1 of my opponent's Digimon or 1 of their Tamers when they have 1 of each?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include only either a card with the [Machine]/[Cyborg]\u00a0trait or a black Tamer card, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a card with the [Machine]/[Cyborg]\u00a0trait and a black Tamer card, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I place 1 [Shuu Yulin] from my hand as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card at the start of my main phase, does this card's effect prevent it from being affected by the [Security] effects of my opponent's Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. As long as the conditions were met at the time you activated the effect, the effect will persist and it can't unsuspend until the end of your opponent\u2019s turn, even if the conditions are no longer met at a later point.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect and suspended 1 of my opponent's Digimon when a Tamer card with the [DigiPolice]\u00a0trait was in this Digimon's digivolution cards.  If the Tamer card with the [DigiPolice]\u00a0trait is then removed from this Digimon's digivolution cards, can my opponent's Digimon that I suspended now unsuspend?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect means that this card is also treated as a card with [Omnimon] while it's flipped over from the deck by a \"reveal this card from the deck\" effect.  If the effect is an effect such as \"add 1 [Omnimon] from the revealed cards,\" you can use that effect to add this card to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"while this card is revealed from the deck, its name is also treated as [Omnimon]\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that you can place up to a total of 2 cards consisting of either 1 [Agumon] or [Greymon] and 1 [Gabumon] and [Garurumon] in the digivolution cards for the DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"[Agumon]/[Greymon]\u00d7[Gabumon]/[Garurumon]\" specified in this card's DigiXros requirements mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 level 6 or higher card is among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn\u2019t activate for Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't referenced by effects, so they don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when a Digimon is played\" effects trigger for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It can't attack because the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies to Digimon played into the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area, and another effect moved the memory to 0 or more, and my turn continued.  If the Digimon that was played into the breeding area is then moved to the battle area by an effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area when it's affected by a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When only 1 of such cards is revealed, it's placed as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card according to the effect's processing order. You can't add a card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect and only 1 card with the [Machine]/[Cyborg]/[SoC]\u00a0trait is among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the card added to the hand from among the revealed cards for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect also have to have the [Machine]/[Cyborg]/[SoC]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.  It won't activate because the trigger timing for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect has already passed when [BT15-052 MetalSeadramon], [BT15-079 Puppetmon], or [BT15-079 Piedmon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect is used to play this card, so it won't trigger until the end of your opponent's next turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT15-052 MetalSeadramon], [BT15-052 Puppetmon], or [BT15-079 Piedmon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect to play this card from my hand, does this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve into a 2-color Digimon that includes white?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an effect plays an opponent's Digimon into the breeding area, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also activate when one of my effects plays an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that you \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e when the memory is at 1 through 10 on your side, 0, or 1 on your opponent's side at the timing when this Digimon is deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"[On Deletion] If your opponent has 1 or less memory, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Deletion] effect activates when my opponent has 1 memory, do both the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and \"gain 1 memory\" effects activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  If you don't perform the action specified for \"by X\" in such an effect, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the \"if a Tamer card with the [SoC]\u00a0trait is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e\" effect in this card's [When Attacking] effect even if I don't perform \"by trashing 1 card in your hand, delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I perform \"by trashing 1 card in your hand,\" does \"if a Tamer card with the [SoC]\u00a0trait is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e\" effect in this card's [When Attacking] effect activate even if my opponent doesn't have a Digimon with 3000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when that Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses both.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses whether or not a card is trashed and chooses the card to trash for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving]effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an effect plays an opponent's Digimon into the breeding area, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also activate when one of my effects plays an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  If you don't perform the action specified for \"by X\" in such an effect, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the \"if a Tamer card with the [SoC]\u00a0trait is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e\" effect in this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect even if I don't perform \"by trashing 1 card in your hand, this Digimon gets +2000 DP for the turn\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 level 6 or higher card is among the revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn\u2019t activate for Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't referenced by effects, so they don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when a Digimon is played\" effects trigger for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It can't attack because the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies to Digimon played into the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area, and another effect moved the memory to 0 or more, and my turn continued.  If the Digimon that was played into the breeding area is then moved to the battle area by an effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area when it's affected by a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Because nothing can be played from their trash, you can't switch the target of this card's attack, and the attack will continue using the target that was specified upon the attack declaration.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens for this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect if my opponent doesn't have any level 4 or lower Digimon cards in their trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an effect plays an opponent's Digimon into the breeding area, does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also activate when one of my effects plays an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.  It won't activate because the trigger timing for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect has already passed when [BT15-031 MetalSeadramon], [BT15-052 Puppetmon], or [BT15-066 Machinedramon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect is used to play this card, so it won't trigger until the end of your opponent's next turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT15-052 MetalSeadramon], [BT15-052 Puppetmon], or [BT15-066 Machinedramon]'s [End of Opponent's Turn] effect to play this card from my hand, does this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve into a 2-color Digimon that includes white?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an effect plays an opponent's Digimon into the breeding area, does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also activate when one of my effects plays an opponent's Digimon/Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You must delete as many as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to delete just 1 of my opponent's Digimon if my opponent has level 3, level 5, and level 7 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card was in the trash, my [Leviamon] attacked a player, and a Digimon or Tamer was played by a [Security] effect upon the security check.  In such cases, can I use this card's [Trash] [All Turns] effect to digivolve the attacking [Leviamon] into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only gets 1 additional security check.  [EX5-063 Leviamon]'s \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e is lost upon the digivolution but it gains \uff1cSecurity A. +2\uff1e, so the total possible security checks will be 3.  In the situation from your question, you have already performed 2 security checks, so you have 1 security check remaining.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My [EX5-063 Leviamon] with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e attacked a player, and a Digimon or Tamer was played by a [Security] effect upon the 2nd security check. This caused the [EX5-063 Leviamon] to digivolve into this card from the trash.  This card has \uff1cSecurity A. +2\uff1e, but does it get 2 additional security checks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card and [Leviamon] in my trash, then my [[[EX5-069|EX5-069 Biting Crush was placed in the battle area.  If my opponent's Digimon is played by an effect at this time, this card and [EX5-069 Biting Crush] will trigger simultaneously, but can I activate [EX5-069 Biting Crush]'s effect first to play [Leviamon]]] from my trash and then use the effect to digivolve that [Leviamon] into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that when you use this effect to play a Digimon card, you must choose one with the DP reduced from the maximum shown by 2000 for each each card in your opponent's security stack. The fewer cards in your opponent's security stack, the greater the DP can be for the Digimon card played.  For example, if your opponent has 3 security cards, the 13000 DP maximum is reduced by 6000, meaning that you can play a Digimon card with 7000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"for each of your opponent's security cards, remove 2000 from this effect's playable card's DP maximum\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon's effect gave me \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and trashed 1 card in my hand. The number of cards in my hand was the same before and after the effect activated, so does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The timing when this card is played into the battle area and the timing when a card is removed from your security stack are the same, so the [All Turns] effect can trigger and activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to give 1 of my opponent's Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e when this card is played by [BT13-012 GeoGreymon]'s [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Main] effect to play a Tamer card with [Sora Takenouchi], does the \"return 1 red Digimon card from your trash to the hand\" effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that when you use this effect to delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon, you must choose one with the DP reduced from the maximum shown by 2000 for each each card in your opponent's security stack. The fewer cards in your opponent's security stack, the greater the DP can be for the Digimon card you delete.  For example, if your opponent has 3 security cards, the 15000 DP maximum is reduced by 6000, meaning that you can delete an opponent's Digimon with 9000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"for each of your opponent's security cards, remove 2000 from this DP deletion effect's maximum\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you have a Digimon with [Gabumon], you must return 1 of your opponent's Digimon with the lowest DP to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have a Digimon with [Gabumon] and my opponent has 1 level 3 Digimon and 1 level 4 Digimon, can I choose the target to return to the hand for this card's effect from these 2 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This effect reads \"may digivolve into [MetalGarurumon] in your hand,\" therefore you can choose to not digivolve after placing [Garurumon] and [WereGarurumon] from your trash under [Gabumon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to place 1 [Garurumon] and 1 [WereGarurumon] from my trash under [Gabumon] but choose to not digivolve into [MetalGarurumon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to give -6000 DP twice to the same Digimon for a total of -12000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. As long as the conditions were met at the time you activated the effect, the effect will persist and will last until the end of your opponent\u2019s turn, even if the conditions are no longer met at a later point.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I had a Tamer with [Izzy Izumi], I used this card to give 1 of my opponent's Digimon \"[On Deletion] Trash the top card of your security stack.\"  If I later lose my Tamer with [Izzy Izumi], will my opponent's Digimon no longer be affected by that effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I only trash cards with the [Machine]/[Cyborg]\u00a0trait from among the cards revealed from my deck for this card's [Main] and [Security] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When only 1 of such cards is revealed, it's added to the hand according to the effect's processing order. You can't trash a card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when I use this card's effect and only 1 card with the [Machine]/[Cyborg]/ trait is among the cards revealed from my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must delete the card with the lowest play cost from among all your opponent's Digimon and Tamers for this effect.  In the example given in the question, you would delete the Digimon with a play cost of 3 as the card with the lowest play cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card when my opponent has a Digimon with a play cost of 3 and a Tamer with a play cost of 4, can I delete my opponent's Tamer with a play cost of 4 as the Tamer with the lowest play cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  If you don't perform the action specified for \"by X\" in such an effect, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't delete 1 of my Digimon for this card's [Main] effect, can I activate the part of the effect after \"then\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  \"Lv.-\" Digimon and Digimon cards without a level can't be targeted by effects that have levels in their conditions.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to trash a Lv.- Digimon card in my hand, can I delete my opponent's Lv.- Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You must delete as many as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete just 1 of my opponent's Digimon if my opponent has both level 4 and level 6 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While I have a Tamer with [Matt Ishida] and my opponent has a Digimon with 10000 DP or more, can I use an effect that digivolves my Digimon to digivolve my [Gabumon] in the battle area into this card in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT15-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  When placing cards from the battle area under this card, you can only choose the top cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card would be played, can the [Dark Masters]\u00a0trait cards I place under this card be from the digivolution cards of Digimon or under Tamers in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you don't perform the action specified for \"by X\" in such an effect, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't place 1 level 6 or lower card from my trash as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card for this card's [End of Your Turn] effect, can I activate the part of the effect after \"then\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and another of my Digimon with \uff1cCollision\uff1e is attacking.  I used the \uff1cCollision\uff1e effect to give \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to an opponent's Digimon that didn't originally have \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, and it blocks.  At such times, if both Digimon have the same DP, they both lose the battle, and they're deleted, does this card's inherited effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  The Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted before this card's inherited effect activates, therefore it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards battled an opponent's Digimon, and both Digimon lost the battle and were deleted.  Can I activate this card's inherited effect at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It triggers once.  If both Digimon lose a battle, both are deleted at the same time.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, other Digimon battled, and both Digimon lost the battle and were deleted.  At such times, if both Digimon have \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, how many times does this card's inherited effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It references the Digimon after it digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect reference the card for the Digimon before or after it digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect delete this Digimon even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect activate when a security card is removed from my security stack by one of my own effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After gaining \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card's [All Turns] effect during my opponent's turn, can this Digimon gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e again from this card's [All Turns] effect during my next turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect is triggered \"when a card is removed from your opponent's security stack,\" so even when you check multiple cards in your opponent's security stack, it is triggered and activates upon the first check. Also, this is a [Once Per Turn] effect, so this effect activates when a card is removed from their security stack upon the first check, and you can't activate the effect again upon the next check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect twice when I use one of my Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e to check 2 cards in my opponent's security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [All Turns] effect gives this Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e when this card attacks and I check my opponent's security stack, do I get an additional security check?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and 8000 DP or less attacked and a security check occurred. If I use this card's [All Turns] effect to delete my opponent's attacking Digimon before the 2nd security check is performed, can I prevent the 2nd security check?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  The effect triggers when a card is removed from a security stack, but this card is removed from the battle area before it can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon attacked a player and a security check occurred. If this card leaves the battle area due to the revealed card's [Security] effect, does this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.  This card's \"this Digimon gains all effects of [Goldramon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards\"  effect is an [All Turns] effect, so it will activate as soon as the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, [When Evolving] effects are gained and will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card digivolved from [BT14-018 Goldramon]. This Digimon gains all effects of [Goldramon] in digivolution cards, but does [BT14-018 Goldramon]'s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If this card's [All Turns] effect is used to gain a [When Digivolving] effect, this card's [When Digivolving] effect and the [When Digivolving] effect gained from the [All Turns] effect will trigger simultaneously upon the digivolution timing, therefore you may choose the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card digivolved from [EX3-035 Goldramon]. This Digimon gains all effects of [Goldramon] in digivolution cards, but after [EX3-035 Goldramon]'s [When Digivolving] effect activates and I return [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from the trash to the hand, can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to use [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect will trigger, but it can't be activated because its conditions aren't met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to activate an [On Deletion] effect at the end of an attack if the effect has conditions for activating, such as [EX4-053 Falcomon]'s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated. If it no longer has a trigger condition before it can be activated, it cannot be activated.[2]",
      "question": "Q: By the [Your Turn] effect of this card, I have [End of Attack] added to the inherited effects of [BT16-011 Garudamon (X Antibody)] and [BT13-014 Garudamon]. If I attack with this card, and at the end of the attack delete an opponent's [BT13-065 PlatinumSukamon] with the inherited effect of [BT13-014 Garudamon], then this card's [Your Turn] effect is lost because of <De-Digivolve>, can I activate [BT16-011 Garudamon (X Antibody)]'s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It references the Digimon after it digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect reference the card for the Digimon before or after it digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it prevents deletion.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect prevent deletion in battles against Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" effect and the \"return 1 of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon to the bottom of the deck\" effect when activating this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve it into a Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait in my security stack, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use an effect that digivolves my Digimon to digivolve this Digimon into a Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into a card with the [Angel]/[Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait in my security stack, then I placed 1 Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]/[Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait from the hand at the bottom of my security stack.  The number of cards in my security stack remained the same, but do \"when a card is removed from a security stack\" or \"When a card is added to a security stack\" effects trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The \"suspend all of your opponent's Digimon with as many or fewer digivolution cards as this Digimon\" part activates even if not DNA digivolving.  The \"none of their Digimon can unsuspend until the end of their turn\" part only activates if DNA digivolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activate when performing a non-DNA digivolution?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They trigger simultaneously, so the turn player activates their effect first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which effect activates first, an [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect on an opponent's Digimon that was played/digivolved, or this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will trigger at times such as when a Digimon is played by [BT5-092 Nokia Shiramine] or when a Digimon digivolves by [P-103 Offense Training]'s effect.  It won't trigger for effects that aren't digivolution effects, such as [BT4-011 Agunimon]'s effect that treats a Tamer as a level 3 red Digimon or [BT6-060 Deputymon]'s effect that allows digivolution requirements to be ignored.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What kinds of effects activated by my opponent will trigger this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only add 1 [Night Claw]\u00a0trait or 1 2-color card to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal for this card's [On Play] effect include only two types of cards, one being a [Night Claw]\u00a0trait card and one being a 2-color card, can I add both types to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] [On Play] effect to digivolve it into a level 4 Digimon card with the [Holy Beast]/[Free]\u00a0trait in the trash, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't occur.  When the [All Turns] effect is used to end an attack, the end of attack timing occurs without a battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [All Turns] effect is used to end an attack, does a battle occur?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  This effect forces the attack to end, therefore the end of attack timing occurs as soon as the effect activates. If activation occurs before the counter timing, the counter timing and following procedures aren't performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [All Turns] effect is used to end an attack when a \uff1cRaid\uff1e effect has switched the target of attack, does the counter timing occur?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  The effect triggers when a card is removed from a security stack, but this card is removed from the battle area before it can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacked a player and a security check occurred. If this card leaves the battle area due to the revealed card's [Security] effect, does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -4000 DP until the end of their turn\" effect and the \"1 of their Digimon gains \uff1cSecurity A. -2\uff1e until the end of their turn\" effect when activating this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.  In such cases, only the player with 1 or more security cards trashes the top card of their security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect activate when a player has 0 cards in their security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include only either a card with [Pulsemon] in its text or a card with the [Abadin Electronics]\u00a0trait, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a card with [Pulsemon] in its text and a card with the [Abadin Electronics]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] [On Play] effect to digivolve it into a level 4 Digimon card with the [Insectoid]/[Free]\u00a0trait in the trash, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon\" effect and the \"gain 1 memory\" effect when activating this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon. It can't unsuspend during your opponent's next unsuspend phase\" effect and the \"gain 2 memory\" effect when activating this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon with the [Insectoid]\u00a0trait and this card in its digivolution cards is suspended, can this card's inherited effect switch the target of an opponent's Digimon's attack to that Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect suspend 1 each of my opponent's Digimon and Tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"trash the top card of your opponent's security stack\" effect and the \"gain 2 memory\" effect when activating this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon while it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It references the Digimon after it digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect reference the card for the Digimon before or after it digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that this Digimon can no longer leave the battle area by processing other than deletion. Such processing includes \"return to the hand/deck,\" \"place in the security stack,\" and \"place under another Digimon or Tamer.\"  It only leaves the battle area by deletion.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"this Digimon can't leave the battle area other than by deletion\" in this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the card is trashed.  Digimon without DP can't be in the battle area according to the rules, therefore upon the rule check timing, the card is considered a card that doesn't belong in the battle area and is trashed.  This is why that card is trashed even if that Digimon is affected by this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon that's affected by this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect would be trashed because it has no DP, is it still prevented from leaving the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"until the end of your opponent's turn, 1 of your Digimon can't have its DP reduced by your opponent's effects and isn't affected by \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) effects\" effect and the \"1 of your Digimon gains \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and \uff1cReboot\uff1e until the end of your opponent's turn\" effect when activating this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  Even if an effect activates and increases your opponent's security stack, their security stack must have 3 or more cards when the effect finishes activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent had 2 cards in their security attack, they activated [ST10-06 Mastemon]'s [When Digivolving] effect, and the effect that places a card from their trash in their security stack and the effect that plays a level 5 or lower Digimon card activated. My opponent temporarily has 3 cards in their security stack, then it becomes 2 cards. Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"\uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) 1 of your opponent's Digimon\" effect and the \"delete 1 of their Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less\" effect when activating this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. The minimum value is 0, the resulting play cost can't be negative.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use the \"reduce the play costs of all of your opponent's Digimon by 1\" effect and all of my opponent's Digimon have their play costs reduced by 3, does an opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 2 now have a play cost of -1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't. This card's effect only reduces the play costs of Digimon in your opponent's battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use the \"reduce the play costs of all of your opponent's Digimon by 1\" effect, is the play cost also reduced for Digimon cards in areas other than the battle area (such as my opponent's hand or trash)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [All Turns] effect to digivolve it into a Digimon card with the [Beast Dragon]/[Undead]/[SoC]\u00a0trait in the hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they activate.  This card's \"This Digimon gains all effects of cards with [Gammamon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards\"  effect is an [All Turns] effect, so it will activate as soon as the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, [When Evolving] effects are gained and will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card, do the [When Digivolving] effects on digivolution cards with [Gammamon] activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The \"until the end of your opponent's turn, this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of their Digimon\" part activates even if not DNA digivolving.  The \"place 1 of your opponent's Digimon with as high or lower a level as the number of cards in your or their security stack at the bottom of their security stack\" part only activates if DNA digivolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activate when performing a non-DNA digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect places 1 of your opponent's Digimon with as high or lower a level as the number of cards in either your or their security stack at the bottom of their security stack, not the total number of cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect place 1 of my opponent's Digimon with as high or lower a level as the total number of cards in my or their security stack at the bottom of their security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If your opponent has a Digimon with as high or lower a level than the number of either your or your opponent's security cards, you must place those Digimon at the bottom of their security stack for this card's [When Digivolving] effect.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have 5 security cards, and my opponent has 1 security card.  Can I refer to the number of my opponent's security cards for this card's [When Digivolving] effect so I don't place their Digimon at the bottom of the security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"when this card would be played\" effect also activate when my opponent has a Digimon with the [Boss]\u00a0trait?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \u3053\u306e\u30ab\u30fc\u30c9\u3092\u767b\u5834\u3055\u305b\u308b\u3068\u304d\u3001\u7279\u5fb4\u306b\u300c\u30d0\u30f3\u30c1\u30e7\u30fc\u300d\u3092\u6301\u3064\u30c7\u30b8\u30e2\u30f3\u304c\u3044\u3066\u3001\u81ea\u5206\u306e\u30c8\u30e9\u30c3\u30b7\u30e5\u304b\u3089\u3001\u7279\u5fb4\u306b\u300cD-\u30d6\u30ea\u30ac\u30fc\u30c9\u300d\u3092\u6301\u3064\u30ab\u30fc\u30c96\u679a\u3092\u30c7\u30c3\u30ad\u306e\u4e0a\u306b\u623b\u3059\u3053\u3068\u304c\u3067\u304d\u308b\u5834\u5408\u3001\u652f\u6255\u3046\u767b\u5834\u30b3\u30b9\u30c8\u3092\u5408\u8a08\u3067-12\u3067\u304d\u307e\u3059\u304b\uff1f"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses both.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses whether or not a card is trashed and chooses the card to trash for this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] [When Digivolving]effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose my [LM-020 Quantumon] that isn't affected by Digimon effects as the target of this card's [When Digivolving] effect, then delete just my opponent's Digimon without deleting my [LM-020 Quantumon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve it into a Digimon card with [Leomon] in my hand/trash regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: 2 copies of this Digimon are deleted at the same time, and their [On Deletion] effects triggered simultaneously. Can I play 1 Tamer card with [Myotismon] in its text when the 1st effect activates, then use the 2nd effect to play a Tamer card with the same name as the Tamer card played by the 1st effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: 2 copies of this Digimon are deleted at the same time, and their [On Deletion] effects triggered simultaneously. Can I play 1 Tamer card with [Myotismon] in its text when the 1st effect activates, then use the 2nd effect to play a Tamer card with the same name as the Tamer card played by the 1st effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"\uff1cDraw 2\uff1e and trash 1 card in your hand\" effect and the \"you may play 1 Digimon card with [Pulsemon] in its text and 6000 DP or less from your trash without paying the cost. At the next end of your opponent\u2019s turn, delete it\" effect when activating this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [All Turns] effect to digivolve into [Fenriloogamon] in my trash, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"1 of your Digimon gains \uff1cRush\uff1e for the turn and may attack a player\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate if not DNA digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Because [BT16-077 Dinobeemon] is already using [BT16-091 Beastly Storm Dance of Affection]'s effect to attack, a played Digimon can gain \uff1cRush\uff1e, but it can't use this card's effect to attack.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I used [BT16-091 Beastly Storm Dance of Affection]'s effect to DNA digivolve into this card, then I used [BT16-091 Beastly Storm Dance of Affection]'s effect to attack. At such times, can a Digimon played using this card's [When Digivolving] effect gain \uff1cRush\uff1e and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does the [When Attacking] effect of this card [End of Your Turn] activate \"Until the end of Your Turn, one of your Digimon gains \"Quick Attack\" and can attack a player with that Digimon\" even if it has not been digivolved?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since \"BT16-077 Dinobymon\" is attacking under the effect of \"BT16-091 Jiayoi no Beast Body Storm Dance,\" the Digimon played can gain \"Quick Attack,\" but cannot attack under the effect of this card.[4]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolved DNA digivolved to this card under the effect of \"BT16-091 Compassionate Beast Body Storm Dance\" and attacked it under the effect of \"BT16-091 Compassionate Beast Body Storm Dance\". At this time, can the Digimon played by this card's [When Attivolving] effect get \"Quick Attack\" and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Digimon that are given \"Quick Attack\" by this effect will attack as much as possible.[5]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to give a Digimon of mine a \"Quick Attack\" and then not attack with that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If only I have a level 4 or lower Digimon, can I choose to not activate this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect and not delete my level 4 or lower Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -7000 DP for the turn\" effect and the \"delete 1 of their unsuspended Digimon\" effect when activating this card's [When Digivolving] [End of Attack] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have 2 or fewer cards in your security stack when the effect activates, repeat <Recovery +1 (Deck)> until there are 3 cards in your security stack. You don't have to do anything when the effect activates if you have 3 or more cards in your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How exactly do I perform \"<Recovery +1 (Deck)> until there are 3 cards in your security stack\" in this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate when this Digimon itself moves from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It activates during the breeding phase. If effects trigger during the breeding phase, the main phase will come after all effects have activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon moves from the breeding area to the battle area during the breeding phase, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate during the breeding phase or main phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I moved one of my Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area when all of my Digimon's DP is reduced by an effect. The moved Digimon's DP becomes 0 and is deleted due to the DP-reducing effect, but does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  When a card with an effect that's pending activation leaves an area while activation is pending, the effect can no longer be activated.  In this case, the effect triggers when this card is moved, but because the DP becomes 0 before activation, this card is deleted and removed from the battle area, and the effect can't be activated.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I moved this card from the breeding area to the battle area when all of my Digimon's DP is reduced by an effect. At such times, if this card's DP becomes 0 and is deleted due to the DP-reducing effect after it's moved, can I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to play 1 Tamer card from my hand without paying the cost even when I don't have [Ukkomon] in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I perform a DigiXros when a Digimon with DigiXros requirements is played into the breeding area by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's returned. In such cases, only the top card is returned to the hand and all digivolution cards are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The Digimon played using this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect digivolved. Is that Digimon returned to the hand at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  The rest of the effect won't activate if you don't perform the specified action in effects with \"by X\" conditions.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon DNA digivolves into a red or yellow Digimon, does the \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -3000 DP for the turn\" effect activate even if I don't suspend this Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's returned. In such cases, only the top card is returned to the hand and all digivolution cards are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The Digimon played using this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect digivolved. Is that Digimon returned to the hand at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  The rest of the effect won't activate if you don't perform the specified action in effects with \"by X\" conditions.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon DNA digivolves into a blue or green Digimon, does the \"trash any 3 digivolution cards under your opponent's Digimon\" effect activate even if I don't suspend this Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's returned. In such cases, only the top card is returned to the hand and all digivolution cards are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The Digimon played using this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect digivolved. Is that Digimon returned to the hand at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  The rest of the effect won't activate if you don't perform the specified action in effects with \"by X\" conditions.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon DNA digivolves into a black or yellow Digimon, does the \"\uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) 1 of your opponent's Digimon\" effect activate even if I don't suspend this Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The Digimon played using this card's [On Deletion] effect digivolved. Is that Digimon deleted at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Digi-Egg cards in the battle area and breeding area are treated as Digimon, so they can be trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to trash 1 Digi-Egg card in the breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must perform both \"deleting 1 of your [Ukkomon] and trashing 1 of your Digimon in the breeding area\" to play a [BigUkkomon] into the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I perform just \"deleting 1 of your [Ukkomon]\" or \"trashing 1 of your Digimon in the breeding area\" to play a [BigUkkomon] into the breeding area for this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \u201cyou may play.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: After performing \"deleting 1 of your [Ukkomon]\" and \"trashing 1 of your Digimon in the breeding area,\" can I choose to not play a [BigUkkomon] into the breeding area for this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's processed.  \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) is processed when a card is sent from the area or from under a card to another area. In this case, it's processed because a card from the area is placed in the trash.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Is \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) processed when this card's [Main] effect trashes a Digimon with \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) in the breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's processed.  \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) is processed when a card is sent from the area or from under a card to another area. In this case, it's processed because it's placed into the trash from under a card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Is \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) processed when this card's [Main] effect trashes a Digimon in the breeding area that has a card with \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to play Digimon without DNA digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not play Digimon for this card's [Main] effect but DNA digivolve using 2 of my Digimon that were already in the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must choose to gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and attack a player or choose to neither gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e or attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to give the DNA digivolved Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e without attacking?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to play Digimon without DNA digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not play Digimon for this card's [Main] effect but DNA digivolve using 2 of my Digimon that were already in the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to play Digimon without DNA digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not play Digimon for this card's [Main] effect but DNA digivolve using 2 of my Digimon that were already in the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the part after \"then\" in this card's effect if I don't have a Digimon with [Dorugoramon]\u00a0?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 5 cards in my security stack. Can I use this card\u2019s \"when this card would be used\" effect to only trash 1 security card and reduce the cost by 2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  An attack declaration can't be made during an attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon attacks and digivolves into this card by an effect during the attack. Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to attack again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT16-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  A \"switch the target of attack\" effect such as \uff1cRaid\uff1e affects the attacking Digimon itself, therefore the target of attack can be switched to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When \"isn't affected by your opponent's effects\" is gained from this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can the target of attack be switched to this Digimon using a \"switch the target of attack\" effect such as \uff1cRaid\uff1e on an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect activate when a security card is removed from my security stack by one of my own effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"then\" part of this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate even if [Magnamon (X Antibody)] or an [Armor Form]\u00a0trait card isn't in this Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can play multiple Digimon from digivolution cards, but they are played at the same time during a single timing, therefore you can only \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e twice if 2 of my Digimon are played from digivolution cards at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to gain 1 memory when I activate \uff1cMind Link\uff1e\u00a0to 1 of your Digimon (Place this Tamer as that Digimon's bottom digivolution card if there are no Tamer cards in its digivolution cards) on a digivolution card of a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and place a Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to digivolve when I activate \uff1cMind Link\uff1e\u00a0to 1 of your Digimon (Place this Tamer as that Digimon's bottom digivolution card if there are no Tamer cards in its digivolution cards) on a digivolution card of a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and place a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's inherited effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with the [SoC]\u00a0trait in the trash, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Even if you have multiple Tamers with [Tai Kamiya], you can only return 1 card to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to return 2 cards with [Garurumon], [Greymon], or [Omnimon] from my trash to the hand when I have 2 Tamers with [Tai Kamiya]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you to DNA digivolve a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon in your hand that has [DNA Digivolution]. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If there's a valid target, you must choose it when you activate the effect. You can't choose to not activate the effect when there is a valid target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has a Digimon with 3000 DP or less, can I activate this card's effect and gain 1 memory but choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can choose your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less as a target, even if the chosen Digimon has an effect that prevents it from being deleted, in order to get the \u201cif this effect didn't delete\u201d part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 3000 DP or less and an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent\u2019s effects,\u201d and another Digimon with 3000 DP or less but no effect. Can I intentionally have this card\u2019s effect target the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion and gain 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This inherited effect's condition is fulfilled if the memory is at 0 through 10 on your opponent's side when a DP-based deletion effect activates on a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"while you have 0 or less memory\" in this card\u2019s inherited effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a card with the [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait or a Tamer card with an inherited effect, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a card with the [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait and a Tamer card with an inherited effect, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means a Tamer card with \"Inherited Effect\" in its lower text.  A Tamer card with a [Security] effect in its lower text isn't a \"Tamer card with inherited effects.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"Tamer card with inherited effects\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If there's a valid target, you must choose it when you activate the effect. You can't choose to not activate the effect when there is a valid target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has a Digimon with 4000 DP or less, can I activate this card's effect and gain 3000 memory but choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can choose your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 4000 DP or less as a target, even if the chosen Digimon has an effect that prevents it from being deleted, in order to get the \u201cif this effect didn't delete\u201d part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 4000 DP or less and an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent\u2019s effects,\u201d and another Digimon with 4000 DP or less but no effect. Can I intentionally have this card\u2019s effect target the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion and have this Digimon get 3000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This inherited effect's condition is fulfilled if the memory is at 0 through 10 on your opponent's side when a DP-based deletion effect activates on a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"while you have 0 or less memory\" in this card\u2019s inherited effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [Takuya Kanbara] digivolves as a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement mean that [Takuya Kanbara] is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Because you're digivolving from a Tamer, it isn't considered an unsuspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates EX3-053 [Metallicdramon]'s [On Play] effect. Can I digivolve an unsuspended [Takuya Kanbara] using this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement in the next turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  P-103 [Offense Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate P-103 [Offense Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and digivolve using this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving or de-digivolving, therefore it's deleted at the end of the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGreymon], then it digivolves or is affected by \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e, what happens to the \"delete this Digimon at the end of this turn\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't deleted because it's no longer considered a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has a Tamer card in its digivolution cards, and I used its [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGreymon], then it was affected by a \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e effect and became a Tamer. Does the \"delete this Digimon at the end of this turn\" effect delete this Tamer at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving, therefore it plays [AncientGreymon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used BT3-109 [Back for Revenge!] on this Digimon, then I used this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGreymon]. After this Digimon is deleted at the end of this turn, does BT3-109 [Back for Revenge!]'s effect play this card or [AncientGreymon] into the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not deleted. Effects that are processed when a specific timing is reached are processed as triggered when the timing is reached. If the Digivolved by this card's effect at the end of the turn, the \"Delete this Digimon at the end of this turn\" of this card is not processed because the timing to be at the end of the turn has passed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have a situation where I have my \"BT17-012 BurningGreymon\" with \"BT18-088 Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto\" as its digivolution card. At the End of Turn, \"BT17-012 Vritramon\" attacked by the digivolving source effect of \"BT18-088 Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto\", and \"BT17-012 Vritramon\" digivolved to this card by its [When Attacking] effect. At this time, if this card's [When Digivolving] effect evolved into \"AncientGreymon\", will that \"AncientGreymon\" be deleted by this card's effect, even though the timing when the turn ended has already passed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [Takuya Kanbara] digivolves as a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement mean that [Takuya Kanbara] is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Because you're digivolving from a Tamer, it isn't considered an unsuspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates EX3-053 [Metallicdramon]'s [On Play] effect. Can I digivolve an unsuspended [Takuya Kanbara] using this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement in the next turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  P-103 [Offense Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate P-103 [Offense Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and digivolve using this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [When Attacking] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in the hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They trigger simultaneously, so the turn player chooses the effect to activate first.  However, if you activate the [When Attacking] effect first and digivolve, \uff1cRaid\uff1e can no longer be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card attacks, does its \uff1cRaid\uff1e or [When Attacking] effect activate first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If there's a valid target, you must choose it when you activate the effect. You can't choose to not activate the effect when there is a valid target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has a Digimon with 6000 DP or less, can I activate this card's effect and gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e but choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can choose your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 6000 DP or less as a target, even if the chosen Digimon has an effect that prevents it from being deleted, in order to get the \u201cif this effect didn't delete\u201d part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 6000 DP or less and an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent\u2019s effects,\u201d and another Digimon with 6000 DP or less but no effect. Can I intentionally have this card\u2019s effect target the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion and gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. All [Security] effects on non-Option cards activate normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards performs a security check, if the checked card is a Digimon card or a Tamer card, does that card's [Security] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If digivolution is performed using the [Main] effect, you must digivolve for a digivolution cost of 3.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve [Takuya Kanbara] as a level 4 red Digimon, can I digivolve by paying a cost of 4 using the standard digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  You can activate the effect when there is no target, but the effect will end without anything happening.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate \"1 of your [Gabumon] may digivolve into [MetalGarurumon] in the hand\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect when I don't have a [Gabumon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If there's a valid target, you must choose it when you activate the effect. You can't choose to not activate the effect when there is a valid target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has a Digimon with 8000 DP or less, can I activate this card's effect and have this Digimon get 3000 DP but choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can choose your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 8000 DP or less as a target, even if the chosen Digimon has an effect that prevents it from being deleted, in order to get the \u201cif this effect didn't delete\u201d part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 8000 DP or less and an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent\u2019s effects,\u201d and another Digimon with 8000 DP or less but no effect. Can I intentionally have this card\u2019s effect target the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion and have this Digimon get 3000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.  When your opponent's Digimon is deleted in battle, it causes ST7-05 [Growlmon]'s inherited effect and \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e on the opponent's Digimon to trigger simultaneously. The turn player's effect activates first, the memory becomes 1, and this Digimon's [Your Turn] effect can no longer activate, therefore it's deleted by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The memory is at 0, I use this Digimon with ST7-05 [Growlmon] in its digivolution cards to attack, and it deleted an opponent's Digimon with \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e in battle. Is this Digimon deleted by the \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e effect at such times?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means for every 10 cards in the total sum of cards in your trash and the cards in your opponent's trash.  For example, if you have 12 cards in your trash and your opponent has 8 cards in their trash, the total would be 20. Therefore, you trash 2 cards from your opponent's security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"For every 10 total cards in both players' trashes\" mean for every 10 cards in either me or my opponent's trashes?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you to DNA digivolve a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon in your hand that has [DNA Digivolution]. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a card with the [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait or a Tamer card with an inherited effect, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a card with the [Hybrid]/[Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait and a Tamer card with an inherited effect, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means a Tamer card with \"Inherited Effect\" in its lower text.  A Tamer card with a [Security] effect in its lower text isn't a \"Tamer card with inherited effects.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"Tamer card with inherited effects\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [Koji Minamoto] digivolves as a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement mean that [Koji Minamoto] is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Because you're digivolving from a Tamer, it isn't considered an unsuspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates EX3-053 [Metallicdramon]'s [On Play] effect. Can I digivolve an unsuspended [Koji Minamoto] using this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement in the next turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  P-104 [Mental Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate P-104 [Mental Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and digivolve using this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement in the next turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving or de-digivolving, therefore it's deleted at the end of the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGarurumon], then it digivolves or is affected by \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e, what happens to the \"delete this Digimon at the end of this turn\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't deleted because it's no longer considered a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has a Tamer card in its digivolution cards, and I used its [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGarurumon], then it was affected by a \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e effect and became a Tamer. Does the \"delete this Digimon at the end of this turn\" effect delete this Tamer at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving, therefore it plays [AncientGarurumon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used BT3-109 [Back for Revenge!] on this Digimon, then I used this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [AncientGarurumon]. After this Digimon is deleted at the end of this turn, does BT3-109 [Back for Revenge!]'s effect play this card or [AncientGarurumon] into the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not deleted. Effects that are processed when a specific timing is reached are processed as triggered when the timing is reached. If the Digivolved by this card's effect at the end of the turn, the \"Delete this Digimon at the end of this turn\" of this card is not processed because the timing to be at the end of the turn has passed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have a situation where I have my \"BT17-023 KendoGarurumon\" with \"BT18-088 Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto\" as its digivolution card. At the End of Turn, I attacked with the [When Attacking] effect of \"BT18-088 Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto\" and \"BT17-023 Galummon\" evolved into this card with the [When Attacking] effect of \"BT17-023 Galummon\". At this time, if this card's [When Digivolving] effect evolved into \"Ancient Garurumon\", will that \"Ancient Garurumon\" be deleted by this card's effect, although the timing of the end of turn has already passed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [Koji Minamoto] digivolves as a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement mean that [Koji Minamoto] is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.  \"When a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger when a Tamer digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement to digivolve, do \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Because you're digivolving from a Tamer, it isn't considered an unsuspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates EX3-053 [Metallicdramon]'s [On Play] effect. Can I digivolve an unsuspended [Koji Minamoto] using this card's \"[Koji Minamoto]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement in the next turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  P-104 [Mental Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate P-104 [Mental Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect and digivolve using this card's \"[Takuya Kanbara]: Cost 2\" digivolution requirement in the next turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [When Attacking] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's 2nd [When Attacking] effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait in the hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They trigger simultaneously, so the turn player chooses the effect to activate first.  However, if you activate the 2nd [When Attacking] effect first and digivolve, the 1st [When Attacking] can no longer be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card attacks, which of its 2 [When Attacking] effects activate first?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's returned. In such cases, only the top card is returned to the hand. All digivolution cards are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The Digimon played using this card's effect digivolved. Is that Digimon returned to the hand at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, then it's sent to the trash, do I return that Digimon card from my trash to the hand at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If digivolution is performed using the [Main] effect, you must digivolve for a digivolution cost of 3.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve [Koji Minamoto] as a level 4 blue Digimon, can I digivolve by paying a cost of 4 using the standard digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  You can activate the effect when there is no target, but the effect will end without anything happening.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate \"1 of your [Agumon] may digivolve into [WarGreymon] in the hand\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect when I don't have an [Agumon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate when the hand increases from the digivolution bonus upon digivolution by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t.  Although cards are added to both players' hands, they are added at the same timing, therefore your opponent only adds 1 card from their security stack to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both my hand and my opponent's hand increase when we both draw 1 card from our decks using an effect such as BT16-020 [GaoGamon]'s [When Digivolving] effect, does my opponent add 2 cards from the top of their security stack to the hand using this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to play a Tamer card even if I don't return a card from the trash to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you don't perform the action specified for \"by X\" in such an effect, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 or fewer security cards, can I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to activate <Recovery +1 (Deck)> even if I don't place 1 [Leon Alexander] from my hand as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a Digimon card with [Kyubimon], [Taomon], or [Sakuyamon] or [Rika Nonaka] or 1 Option card with a cost of 2 or more, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a Digimon card with [Kyubimon], [Taomon], or [Sakuyamon] and [Rika Nonaka] or 1 Option card with a cost of 2 or more, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the Option card you use has a cost of 2 or more, this card's inherited effect activates regardless of the actual cost paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate an effect that reduces the cost of an Option card with a cost of 2 or more and I only pay a cost of 1, or if I do not pay the cost at all by activating an effect that allows me to use an Option card without paying the cost, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  It doesn't activate if the cost of an Option card consistently changes when it's in the hand and becomes 1 or less due to that card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if I use an Option card when it has a cost of 1 or less due to a \"reduce the cost of this card in the hand by 1\" effect on a card such as  such as BT2-099 [Glorious Burst] or BT8-097 [Crimson Blaze]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the Option card you use has a cost of 2 or more, this card's inherited effect activates regardless of the actual cost paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate an effect that reduces the cost of an Option card with a cost of 2 or more and I only pay a cost of 1, or if I do not pay the cost at all by activating an effect that allows me to use an Option card without paying the cost, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  It doesn't activate if the cost of an Option card consistently changes when it's in the hand and becomes 1 or less due to that card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if I use an Option card when it has a cost of 1 or less due to a \"reduce the cost of this card in the hand by 1\" effect on a card such as  such as BT2-099 [Glorious Burst] or BT8-097 [Crimson Blaze]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -3000 DP\" effect and the \"suspend 1 or your opponent's Digimon\" effect when activating this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [When Digivolving] effect and inherited effect don't allow ignoring color requirements, so you can only use cards that meet the color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I ignore the color requirements when I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect or inherited effect in order to use an Option card with [Plug-In] or a yellow Option card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my red or yellow [Marcus Damon] is deleted, can I use this card's inherited effect to place the deleted [Marcus Damon] card from my trash on top of my security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [When Digivolving] effect doesn't allow ignoring color requirements, so you can only use cards that meet the color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I ignore the color requirements when I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect in order to use an Option card with [Plug-In] or a yellow Option card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the Option card you use has a cost of 2 or more, this card's [Your Turn] effect activates regardless of the actual cost paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate an effect that reduces the cost of an Option card with a cost of 2 or more and I only pay a cost of 1, or if I do not pay the cost at all by activating an effect that allows me to use an Option card without paying the cost, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  It doesn't activate if the cost of an Option card consistently changes when it's in the hand and becomes 1 or less due to that card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate if I use an Option card when it has a cost of 1 or less due to a \"reduce the cost of this card in the hand by 1\" effect on a card such as  such as BT2-099 [Glorious Burst] or BT8-097 [Crimson Blaze]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  This card's [When Digivolving] effect affects \"all of your opponent's Digimon,\" therefore it will also apply to opponent's Digimon that are newly played until the end of their turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon has [Leon Alexander] in its digivolution cards, and I activated its [When Digivolving] effect. Can it give \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e to my opponent's Digimon that are played into the battle area afterward?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both the \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -6000 DP\" effect and <Recovery +1 (Deck)> when activating this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Once the [End of Your Turn] effect activates, you can perform the part of the effect after \"then\" regardless of the number of security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 3 security cards, can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to gain <Recovery +1 (Deck)> and then use 1 of my Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon if my security stack increases to 4 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal with this card's effect include only an [Argomon] or [Rhythm], can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both an [Argomon] and [Rhythm], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is played by another card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's inherited effect to digivolve into [Eosmon] in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose the targets.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"when this card would be digivolved into\" effect allow me to choose the targets to suspend from among my Tamers and my opponent's Tamers when this card would be digivolved into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If you have 4 or more [Argomon] in your trash after this card or [Argomon] in this card's digivolution cards is sent to the trash, you can use this card's [On Deletion] effect to play a level 6 [Argomon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon was deleted when I had 3 [Argomon] in my trash. At such times, can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to play 1 level 6 [Argomon] from my hand without paying the cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to delete another of my level 3 Digimon cards with the [Beast]\u00a0trait and then play that deleted Digimon card from the trash without paying the cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If a card is removed from the trash before a triggered [On Deletion] effect activates, that [On Deletion] effect can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's inherited effect to delete a level 3 Digimon card with an [On Deletion] effect and the [Beast]\u00a0trait, then I played that deleted Digimon card from the trash without paying the cost. Can I activate the deleted Digimon's [On Deletion] effect at such times?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 4 cost and placing this card as 1 of your level 5 or higher Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 4 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 4 cost even when I don't have any level 5 or higher Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must choose to suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon and attack, or you must choose to not suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon and not attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to place this card as 1 of my level 5 or higher Digimon's bottom digivolution card and suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon without attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, if this card is played before the effect activates, this card's [All Turns] inherited effect can no longer be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon with multiples of this card in its digivolution cards would be deleted, can I use this card's [All Turns] inherited effect to play multiples of [Parasitemon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The effect reads \"up to 4,\" therefore you can place any number from 1 to 4.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to place just 2 cards in digivolution cards when I have 4 level 5 or lower [Argomon] in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  \"Lv.-\" Digimon don't have a level, therefore they can't be chosen as targets for an effect that deletes up to 4 levels' worth of Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to delete up to 4 levels' worth of Digimon, can I delete my opponent's \"Lv.-\" Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If a card is removed from the trash before a triggered [On Deletion] effect activates, that [On Deletion] effect can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: BT17-048 [Argomon] was deleted while it had an [Argomon] with an [On Deletion] effect in its digivolution cards. I first used BT17-048 [Argomon]'s [On Deletion] effect to play this card. At such times, if I use this card's [On Play] effect to place [Argomon] in digivolution cards before activating the [On Deletion] effect, what happens to that effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  Even if a target Digimon of this card's [When Digivolving] effect becomes a level 9 or higher Digimon, it can't attack players.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I chose 1 opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 8 or less as the target for \"can't attack players\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect.  If that opponent's Digimon digivolves during their next turn and becomes a Digimon with a play cost of 9 or more, can it now attack players?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: 1 card.  Unless specified otherwise, you can only place 1 of each of the cards shown in the DigiXros requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How many [Machinedramon] cards can I place under this card when I DigiXros it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct. In addition to Digimon from the hand or battle area, you may also place cards from the trash for the DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"cards from your trash may also be placed for this card's DigiXros\" mean that I can place cards from my hand, battle area, and/or trash for the DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This effect reads \"you may play,\" so if you perform the conditions specified for \"by X,\" you may choose whether or not to activate the effect shown in text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to place [Doomsday Clock] from my hand or trash as a digivolution card, can I choose to not play [Diaboromon] Tokens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  You can play 2 [Diaboromon] Tokens, but they are played at the same time during a single timing, therefore the effect only triggers once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect on a card like BT2-059 [Kurisarimon] or BT2-053 [Keramon] trigger twice when I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to play 2 [Diaboromon] Tokens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to switch the attack target to my unsuspended Digimon with [Diaboromon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Because your opponent's Digimon was the target of the battle and is no longer in play, a battle doesn't occur. However, the counter timing and end of attack timing still exist, therefore any applicable effects will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon without digivolution cards, and this card's [Your Turn] effect deletes that Digimon, what happens to the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It triggers at the timing when this card is in the trash and your [Dorugamon] would be deleted.  [Trash] means that an effect can trigger and activate when the card is in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When exactly is the timing when this card's [Trash] [All Turns] effect triggers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, the DP-reducing effect will be carried over after the [Trash] effect activates and digivolution occurs, therefore deletion will occur again if the DP is still 0 after the effect activates and digivolution occurs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Trash] effect to digivolve when my [Dorugamon] would be deleted by its DP becoming 0, can I prevent that deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  The Digimon is deleted before the [When Digivolving] effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Trash] effect to digivolve when my [Dorugamon] would be deleted due to its DP being reduced by 10000. Its DP became 0 due to the DP-reducing effect, but can I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect after it digivolves at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it activates instead of \"Then, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 4 or less instead\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate instead of \"Trash 1 card in your hand. Then, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It triggers at the timing when this card is in the trash and your [DoruGreymon] would be deleted.  [Trash] means that an effect can trigger and activate when the card is in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When exactly is the timing when this card's [Trash] [All Turns] effect triggers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, the DP-reducing effect will be carried over after the [DoruGreymon] effect activates and digivolution occurs, therefore deletion will occur again if the DP is still 0 after the effect activates and digivolution occurs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Trash] effect to digivolve when my [DoruGreymon] would be deleted by its DP becoming 0, can I prevent that deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  The Digimon is deleted before the [When Digivolving] effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Trash] effect to digivolve when my [DoruGreymon] would be deleted due to its DP being reduced by 10000. Its DP became 0 due to the DP-reducing effect, but can I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect after it digivolves at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it activates instead of \"Then, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less instead\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate instead of \"Trash 1 card in your hand. Then, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s inherited effect to choose my Digimon with a \"can't be deleted by effects\" effect and only delete an opponent's Digimon with as high or lower a level as that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect means that this card is also treated as a level 6 card while it's flipped over from the deck by a \"reveal cards from the deck\" effect.  If the effect is an effect such as \"add 1 level 6 Digimon card from the revealed cards,\" you can use that effect to add this card to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"while this card is revealed from your deck, this card is also treated as level 6\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The effect reads \"also treated as level 6,\" therefore this card can be treated as both level 5 and level 6, so you can add 2 copies to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal 2 copies of this card using BT3-051 [Dokugumon]'s [On Play] effect, can I add both copies to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate. This Digimon is deleted by the rules, not the DP-reducing effect. Therefore, it doesn't meet the \"if deleted by an effect\" condition.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"if deleted by an effect\" effect activate when this Digimon's DP becomes 0 and is deleted due to a DP-reducing effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect targets a level 5 or lower card with [Dark Masters] in its text from your trash.  This card's inherited effect has been changed to \"[When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] By placing 1 level 5 or lower card with [Dark Masters] in its text from your trash as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card, this Digimon gets +2000 DP for the turn.\"    Please see the notices regarding changes to the rules/rulings on the official website.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards does \"level 5 or lower card with [Dark Masters] in its text\" in this card's inherited effect refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's returned. In such cases, only the top card is returned to the hand and all digivolution cards are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The Digimon played using this card's [When Digivolving] effect digivolved. Is that Digimon returned to the hand at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally, the turn will end and the turn will switch when the memory moves to 1 or more on your opponent's side. But while this effect is activated, the turn won't end unless the memory moves to 3 or more on your opponent's side.  Your turn will continue when your opponent's memory is at 1 or 2.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only applies during your turn. Your opponent's turn continues until the memory moves to 1 or more from your perspective.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the memory moves to 2 or less on my opponent's side during my opponent's turn, does the turn switch to my turn with this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your turn continues.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The memory moved to 3 or more on my opponent's side and the turn ended while this card's inherited effect was activated. If the memory moves to 1 or 2 on my opponent's side due to an [End of Your Turn] effect, does my turn continue?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. \uff1cBlitz\uff1e still requires the memory to be at 1 or more on your opponent's side for attacking.  Attacking is possible when your opponent's memory is at 1 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the memory moves to 3 or more on my opponent's side while this card's inherited effect is activated, does \uff1cBlitz\uff1e allow for attacking?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to place 1 level 5 card with [Dark Masters] in its traits as a digivolution card even when my opponent doesn't have a level 5 or lower Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, if a Digi-Egg card is the target of an effect that places it at the bottom of the deck, it will be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect on a Digi-Egg card in my opponent's trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This effect reads \"you may play,\" so if you perform the conditions specified for \"by X,\" you may choose whether or not to activate the effect shown in text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to delete 1 of my other Digimon but then choose to not play [Ornismon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It triggers at the timing when this card is in the trash and your [Dorugoramon] would be deleted.  [Trash] means that an effect can trigger and activate when the card is in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When exactly is the timing when this card's [Trash] [All Turns] effect triggers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, the DP-reducing effect will be carried over after the [Dorugoramon] effect activates and digivolution occurs, therefore deletion will occur again if the DP is still 0 after the effect activates and digivolution occurs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Trash] effect to digivolve when my [Dorugoramon] would be deleted by its DP becoming 0, can I prevent that deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect allow me to pay a cost of 2 even when I play a white Tamer card with a play cost of 4 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also use this card's inherited effect to switch the attack target to an unsuspended [Eosmon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also use this card's inherited effect to switch the attack target to an unsuspended [Eosmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.  You perform the part of the effect after \"then\" regardless of whether or not a Tamer was played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both players don't play a Tamer for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, do I still perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards)?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The information on [Eosmon] is referenced at the time it's played, therefore you can perform deletion even if that [Eosmon] is removed from the battle area before the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the played [Eosmon] is removed from the battle area before this card's [All Turns] effect activates, can I still delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon with as much or less DP as the played [Eosmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card itself is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: 5000 DP or less.  If the same reference to an \"X\" trigger condition being performed isn't being made for an effect when it has a \"when X\" trigger condition, the state when the effect has triggered will be referenced.  In this case, processing was performed when your BT6-083 [Eosmon] had 5000 DP, therefore you can delete a Digimon with 5000 DP or less.[2]",
      "question": "Q: My BT6-083 [Eosmon] was played, then this card's [All Turns] effect and another effect triggered simultaneously.  If another effect activates and the DP of my played BT6-083 [Eosmon] changes from 4000 to 5000, then I activate this card's [All Turns] effect, what is the DP of Digimon I can delete?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If the same reference to an \"X\" trigger condition being performed isn't being made for an effect when it has a \"when X\" trigger condition, the state when the effect has triggered will be referenced.  In this case, because the Digimon that could be referenced by this card's [All Turns] effect was removed, you can't delete a Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Another of my [Eosmon] was played, then this card's [All Turns] effect and another effect triggered simultaneously. I activated the other effect, then my played [Eosmon] was removed from the battle area.  If I then activate this card's [All Turns] effect, can I delete an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card itself plays?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: DP5000 or less. If the triggering condition is \"when you do 00\" and the effect does not have the same reference as the triggering condition of \"when you do 00,\" then it refers to the situation at the time the effect is being processed. In this situation, the DP of your \"BT6-083 Eosmon\" is 5000 at the time it is being processed, so you can delete Digimon with DP 5000 or less.[3]",
      "question": "Q: My \"BT6-083 Eosmon\" appeared and this card's [All Your Turns] effect and another effect triggered simultaneously. If the DP of my \"BT6-083 Eosmon\" that played after the other effect is activated goes from 4000 to 5000, which DP or less can be deleted by the [All Your Turns] effect of this card that was triggered after that?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be deleted. If the triggering condition is \"when you do 00\" and the effect does not have the same reference as the triggering condition of \"when you do 00,\" then the situation at the time the effect is processed is referenced. In this situation, the card cannot be deleted because there are no more Digimons that can be referenced by the card's [All Turns] effect.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Other your \"Eosmon\" appeared and this card's [All Your Turns] effect and other effects triggered at the same time. My \"Eosmon\" which appeared and activated from the other effect has left the Battle Area. Can I delete my opponent's Digimon with this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activated after that?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If a Digi-Egg card is affected by an effect that places it at the bottom of the deck, it will be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to Digi-Egg cards in the trash when this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect activates?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that\u2019s correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"if this effect returned level 7 white cards\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect mean that it will activate even if I return a card such as BT12-112 [Shoutmon X7: Superior Mode] that has 2 or more colors including white?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 6 memory if I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to return 2 level 7 white cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If DNA Digivolving, you choose 1 of your opponent's Digimon and return all of your opponent's Digimon with the same level to the bottom of the deck.  For example, if you use this effect to choose a level 3 Digimon, you return all of your opponent's level 3 Digimon to the bottom of the deck.  Then, you delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may still delete one of the opponent's Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this card didn\u2019t DNA digivolve, can its [On Play] / [When Digivolving] effect still delete one of the opponent\u2019s Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  \uff1cPiercing\uff1e activates as soon as your opponent's Digimon is deleted in battle, therefore you can still perform a security check even if the effect is lost after activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon that gained \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and has this card in its digivolution cards was deleted in battle with an opponent's Digimon when my Digimon had 10000 DP, then I performed a security check using \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.  If the [Security] effect on the checked card reduces the DP of the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards to 9000 or less, can I still perform the 2nd security check using this card's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The effect reads \"may digivolve,\" so you can choose whether or not to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to place this Tamer and 1 [Growlmon] and 1 [WarGrowlmon] from my trash as the bottom digivolution cards of 1 of my [Guilmon], but choose to not may digivolve into [Gallantmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \uff1cBlitz\uff1e can activate as long as your opponent has 1 or more memory when you would activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Gallantmon] digivolved by this card's [End of Your Turn] effect has \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, can I activate it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to gain 2 memory if I have a Digimon with [Greymon] and a Digimon with [Garurumon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Even if the played Digimon is removed before the effect activates, it triggers because the \"when [...] Digimon is played\" condition is met, then the effect can activate. However, the \"if you have a Digimon with [XX]\" condition is no longer met once the Digimon is removed, therefore you don't gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I play a Digimon with [Greymon], then its DP becomes 0 and is deleted upon play due to a persistent effect, can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [End of Your Turn] effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack using my Digimon with [Omnimon] even when it's suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If BT5-086 [Omnimon] digivolves during the main phase, you can use the [End of Your Turn] effect to attack again after the attack from \uff1cBlitz\uff1e ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked using BT5-086 [Omnimon]'s \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and unsuspended it using the other [When Digivolving] effect. After the attack ends, can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The effect will trigger on both copies, but after the attack declaration is made for the 1st [Omnimon] and effects such as [When Attacking] effects have finished activating, the effect on the 2nd copy of this card that was pending activation will activate before the counter timing. However, a new attack declaration can't be made during an attack, and only the 1st [Omnimon]'s attack can be performed as a result.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 copies of this Tamer and 2 unsuspended Digimon with [Omnimon], can I activate the [End of Your Turn] effect on both copies of this card and attack using both of the Digimon with [Omnimon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  It triggers because <Partition> is an effect where the specified cards are played from digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when my Digimon is played by <Partition>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also activate if a single effect such as \"\uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, trash 1 card in the hand\" trashes the same number of cards as the number that were added from the draw?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when the hand increases from the digivolution bonus upon digivolution by an effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Even if the part after the conditions specified with \"by X\" in an effect can't be resolved, the effect can still activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to suspend this Tamer when my level 5 or higher [Free]\u00a0trait Digimon would be deleted in battle, even if I don't have any level 4 or lower Digimon cards in that Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The card is removed from digivolution cards before \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my level 5 or higher [Free]\u00a0trait Digimon would be deleted in battle, I used this card's [All Turns] effect to play a level 4 or lower Digimon card with \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e in its inherited effects from that Digimon's digivolution cards. Can I use \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e to delete the battled opponent's Digimon at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [End of Your Turn] effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack even when the [Free]\u00a0trait Digimon is suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The effect will trigger on both copies, but after the attack declaration is made for the 1st Digimon and effects such as [When Attacking] effects have finished activating, the effect on the 2nd copy of this card that was pending activation will activate before the counter timing. However, a new attack declaration can't be made during an attack, and only the 1st Digimon's attack can be performed as a result.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 copies of this Tamer and 2 unsuspended [Free]\u00a0trait Digimon, can I activate the [End of Your Turn] effect on both copies of this card and attack using both of the [Free]\u00a0trait Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The effect reads \"may digivolve,\" so you can choose whether or not to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to place this Tamer and 1 [Kyubimon] and 1 [Taomon] from my trash as my [Renamon]'s bottom digivolution cards, but then choose to not digivolve into [Sakuyamon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  EX4-030 [Kuzuhamon] is treated as if it has [Sakuyamon]. This effect doesn't treat it as if it has the name [Sakuyamon], therefore digivolution isn't possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve 1 of my [Renamon] into EX4-030 [Kuzuhamon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Marcus Damon] is treated as a Digimon by this card's effect and then its DP is reduced to 0 by an effect, is it deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve a Digimon other than the played Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  Suspending from an attack declaration is due to the rules, therefore it doesn't trigger \"when an effect suspends X\" effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"when an effect suspends\" in this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when an attack declaration is made for a Digimon and it's suspended using an effect such as \uff1cBlitz\uff1e or an \"attack using X\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with [Dex] in the trash regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of All Turns] effect in this card's inherited effect to play this card itself when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can activate.  This card's [All Turns] effect only prevents effects from activating at the [On Play] timing. Effects can still activate at the [Main] timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also prevent [Main] effects from activating if they have multiple activation timings such as [On Play] [Main]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when that Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  Effects that play into the breeding area aren't considered hatching, so it doesn't trigger this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card's [All Turns] effect triggered by \"play into an empty space in your breeding area without paying the cost\" effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  When this card is newly played, the [End of Your Turn] timing has already passed, and the effect can't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to play a copy of this card, can I activate the [End of Your Turn] effect on the newly played copy of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to play 1 Digimon card with the [Ten Warriors]\u00a0trait or 1 Tamer card with inherited effects without returning 1 Digimon card from my trash to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means a Tamer card with \"Inherited Effect\" in its lower text.  A Tamer card with a [Security] effect in its lower text isn't a \"Tamer card with inherited effects.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"Tamer card with inherited effects\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" refers to when that Digimon is placed in the trash other than as a result of a battle, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area other than by [...] a battle\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they do not leave the Battle Area. DNA digivolves digivolve as a new Digimon, so it is a different Digimon than the one that leaves.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If two Digimon including the leaving Digimon digivolved by the \"Delay\" effect of this card, does the Digimon that digivolved DNA digivolves leave the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When a Digimon leaves the Battle Area other than as a result of a Battle is when it is \"placed in trash,\" \"returned to hand or deck,\" \"placed in security,\" \"moved to the Breeding Area,\" or \"placed under another card\" other than as a result of a Battle.[3]",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does this card mean \"when leaving the Battle Area outside of a battle\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot ignore the digivolution requirements, so you cannot DNA digivolve to a Digimon card that does not have \"digivolves\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the \"Delay\" effect of this card to digivolve DNA digivolution to a Digimon card that does not have \"Jogress\" in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot ignore the digivolution requirements, so you cannot digivolve DNA digivolves with a Digimon that is not designated as a \"digivolution\" digivolution.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the \"Delay\" effect of this card to perform DNA digivolves with a Digimon not designated as a \"digivolve\" in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with [Gallantmon] in the hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Main] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into a level 5 or higher Digimon card with the [Free]\u00a0trait in the hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with [Imperialdramon] in the hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> and this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect will trigger simultaneously, but if you use this card's effect to digivolve first, the triggered <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> on BT16-025 [Paildramon] will be negated and won't activate.No, you can't activate it.  <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> and this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect will trigger simultaneously, but if you use this card's effect to digivolve first, the triggered <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> on BT16-025 [Paildramon] will be negated and won't activate.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When BT16-025 [Paildramon] would be deleted by an opponent's effect, can I activate BT16-025 [Paildramon]'s <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> effect after using this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  BT16-025 [Paildramon]'s <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> inherited effect can't be activated because it doesn't trigger when the Digimon is deleted by an opponent's effect.[3]",
      "question": "Q: When BT16-025 [Paildramon] is deleted by an opponent's effect, can I activate BT16-025 [Paildramon]'s <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> inherited effect after using this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> and this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect will trigger simultaneously, and the triggered <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> on BT16-025 [Paildramon] can be activated, even if you use this card's effect to digivolve first.[3]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon with BT16-025 [Paildramon] in its digivolution cards is deleted by an opponent's effect, can I activate BT16-025 [Paildramon]'s <Partition (blue Lv.4 + green Lv.4)> inherited effect after using this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  1 digivolution can only be performed on 1 Digimon. You can't perform separate digivolutions on multiple cards at the same time.  Therefore, when multiples of your Digimon with the [Free]\u00a0trait would be deleted other than by one of your effects, you can only use this card's effect to digivolve 1 of those Digimon.  In addition, only the digivolved Digimon is prevented from being deleted.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when multiples of my Digimon with the [Free]\u00a0trait would be deleted at the same time other than by one of my effects, can I digivolve all of those Digimon and prevent them from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Only the turn player can attack.  In this case, your EX3-063 [Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode] can't attack because it isn't your turn.[2]",
      "question": "Q: [All Turns] When my Digimon with the [Free]\u00a0trait would be deleted other than by one of my effects during my opponent's turn, I used this card's [All Turns] effect to digivolve that Digimon into EX3-063 [Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode].  Can I then use \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in EX3-063 [Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode]'s [When Digivolving] effect to attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  \"Top card\" refers to 1 or more cards with cards underneath it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to place a Digimon card with [Pulsemon] in its text and no digivolution cards on top of my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  After you place it on top of the security stack, the Tamer card will become the top card and it will remain in the battle area as a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to place a Digimon card with [Pulsemon] in its text that has just 1 Tamer card under it on top of the security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with [ShineGreymon] in the hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It comes from the cards in your hand.  This card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect has been changed to \"1 of your Digimon may digivolve into a Digimon card with [ShineGreymon] in the hand without paying the cost.\"    Please see the notices regarding changes to the rules/rulings on the official website.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve 1 of my Digimon into a Digimon card with [ShineGreymon], what area does the card with [ShineGreymon] come from?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Cards can't be placed under tokens.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to place this card in the digivolution cards of a [Diaboromon] Token that was played by this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When this effect activates, the player that activated the effect wins the game.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"you win the game\" in this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when that Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [End of Opponent's Turn] effect in this card's inherited effects to place this card itself in the battle area when this card is in a Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It triggers at the timing when this card is in the trash and your level 6 Digimon with [Pulsemon] in its text is played.  [Trash] means that an effect can trigger and activate when the card is in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When exactly is the timing when this card's [Trash] [Your Turn] effect triggers?"
    }
  ],
  "BT17-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. \"This Digimon gains all the names...\" means that it also gains the names from (Rule) on digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also give it the names from (Rule) on level 3 or lower cards in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards and Option cards don't have levels, therefore they don't meet the \"level 3 or lower cards\" condition and their names aren't gained.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also give it the names from Tamer cards and Option cards in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  \"Hatch a Digi-Egg\" means taking the top card of your Digi-Egg deck and placing it face-up in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to hatch a Tamer card with [Tai Kamiya] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: 3 cards.  In this case, there are 3 colors (red, blue, and yellow) in your opponent's Digimon and Tamers, therefore you trash 3 cards from the top of your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 1 red and blue Digimon and 1 red and yellow Tamer in their battle area.  How many cards do I trash from the top of my deck when this card's inherited effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: With this effect, your opponent's memory will no longer increase by any effects except Tamer effects. This effect affects the opponent player.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"your opponent can't gain memory other than by Tamer effects\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can gain memory.  When an effect is activated on a card that's treated as both a Digimon and a Tamer, the effect is treated as both a Digimon effect and a Tamer effect, therefore you can gain memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [All Turns] effect on BT17-087 [Marcus Damon] to gain memory if it's treated as a Digimon and suspends while my opponent has \"your opponent can't gain memory other than by Tamer effects\" activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the DNA digivolution requirements have to be met.  In addition, DNA digivolution can't be performed unless the [Millenniummon] has DNA digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand, do the DNA digivolution requirements have to be met for [Millenniummon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.  The [On Deletion] effect activates after the card is placed in the trash, therefore this card itself in the trash can DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Deletion] effect allow my [Machinedramon] and this card itself in the trash that activated the effect to DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] from your hand by using your [Machinedramon] in the battle area and your [Kimeramon] in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Deletion] effect, which locations must the [Machinedramon] and [Kimeramon] be in to DNA digivolve to [Millenniummon] from the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your [Machinedramon] in the battle area and [Kimeramon] in your trash can DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What are the areas where [Machinedramon] and [Kimeramon] can DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand using this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, DNA digivolution requirements must be met. Also, \"Millenniummon\" without DNA digivolution cannot have DNA digivolution.[3]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [On Deletion] effect digivolves Joggles to a \"Millenniummon\" in my hand, does it have to meet the digivolution requirements for that \"Millenniummon\"'s Joggles?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible. Since the [On Deletion] effect is activated after the card is placed in Trash, this card in Trash itself can DNA digivolves to \"Millenniummon\" in your hand.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect digivolve [DNA digivolves] to [Millenniummon] in my [Hand] with my [Machinedramon] and this card itself in the trash that activated this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: With your \"Mugendramon\" in the Battle Area and \"Kimeramon\" in your trash, you can DNA digivolve to \"Millenniummon\" in your hand.[4]",
      "question": "Q: In what location can the [On Deletion] effect of this card [On Deletion] be used with Machinedramon and Kimeramon to DNA digivolve to Millenniummon in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's digivolution requirement to digivolve for a cost of 5 even when my [Takuya Kanbara] has more than 5 [Hybrid]\u00a0trait cards under it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. After this card's [Your Turn] effect activates, then you perform the security check for \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.  This card's [Your Turn] effect and \uff1cPiercing\uff1e trigger simultaneously, but the activated \uff1cPiercing\uff1e is processed immediately before the attack ends, therefore \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e is first gained from this card's [Your Turn] effect, then you perform the security check for \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card gains \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from another card's effect, then this card attacks and deletes an opponent's Digimon in battle, do I perform the security check for \uff1cPiercing\uff1e after this card's [Your Turn] effect activates?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack.  When digivolving into this card, the turn end conditions won't be met until all of the resulting processing has been resolved.  In this case, this card's [When Digivolving] effect, [Your Turn] effect, and any effects triggered by them must first be resolved, and then the turn end conditions will be met.  Then, the end of the turn timing will occur and BT18-088 [Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto]'s [End of Your Turn] effect will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: BT18-088 [Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto] digivolved into this card, and the memory gauge moved to 1 on my opponent's side.  Then, I used this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to attack and used this card's [Your Turn] effect to unsuspend it.  Can I then use the [End of Your Turn] inherited effect on BT18-088 [Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto] in this card's digivolution cards to attack a player?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can digivolve.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's digivolution requirements also be from \"Takuya Kanbara\" with more than 5 cards with \"Hybrid Body\" in the trait below, at a digivolution cost of 5?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. and then checks with \"Penetrate\". This card's [Your Turn] effect and \"Penetration\" are triggered at the same time, but the activated \"Penetration\" is processed just before the [End of Attack], so the \"Penetration\" is checked after the \"S Attack +1\" is obtained by this card's [Your Turn] effect.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon is deleted in a battle in which this card, which has gained \"Penetrate\" by the effect of another card, attacks, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate and then check with \"Penetrate\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can attack. Until you digivolve to this card and resolve all the processes caused by it, you still do not meet the end-of-turn requirements. In this situation, all [When Digivolving] and [End of Your Turn] effects of this card and the effects caused by them are resolved, and the End of Turn condition is satisfied. After that, it becomes End of Turn, and the [End of Your Turn] effect of \"BT18-088 Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto\" is triggered.[2]",
      "question": "Q: The situation is that you evolved from \"BT18-088 Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto\" to this card, and its memory is more than 1 on the opponent's side. At this time, I attacked with this card's [When Digivolving] effect and became active with this card's [Your Turn] effect. After that, can I attack a player with the [When Digivolving] effect of [End of Your Turn] of this card's [BT18-088 Takuya Kanbara & Koji Minamoto], which is the digivolving card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, for each color of the digivolution source of this card, choose and trash one of your opponent's Digimon digivolution sources and rest one of your opponent's Digimon.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect, if this card has three colors of digivolved cards, choose and trash three of the opponent's digivolved Digimon and choose and rest three of the opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only return Digimon cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When DNA digivolving into this card and using this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to return 1 of each Digimon card with different levels from my opponent's trash to the top of the deck, can I return a Digi-Egg card to the top of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only return Digimon cards with levels. You can't return a \"Lv.-\" Digimon card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When DNA digivolving into this card and using this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to return 1 of each Digimon card with different levels from my opponent's trash to the top of the deck, can I return a Digimon card without a level to the top of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's digivolution cards are considered placed in the trash at the same time as deletion, therefore they can be placed at the bottom of the deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [On Deletion] effect to return [Kimeramon] and [Machinedramon] from my trash to the bottom of my deck, can I return [Kimeramon] and [Machinedramon] that were in this card's digivolution cards to the bottom of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.  In order for the conditions for this card's [On Deletion] effect to be met, you must return 1 [Kimeramon] and 1 [Machinedramon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to return just 1 [Kimeramon] or 1 [Machinedramon] from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a multicolor blue or red Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand or place as bottom digivolution cards as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand or place as bottom digivolution cards as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Effects with the [Hand] icon can activate when their card is revealed from the hand.  This effect can activate during the main phase when you reveal this card from the hand and process the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card's [Hand] [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.  In order for the conditions for this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to be met, you must place 1 [Kumamon] and 1 [Korikakumon] under your Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to place just 1 [Kumamon] or [Korikakumon] from my trash under my Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Hand] [Main] effect where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's [When Attacking] effect can play a blue level 3 Digimon card, or it can play a Tamer card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards can be played using this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can suspend.  This card's \"none of their Digimon with no digivolution cards can suspend\" effect only affects Digimon with no digivolution cards.  If a Digimon later obtains a digivolution card, this effect will no longer affect it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards obtains a digivolution card after this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates, can that Digimon suspend?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Effects with the [Hand] icon can activate when their card is revealed from the hand.  If your breeding area is empty, this effect can activate during the main phase when you reveal this card from the hand and process the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card's [Hand] [Main] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You will gain <Recovery +1 \u226aDeck\u226b> if a card isn't trashed by your opponent from \"your opponent may trash their top security card.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card will \"if this effect didn't trash\" in this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] [On Play] give me <Recovery +1 \u226aDeck\u226b> if it isn't trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can also choose to not add them to your hand.  If you don't add them, you shuffle your security stack without gaining <Recovery +1 \u226aDeck\u226b>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are found in my security stack, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects change the original DP shown on the target card to the predetermined value shown in the effect.  For example, if a Digimon has an original DP of 8000 and it's chosen as the target for a \"[Main] Change the original DP of 1 of your opponent's Digimon to 3000 until the end of their turn\" effect, that Digimon's original DP will become 3000 instead of 8000.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"change 1 Digimon's original DP\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Its original DP is changed, then +1000 is added to the changed DP.  Values added to DP don't affect the original DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a Digimon that got +1000 DP has its original DP changed by the \"change 1 Digimon's original DP\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The original DP is changed to the most recent value.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a Digimon has its original DP changed and is then affected by a \"change 1 Digimon's original DP\" effect again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  Effects that change information can't change information that a card didn't originally have.  For example, if a Digimon has its original DP changed by an effect and then its top card becomes a card without DP due to a \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e effect, it will no longer be affected by the effect that changes the original DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a Digimon without DP be affected by the \"change 1 Digimon's original DP\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can DNA digivolve using a level 5 blue or yellow Digimon and a level 5 green or black Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What DNA digivolution combinations are possible with this card's DNA digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's digivolution requirement to digivolve for a cost of 5 even when my [Koji Minamoto] has more than 5 [Hybrid]\u00a0trait cards under it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon attacks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a multicolor green or red Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e twice, not \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e.  When performing \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e, the top 2 cards are considered to be trashed at the same time, but when performing \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e twice, the top 2 cards are trashed 1 at a time.  For example, if using \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e to simultaneously trash the top 2 cards of a suspended Digimon and the 2nd card trashed is BT15-047 [Kabuterimon], its effect won't activate. However, if performing \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e twice and the Digimon becomes BT15-047 [Kabuterimon] after the 1st instance of \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e trashes a card, it won't be affected by the 2nd instance of \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e and won't be trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 face-up security cards.  If this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates, do I perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Effects with the [Hand] icon can activate when their card is revealed from the hand.  This effect can activate during the main phase when you reveal this card from the hand and process the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card's [Hand] [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.  In order for the conditions for this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to be met, you must place 1 [Kazemon] and 1 [Zephyrmon] under your Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to place just 1 [Kazemon] or [Zephyrmon] from my trash under my Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Hand] [Main] effect where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when another of my Digimon is deleted in battle?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a multicolor black or yellow Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: With this effect, your opponent's memory will no longer increase by any effects except Tamer effects. This effect affects the opponent player.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"your opponent can't gain memory other than by Tamer effects\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can gain memory.  When an effect is activated on a card that's treated as both a Digimon and a Tamer, the effect is treated as both a Digimon effect and a Tamer effect, therefore you can gain memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [All Turns] effect on BT17-087 [Marcus Damon] to gain memory if it's treated as a Digimon and suspends while my opponent has \"your opponent can't gain memory other than by Tamer effects\" activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand and place as bottom digivolution cards as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand and place as bottom digivolution cards as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't have to choose an opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to choose an opponent's Digimon for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't attack using a Digimon that can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose an opponent's Digimon that can't attack for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect, does my opponent attack with that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, your opponent can't attack using that Digimon. A new attack declaration can't be made during an attack.  In such cases, even if you choose an opponent's Digimon for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect when there is already an attacking Digimon, your opponent can't attack with the chosen Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon is attacking using an effect at the end of their turn.  If I choose an opponent's Digimon for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect, does my opponent attack with that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose a Digimon that isn't affected by effects for this and have it attack.  Such Digimon aren't affected by effects, but they can be chosen.  In addition, \"your opponent attacks with the chosen Digimon\" in this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect affects a player, therefore your opponent must attack with the chosen Digimon if it can attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose a Digimon that isn't affected by effects for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect and have it attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Effects with the [Hand] icon can activate when their card is revealed from the hand.  This effect can activate during the main phase when you reveal this card from the hand and process the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card's [Hand] [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.  In order for the conditions for this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to be met, you must place 1 [Beetlemon] and 1 [MetalKabuterimon] under your Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to place just 1 [Beetlemon] or [MetalKabuterimon] from my trash under my Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Hand] [Main] effect where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they trigger simultaneously.  However, if you activate BT18-015 [Kimeramon]'s [On Deletion] effect first and then DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] using [Kimeramon] and this card while its [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect has triggered, this card will be removed from the battle area before the [On Play] effect can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card would be played, I deleted my BT18-015 [Kimeramon], then I played this card.  At such times, does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect trigger simultaneously with BT18-015 [Kimeramon]'s [On Deletion] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the DNA digivolution requirements have to be met.  In addition, DNA digivolution can't be performed unless the [Millenniummon] has DNA digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand, do the DNA digivolution requirements have to be met for [Millenniummon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.  The [On Deletion] effect activates after the card is placed in the trash, therefore this card itself in the trash can DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Deletion] effect allow my [Kimeramon] and the BT18-073 [Machinedramon] itself that activated the effect in the trash to DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can DNA digivolve into [Millenniummon] from your hand by using your [Kimeramon] in the battle area and your [Machinedramon] in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [On Deletion] effect, which locations must [Kimeramon] and [Machinedramon] be in to DNA digivolve to [Millenniummon] from the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect can play a black card with a play cost of 7 or less.  This includes both Digimon cards and Tamer cards that are black and have play costs of 7 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards can be played by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a multicolor purple or yellow Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects change the original color shown on the target card to the predetermined color shown in the effect.  For example, if a Digimon's original color is red and it's chosen as the target for a \"[On Play] [When Digivolving] Until the end of your opponent's turn, change the original color of 1 of your opponent's Digimon or Tamers to 1 non-white color\" effect, then you choose a non-white color, and that Digimon's original color will become that color.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"change the original color\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Its original color is changed, and it retains the gained color.  Gained colors don't affect the original color.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a Digimon that gained a color has its original color changed by the \"change the original color\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The original color is changed to the most recent color.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a Digimon has its original color changed and is then affected by a \"change the original color\" effect again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The original color can be changed to any 1 color from among red, blue, yellow, green, black, or purple.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What original colors can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect change an opponent's Digimon or Tamer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution requirements have to be met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, do the digivolution requirements have to be met?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's digivolution requirement where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's digivolution requirement, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: 3 cards.  In this case, there are 3 colors (red, blue, and yellow) in your opponent's Digimon and Tamers, therefore you trash 3 cards from the tops of both players' decks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 1 red and blue Digimon and 1 red and yellow Tamer.  How many cards do I trash from the tops of both players' decks when this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Effects with the [Hand] icon can activate when their card is revealed from the hand.  This effect can activate during the main phase when you reveal this card from the hand and process the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card's [Hand] [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.  In order for the conditions for this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to be met, you must place 1 [Beetlemon] and 1 [MetalKabuterimon] under your Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Hand] [Main] effect to place just 1 [Beetlemon] or [MetalKabuterimon] from my trash under my Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it digivolves from the Tamer as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Hand] [Main] effect where it can digivolve from a Tamer mean that the Tamer that will become a digivolution card is treated as a Digimon when it digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that would digivolve.  When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon would digivolve\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer would digivolve using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that would digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't considered a Digimon that digivolves.  When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, \"when a Digimon digivolves\" effects don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Tamer digivolves using this card's [Hand] [Main] effect, is it considered a Digimon that digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon that aren't affected by effects aren't affected by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect.  Because this effect didn't delete, you can process the part of the effect after \"if this effect didn't delete.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if an opponent's Digimon that isn't affected by effects is chosen for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents all of your 0 DP Digimon from being deleted.  It prevents deletion from effects as well as deletion from the rules (including the rules that delete 0 DP Digimon upon a rule check and deletion upon losing a battle).[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [All Turns] effect do, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You may choose 1 card with a combination of having the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait and a different name from your trash and place it under this Tamer.  For each of your other Tamers, you add 2 to the maximum number of cards this effect may place under this Tamer.  For example, if you have 1 Tamer other than this Tamer, you can choose up to 3 cards with the [Hybrid]\u00a0trait and different names from your trash and place them under this Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't attack. A new attack declaration can't be made during an attack.  In such cases, even if you activate this card's [End of Your Turn] inherited effect when you already have an attacking digimon, a new attack can't be performed using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon is attacking using an effect at the end of my turn.  Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] inherited effect to attack a player using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: From the battle area.  When text doesn't specify an area, it means that it specifies, references, or affects the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to place up to 4 of my Tamers with different colors under 1 of my [Susanoomon] as its bottom digivolution cards, what areas can I choose Tamers from?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to place 1 of my red and blue Tamers and 1 of my red and yellow Tamers under 1 of my [Susanoomon] as its bottom digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they trigger simultaneously.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When multiple copies of this card are trashed from the security stack at the same time, does the \"when this card is trashed from the security stack\" effect on each of those cards trigger simultaneously?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If the \"by trashing your top security card\" condition isn't performed, the rest of the effect isn't processed. In this case, you can't process this effect unless you trash your top security card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I process \"then, if you have 2 or fewer security cards, place this card as your bottom security card\" in this card's [Main] effect even I don't perform \"by trashing your top security card\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can give that effect to such Digimon, but Digimon that aren't affected by effects won't be affected by it, therefore the gained effect won't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to give \"[Start of Your Main Phase] This Digimon attacks\" to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect trashes an Option card that was placed by a \"place this card in the battle area\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"trash 1 Option card in your opponent's battle area\" effect do, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must trash their top security card if possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not trash my opponent's top security card when I use this card's [End of All Turns] effect to delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon and 1 of their Tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "BT18-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can digivolve from [Takuya Kanbara] with 10 [Hybrid]\u00a0trait cards under it or [Koji Minamoto] with 10 [Hybrid]\u00a0trait cards under it for a cost of 6.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When is digivolution possible with this card's digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's digivolution requirement to digivolve for a cost of 6 even when my [Takuya Kanbara] or [Koji Minamoto] has more than 10 [Hybrid]\u00a0trait cards under it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't use that digivolution requirement with <Blast Digivolve>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's <Blast Digivolve> allow me to use the \"[Takuya Kanbara]/[Koji Minamoto] w/10 [Hybrid]\u00a0trait cards under\" digivolution requirement to digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose the order of the security cards that are placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [When Attacking] effect to place multiple Tamer cards as my bottom security cards, can I choose the order of the cards that are placed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate <Decode (Blue Lv.4)> and return their Digimon to the hand.  In such cases, <Decode (Blue Lv.4)> interrupts this card's inherited effect.  Once it activates, you return BT19-024 [MarineBullmon] to the bottom of the deck and return 1 of your opponent's level 5 or lower Digimon to the hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have BT19-024 [MarineBullmon] with this card in digivolution cards in the battle area.  When my opponent's Digimon attacks and I use this card's inherited effect to return BT19-024 [MarineBullmon] to the bottom of the deck, can I activate BT19-024 [MarineBullmon]'s <Decode (Blue Lv.4)> and then return 1 of my opponent's level 5 or lower Digimon to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This digivolution card has the digivolved card's digivolution card effect, which means that if the Digimon with this card as its digivolved card has a memory of either \"0 to 10 on the opponent's side\" at the time it activates the DP Deletion effect, the condition has been met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does the digivolution card's inherited effect mean \"while memory is 0 or less\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect adds the upper limit of the value texted in the DP deletion effect. For example, \"[On Opponent's Turn] Delete one opponent's Digimon with DP3000 or less [When Digivolving]\" while \"[On Digivolving] Delete one opponent's Digimon with DP3000 or less\" is activated. will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with a DP of 4000 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"DP deletion effect limit +X000\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be added. You cannot add the upper limit of the DP deletion effect for which no numerical value is texted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While the \"DP Deletion Effect Limit + X000\" effect is active, can I add an upper limit to the effect that deletes opponents' Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP, such as \"Deletes opponents' Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP.\"? Can I add an upper limit to the effect that deletes the Digimon by referring to its DP, such as \"This Digimon's DP is less than or equal to the opponent's Digimon's DP\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot digivolve. Digivolution requirements cannot be ignored.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this card to \"BT11-018 Shoutmon DX\" with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After the [On Deletion] effect of this card plays a tamer card, can this card be placed under that tamer in a \"save\" after \"then\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This digivolution card has the digivolved card's digivolution card effect, which means that if the Digimon with this card as its digivolved card has a memory of either \"0 to 10 on the opponent's side\" at the time it activates the DP Deletion effect, the condition has been met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does the digivolution card's inherited effect mean \"while memory is 0 or less\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect adds the upper limit of the value texted in the DP deletion effect. For example, \"[On Opponent's Turn] Delete one opponent's Digimon with DP3000 or less [When Digivolving]\" while \"[On Digivolving] Delete one opponent's Digimon with DP3000 or less\" is activated. will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with a DP of 4000 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"DP deletion effect limit +X000\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be added. You cannot add the upper limit of the DP deletion effect for which no numerical value is texted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While the \"DP Deletion Effect Limit + X000\" effect is active, can I add an upper limit to the effect that deletes opponents' Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP, such as \"Deletes opponents' Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP.\"? Can I add an upper limit to the effect that deletes the Digimon by referring to its DP, such as \"This Digimon's DP is less than or equal to the opponent's Digimon's DP\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When leaving the Battle Area\" refers to when this Digimon is \"placed in trash,\" \"returned to hand or deck,\" \"placed in security,\" \"moved to the Breeding Area,\" or \"placed under another card.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does this card mean when it says \"when leaving the Battle Area\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card can also be treated as a \"Shoutmon\" only in DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be placed under a tamer in a \"Material Save\" of a Digimon with \"Shoutmon\" in the DigiXros conditions, such as \"BT10-013 Shoutmon X5\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is deleted, I activated this card's [All Turns] effect and placed a Digimon card with play cost 4 or less with \"Cross Heart\" in its trait under my tamer in this card's digivolved. After that, can I play the Digimon card I placed under this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. If you have an opponent Digimon that you can choose, you must choose that Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I am in a situation where there is an opponent's Digimon with DP 8000 or less. Can I not select the Digimon to be deleted by this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible. You can satisfy the \"if not deleted by this effect\" condition by choosing an opponent's Digimon that is not deleted by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I am in a situation where I have an opponent's \"BT14-062 Datamon\" and an opponent's Digimon with DP 8000 or less. Can I select \"BT14-062 Datamon\" with this card's [On Digivolving] effect and fulfill the \"If this effect does not delete it\" requirement without making the Digimon delete?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Aquatic] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Aquatic] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Aquatic] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After the [On Deletion] effect of this card plays a tamer card, can this card be placed under that tamer in a \"save\" after \"then\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Aquatic] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Aquatic] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it satisfies. In this situation, even if <De-Digivolving> causes the opponent's Digimon to become a Digitamon card with no DP, it is not trashed until the card's [On Play] and [When Digivolved] effects are resolved, and the card is treated as a Digimon. Therefore, the \"if there are 2 or more opponent Digimon\" condition of this effect is met, and you can return one of your opponent's Digimon of Lv.4 or lower to your hand. After returning it, the Digimon card is trashed. Also, if this effect returns a Digimon card to your hand, the card is placed at the bottom of the Digi-egg Deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The situation is that the opponent has 2 Digimon. If one of my opponent's Digimon becomes a Digitama Card without DP due to <De-Digivolve 2> of this card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects, does it satisfy the \"if the opponent has 2 or more Digimon\" requirement of this effect after that?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. In this situation, if the opponent's Digimon becomes a Tamer by <De-Digivolve>, the \"if the opponent has 2 or more Digimon\" condition of this effect is not met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The situation is that the opponent has 2 Digimon. If an opponent's Digimon becomes a Tamer by <De-Digivolve 1> of this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, does it satisfy the \"if the opponent has 2 or more Digimon\" requirement of this effect after that?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon card with \"Blue Flare\" or \"Cross Heart\" in its trait and play cost 5 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card can play from under the tamer by this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Aquatic] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate <Decode (Blue Lv.5)> and return a Digimon to the bottom of the deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to return this card to the bottom of the deck, can I activate this card's <Decode (Blue Lv.5)> and then return 1 of my opponent's level 6 or lower Digimon to the bottom of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they trigger simultaneously.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to return this card itself to the bottom of the deck, I use this card's <Decode (Blue Lv.5)> to play a card with an [On Play] effect, then I attempt to return my opponent's EX6-054 [Lucemon: Chaos Mode] to the bottom of the deck, and EX6-054 [Lucemon: Chaos Mode]'s [All Turns] effect plays a card with an [On Play] effect.  At such times, do the [On Play] effects on cards played by these effects trigger simultaneously?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You perform the DigiXros at the timing when the card is played.  You perform the DigiXros when this card's <Decode (Blue Lv.5)> is used to play BT19-025 [MetalGreymon], then you choose an opponent's Digimon to return to the bottom of the deck for this card's [End of Your Turn] effect.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect, return this card itself to the bottom of the deck, and use this card's <Decode (Blue Lv.5)> to play BT19-025 [MetalGreymon], at what timing is the DigiXros performed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Aquatic] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A yellow Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and the [Data]\u00a0trait or a yellow Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and the [Witchelny]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards will trigger this card's inherited effect when they would leave the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Only one of the two can be placed on the digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect be placed on the digivolved digivolved card of the \"Shooting Starmons\" that I played, unless I have both \"Starmons\" and \"Pickmons\" in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card can also be treated as \"Starmons\" only in DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I put this card under a tamer in a \"Material Save\" of a Digimon with \"Starmons\" in the DigiXros conditions, such as \"BT10-013 Shoutmon X5\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when this card itself plays?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A yellow Option card with a cost of 5 or less or a purple Option card with a cost of 5 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards can be placed as the bottom security card by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: A yellow Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and the [Data]\u00a0trait or a yellow Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and the [Witchelny]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards will trigger this card's inherited effect when they would leave the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Wizardmon] or [X Antibody] is in digivolution cards, can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to place a yellow or purple Option card with a cost of 5 or less from my hand as the bottom security card even when I can't add my top security card to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card can also be treated as \"Dorlumon\" only in DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be placed under a tamer in a \"Material Save\" of a Digimon with \"Dorlmon\" in the DigiXros conditions, such as \"BT10-013 Shoutmon X5\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This card's [All Turns] effect and BT19-029 [Tapirmon]'s inherited effect will trigger simultaneously. The player can choose the activation order of these effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card with BT19-029 [Tapirmon] in digivolution cards in the battle area.  When this Digimon would leave the battle area by an opponent's effect, can I first activate this card's [All Turns] effect and gain <Recovery +1 (Deck)>, then use BT19-029 [Tapirmon]'s inherited effect to trash a security card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect even when either player's security cards can't be trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a card with the [Royal Base]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, all of those Digimon are prevented from leaving.  This card's [All Turns] effect affects all Digimon without having to choose them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when multiples of my other Digimon with the [Royal Base]\u00a0trait would leave the battle area at the same time by effects, are all of those Digimon prevented from leaving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: BT19-053 [QueenBeemon]'s [All Turns] effect places all of your Digimon with the [Royal Base]\u00a0trait into your security stack.  In such cases, this card's [All Turns] effect prevents all of your Digimon with the [Royal Base]\u00a0trait from being deleted, but if BT19-053 [QueenBeemon]'s [All Turns] effect activates afterward, you can place all of your [Royal Base]\u00a0trait Digimon that were affected by the deletion effect into your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card, BT19-053 [QueenBeemon], and another Digimon with the [Royal Base]\u00a0trait in my battle area.  My opponent uses BT5-110 [All Delete] and I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when multiples of my other Digimon would leave the battle area at the same time, and all of my other Digimon with the [Royal Base]\u00a0trait are prevented from leaving. What happens if BT19-053 [QueenBeemon]'s [All Turns] effect activates afterward?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play \"EX4-063 Henry Wong & Shu-Chong Wong\" with the [When Digivolving] effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card can also be treated as a \"ballistamon\" only in DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be placed under a tamer in a \"material save\" of a Digimon with \"ballistamon\" in the DigiXros conditions, such as \"BT10-013 Shoutmon X5\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to play a Digimon when this card attacks, can I suspend the played Digimon using this card's \uff1cAlliance\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when this card itself would leave the battle area other than in battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can place all of those Digimon face-up at the bottom of your security stack.  This card's [All Turns] effect affects all Digimon without having to choose them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when multiples of my Digimon with the [Royal Base]\u00a0trait would leave the battle area at the same time, can I place all of those Digimon face-up at the bottom of my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand and place under your Tamers as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand and place under my Tamers as possible?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you only reveal 1 of the applicable cards, you add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal for this card's [On Deletion] effect include only 1 card with [Knightmon] in its text or the [Twilight]\u00a0trait, can I place that card under my Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, I add to my hand whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card add the target card to the hand whenever possible if it is among the cards revealed from the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"card with 'Dragon Man Type' in its trait\" or \"card with 'Cyborg Type' in its trait\" and one \"card with 'Ryo Akiyama' in its name\" or \"option card with 'Devices' in its trait\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. \u226aCollision\u226b is always activated during the attack of the Digimon that has this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Attacking] effect digivolved into a \"Raptor Sparrowmon\" with \"Cross Heart\" as a trait, will this card's inherited effect of \"Collision\" be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, I add to my hand whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card add the target card to the hand whenever possible if it is among the cards revealed from the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This card can also be treated as \"Sparrowmon\" only in DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be placed under a tamer in a \"Material Save\" of a Digimon with \"Sparrowmon\" in the DigiXros conditions, such as \"BT10-013 Shoutmon X5\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect trashes option cards placed by the \"Place in Battle Area\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"trash an option card in the Battle Area\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, we will definitely trash it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Attacking] effect always require me to trash any of my option cards in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, we must attack whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the [End of Your Turn] effect of this card [End of Opponent's Turn] attack the player with this card as much as possible if there is an opponent's Digimon in active state?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot attack with the effect of the second card. While attacking, you cannot declare a new attack. In this situation, at the end of your Turn, the two [When End of Your Turn] effects of this card are triggered simultaneously, and you attack with the first [End of Your Turn] effect. Before the Counter timing, the second [When End of Your Turn] effect can be activated, but since you cannot declare an Attack during the Attack, the second card cannot attack even if you activate it.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have two copies of this card in my Battle Area. At the End of Your Turn, I attacked with the first card's [End of Your Turn] effect. Can I attack with the second card's [End of Your Turn] effect after that?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can delete a Digimon or Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to delete my Digimon or Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card would be deleted, I used this card's <Material Save> to place a card from this card's digivolution cards under my Tamer. Can I then use this card's [On Deletion] effect to play the card that was placed under my Tamer by <Material Save>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect trashes option cards placed by the \"Place in Battle Area\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"trash an option card in the Battle Area\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can trash either your or your opponent's option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect trash either my or my opponent's option cards in the Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can delete a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to delete my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to switch the target of attack to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After the [On Deletion] effect of this card plays a tamer card, can this card be placed under that tamer in a \"save\" after \"then\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to delete this Digimon itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: 1 of your level 4 or lower purple Digimon or 1 of your level 4 or lower red Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What Digimon's deletion will trigger this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to switch the target of attack to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: 1 Digimon.  You choose 1 of your opponent's Digimon for this card's [When Digivolving] effect, then you give it \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e for each of your Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 Digimon.  How many of my opponent's Digimon can be affected by \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e using this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses and trashes the cards in their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the cards to trash in the hand for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The [Main] effect cannot be activated at the same time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the [Main] effect of this card be activated at the same time as an effect that digivolves, such as \"P-103 Offense Training\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: BT19-078[1]",
      "question": "Q: Yes, it is possible."
    }
  ],
  "BT19-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  Cards from under your Tamers can also be placed for each of those cards' DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when multiples of the specified cards would be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally, in DigiXros, you can place a card from your hand or Battle Area under that card, but if you activate the [All Turns] effect of this card, you can also place a card under your tamer in the DigiXros of that card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What is the [All Turns] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be placed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [All Turns] effect also place cards under tamers other than this tamer under cards that DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is triggered. In each DigiXros of all those cards, you can also place cards under your tamer.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when multiple specified cards play at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. \u226aYou must attack as much as possible with the Digimon that gave you the \"rush\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Your Turn] effect not attack with that Digimon after it gives \"Rush\" to \"Growlmon\" or \"Gallantmon\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  Cards from under your Tamers can also be placed for each of those cards' DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when multiples of the specified cards would be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally, in DigiXros, you can place a card from your hand or Battle Area under that card, but if you activate the [All Turns] effect of this card, you can also place a card under your tamer in the DigiXros of that card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What is the [All Turns] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be placed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [All Turns] effect also place cards under tamers other than this tamer under cards that DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is triggered. In each DigiXros of all those cards, you can also place cards under your tamer.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when multiple specified cards play at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: One Digimon card with \"Renamon\" in its name, one Digimon card with \"Kyubimon\" in its name, one Digimon card with \"Taoimon\" in its name, or one Digimon card with \"Sakuyamon\" in its name, and one option card with \"Plug-in\" in its name.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect and BT18-004 [Puroromon]'s inherited effect triggered simultaneously when I had no face-up security cards.  At such times, can I use BT18-004 [Puroromon]'s effect to place a card from my hand face up as my bottom security card, then use this card's effect to gain 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the [Main] effect of this card prevent \"Cyber Drummon\" from playing after the option card in the Battle Area is trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your [Composite]\u00a0trait cards with DigiXros requirements or your [Twilight]\u00a0trait cards with DigiXros requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards trigger this card's [All Turns] effect when they would be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Normally, you can place cards from your hand and battle area under a card to be played for a DigiXros, but when this card's effect is activated, in addition to cards from your hand and battle area, 1 card from under your Tamers and 1 card from your trash can also be placed under the card to be played for the DigiXros.  This effect also allows you place a card from just one area. For example, you can place 1 card from your trash without placing a card from under your Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"1 card under your Tamers and 1 card in your trash can also be placed for their DigiXros\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also allow me to place cards from under a Tamer other than this Tamer for a DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  1 card from under your Tamers and 1 card from your trash can also be placed for each of those cards' DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also trigger when multiples of the specified cards would be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this card in my battle area.  If I activate the [All Turns] effect on both copies of this card when 1 of the specified cards would be played, can I place 2 cards from under my Tamers, 2 cards from my trash, or other combinations of cards placed under the card to be played for the DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this card in my battle area.  If I activate the [All Turns] effect on both copies of this card when multiples of the specified cards would be played, can I place 2 cards from under my Tamers, 2 cards from my trash, or other combinations of cards placed under the cards to be played for the DigiXroses?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The number will be unaffected by DP minus. For example, if you choose a Digimon with an original DP of 5000 (current DP is 3000) that is DP-2000 due to the card's [Main] effect, that Digimon will no longer be DP minus and its DP will be 5000.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I am in a situation where I have my Digimon with a minus DP. What happens if I use this card's [Main] effect to select that Digimon with a minus DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. A condition for a [thing] cannot be performed only in part of its content. For the conditions of this [Main] effect, one \"Shoutmon EX6\" and one \"Shooting Starmon\" must be active respectively.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I am in a situation where I have \"Shoutmon EX6\" in my Rest state and \"Shooting Starmon\" in my Active state. If I choose the second effect for this card's [Main] effect, can I make only \"Shoutmon EX6\" active and attack with one of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The card is either \"my card with the name \"WarGrowlmon\" lv.5\" or \"my card with the name \"TaoMon\" lv.5\" or \"my card with the name \"RapidMon\" lv.5\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the first effect of this card ignore color requirements while any Digimon is present?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"WarGrowlmon\" tokens cannot play. The \"ACE\" described in the name is not included in the name.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate the [Main] effect of this card when I have my \"WarGrowlmon ACE\", can I play each of the tokens \"WarGrowlmon\", \"TaoMon\" and \"RapidMon\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Tokens played by the [Main] effect of this card do not have Lv. You cannot choose these tokens because only your Digimon of Lv. 5 can be chosen by the \"After\" and subsequent effects of this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I select a token played by this card's [Main] effect and after \"after\" this effect, give that Digimon two \"linkages\" and attack with that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. \u226aYou must attack as much as possible with the Digimon that gave you two \"linkages\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the [Main] effect of this card not attack with that Digimon after giving it 2 [Linkage]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The card is a card with the name \"WarGrowlmon\" Lv.5, or \"TaoMon\" Lv.5, or \"RapidMon\" Lv.5.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can play under the [Security] effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to return 1 of my blue Digimon with <Decode> to the bottom of the deck, can I activate <Decode> and then return 1 of my opponent's level 6 or lower Digimon to the bottom of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The second effect is activated, until the end of that opponent's turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card in the Battle Area is trashed during my opponent's turn, how long will the second effect of this card be given?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You perform <Recovery +1 (Deck)>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent doesn't trash a security card for this card's [Your Turn] effect, which player performs <Recovery +1 (Deck)>?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you delete their Digimon until they have 0 left.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 0 security cards.  If I activate this card's [Main] effect, do I delete my opponent's Digimon until they have 0 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't met.  The \"if this effect deleted\" condition is only met when a Digimon is deleted by this card's effect.  In this case, EX6-059 [Barbamon] wasn't deleted by this card's effect, therefore the \"if this effect deleted\" condition isn't met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I tried to delete my opponent's EX6-059 [Barbamon] using this card's [Main] effect.  In response, my opponent uses \uff1cScapegoat\uff1e on EX6-059 [Barbamon] to delete their other Digimon and prevent EX6-059 [Barbamon] from being deleted.  At such times, is this card's \"if this effect deleted\" condition met?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The second effect is activated, until the end of that opponent's turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card in the Battle Area is trashed during my opponent's turn, how long will the second effect of this card be given?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can choose 1 of your Digimon with [Millenniummon] that was affected by the removal processing and play 1 [Wicked God]\u00a0trait Digimon card with a play cost 1 higher than that Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect when multiples of my Digimon with different play costs and [Millenniummon] would leave the battle area at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. All of your Digimon and tamers in the Battle Area must have \"De Reaper\" as a trait to activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Security] effect be activated even if there is a Digimon with \"De-Reaper\" in its trait and a Tamer without \"De-Reaper\" in its trait in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be activated. Text that does not describe which location can specify or refer to a Battle Area and affect the Battle Area. In the case of this card's [Security] effect, it can be activated if all of your Digimon and Tamer in the Battle Area have \"De Reaper\" as a trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Security] effect be activated even if all my Digimon and Tamer in Battle Area have \"De-Reaper\" in their traits and my Digimon in Breeding Area do not have \"De-Reaper\" in their traits?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated. Text that does not describe which location can specify or reference a Battle Area and affects the Battle Area. In the case of this card's [Security] effect, it cannot be activated if there is no one of your Digimon or Tamer with \"De-Reaper\" in its trait in the Battle Area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Security] effect be activated even if my Digimon and Tamer are not in the Battle Area and my Digimon with the trait \"De-Reaper\" is in the Breeding Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be used. However, it cannot activate this effect because it does not meet the condition of the [Main] effect of this card, \"if you have no face-up security of your own\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card in my hand when I have my own face-up security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It becomes ostensible security and remains public. The rules are the same as for normal security, except that it is ostensible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to a card placed face up in security by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. It must be activated when the opponent's Digimon attacks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate the [Security] effect of this card when my opponent's Digimon attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Checked as published. The rules are the same as for normal checks, except as published.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when checking a security placed face down?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If a security placed face up is checked, does the card's [Security] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The security that was face up is turned back face down and then shuffled. After shuffling, the cards are not turned face up.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when shuffling a security that contains a security placed face up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the <Overclock ([Composite]\u00a0trait)> effect allows it to attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card with no digivolution cards can't be suspended because of its [All Turns] effect, but does this card's <Overclock ([Composite]\u00a0trait)> effect allow it to attack without suspending?"
    }
  ],
  "BT19-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose either your or your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects select other Digimon of either myself or my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does this card's inherited effect activate during my unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect doesn't refer to [Tsumemon], but to the name of the Digimon this card digivolves into.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What counts as \"another Digimon in play with the same name as this Digimon\"? Does this only count if I have another Digimon in play named [Tsumemon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if this Digimon is blocked, the effect activates if you declared an attack against your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if this Digimon is blocked, the effect activates if you declared an attack against your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if this Digimon is blocked, the effect activates if you declared an attack against your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. They weren't flipped over in a security check, so they don't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's When Attacking effect to trash my opponent's Security Cards. Do the security effects on those cards activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 1 or more cards in their security stack. I attack my opponent with this Digimon and its When Attacking effect trashes the rest of their security cards, leaving them with zero cards in their security stack. If the attack isn't blocked and my attack is successful when they have zero cards in their security stack, do I win the game?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, play costs can't be reduced to less than zero. You can play the card for free, but you can't gain memory with effects that reduce play costs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 5 or more Digimon with no digivolution cards in play, meaning this card's effect reduces its cost by 5, to -1. Can I play it by gaining a memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to unsuspend this card if it digivolves while suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon's attacks can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"This Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards.\" How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon's attacks can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"This Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards.\" How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't use this Digimon's effect to suspend your blue Tamers. The effect only allows you to unsuspend this Digimon when another effect suspends one of your blue Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this Digimon's effect to suspend one of my blue Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If an effect unsuspends a card that's already unsuspended, it doesn't count as unsuspending it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is unsuspended during my main phase, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's \"gain 1 memory\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if both Digimon are deleted simultaneously, the effects activate one at a time. When the first Salamon's effect activates, you add 1 card to your security stack, bringing the total up to 4. This means the \"3 cards or less\" condition for the second Salamon's effect no longer applies. The second Salamon's effect doesn't activate, and your security stack remains at 4 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 3 cards in my security stack when 2 copies of this Digimon are deleted at the same time. Do the [On Deletion] effects on both cards activate, bringing my security stack up to 5 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs, and the attack ends. If there are other When Attacking effects, \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects, and/or effects activated at counter timing, they activate, and then the attack ends. If it's then blocked at blocker timing, start a battle with the blocking Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon, then use this Digimon's inherited effect to reduce the opponent's Digimon to 0 DP and delete it. What happens to the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [When Attacking] effect every time I attack with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, does that [On Play] effect activate when the Digimon enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. During checks, it will fight your opponent's attacking Digimon as a Security Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card face down on top of my security stack because of its effect, does it become a security card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the [When Evolving] effect activates separately for each yellow Tamer you suspend, and you get to choose the target for each effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to suspend 2 or more yellow Tamers. Can I choose 2 or more of my opponent's Digimon and give all of them -4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they're treated as activating at the same timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect two or more times. Are they treated as activating at separate timings?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If either a level 5 Digimon card or a green Tamer card are present in the 3 cards you reveal, you get to add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal with this card's effect don't contain both a level 5 Digimon card and a green Tamer card, do I still get to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if there was only either a Lv.5 Digimon card or a green tamer card, it will be added to your hand.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card require both a lvl 5 Digimon card and a green tamer card to be added to my hand among the 3 cards revealed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"Digimon card of Lv.5 or lower\" and one \"Green tamer card\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's inherited effect to play a Digimon card with an [On Play] effect, does that [On Play] effect activate when the Digimon enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The Digimon suspended by this effect -- along with all of your opponent's other suspended Digimon -- remain suspended during their unsuspend phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [On Play] effect to suspend an opponent's Digimon. Is that Digimon the only one that doesn't unsuspend during my opponent's next unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It only prevents suspended Digimon from unsuspending. Any unsuspended Digimon remain that way.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect cause my opponent's unsuspended Digimon to suspend themselves during their next unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn't affect Tamers. They unsuspend as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect prevent my opponent's suspended Tamers from unsuspending during their next unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it remains unsuspended during the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to attack an opponent's unsuspended Digimon. Does the opponent's Digimon suspend itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect doesn't refer to [Keramon], but to the name of the Digimon this card digivolves into.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What counts as \"another Digimon with the same name as this Digimon\"? Does this only count if I have another Digimon in play named [Keramon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect doesn't refer to [Kurisarimon], but to the name of the Digimon this card digivolves into.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What counts as \"another Digimon with the same name as this Digimon\"? Does this only count if I have another Digimon in play named [Kurisarimon]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate from breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is in my breeding area when I digivolve it into a Diaboromon from my hand. Does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This inherited effect only allows you to gain 1 memory per turn, no matter how many Digimon are deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If 2 or more of my other Digimon are deleted at the same time, can I gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you may choose not to use it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete a Digimon in my breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete a Digimon in my breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the effect of [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon] and [When Attacking] would be resolved at the same time, the opponent's effect will be resolved first, and then VenomMyotismon's effect will be resolved.",
      "question": "Q: [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]'s effect is \"[Opponent's Turn] When the opponent's Digimon suspends\". The opponent's Digimon is rested to attack. Which comes first [When Attacking] or the [Opponent's Turn] effect of VenomMyotismon to increase memory by 1? Is it the same timing as [When Attacking]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is triggered as soon as the opponent declares an attack suspending the Digimon. (See more in Attack Resolution)",
      "question": "Q: Is [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]'s [Opponent's Turn] effect considered a [Reaction] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The effect of this card was not triggered when the attack was declared (which caused the Digimon to suspend), so it cannot be activated. (See more in Effect Resolution)",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks and activates an effect that \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e on my Level 7 Digimon that becomes a [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]. Can I use VenomMyotismon's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Even though the effect of [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon] was triggered, the Digimon has lost the [Opponent's Turn] effect of VenomMyotismon so it cannot be activated. (See more in Effect Resolution)",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks and activates an effect that \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e on my [BT2-079 VenomMyotismon]. Can I use VenomMyotismon's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens are special cards that some effects put into play to represent Digimon or Tamers. This card's effect, for example, plays a token that's treated as a Digimon named [Diaboromon]. For a more detailed explanation of how tokens work, check the official rule manual.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What's a token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect by deleting a [Diaboromon] token when this Digimon is about to be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. this card's [All Turns] effect only takes effect when this Digimon is deleted. You can't activate it when a [Diaboromon] token is deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect by deleting a [Diaboromon] token when this Digimon is about to be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The token is considered a Digimon with the specified name, and is deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon and a [Diaboromon] token in play in my battle area when my opponent uses [BT1-084 Omnimon]'s [On Evolution] effect to choose [Diaboromon]. Are this Digimon and my [Diaboromon] token both deleted due to having the same name?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when this Digimon is about to be deleted in a battle with an opponent's Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [On Deletion] effect only returns this card to play. Any cards that were in its digivolution cards go to the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When playing this card from my trash using its [On Deletion] effect, do the cards it had as digivolution cards return to my battle area as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Tamer's effect becomes active once you declare your attack against another player. The +2000 DP bonus remains even if the target of attack changes due to \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with a Digimon, and suspend this Tamer. If my opponent blocks the attack, what happens to the +2000 DP bonus from this Tamer's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. \"Trash all of the digivolution cards of those Digimon\" is an explanation of what happens to the digivolution cards of the Digimon when it returns to their hand. It doesn't count as trashing digivolution for the purposes of this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: You activate an effect that reads \"Return 1 of your opponent's Digimon to their hand. Trash all of the digivolution cards of that Digimon\" to return an opponent's Digimon to their hand. When your opponent's digivolution cards are trashed as a result, can you activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving Digimon in your breeding area doesn't activate the effect that reduces digivolution cost by 1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon in my breeding area into a Digimon card with [Tyrannomon]. Can I use this Tamer's effect to reduce the digivolution cost by 1?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"purple Digimon card\" or \"purple option card\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is returned to the hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as trashing 1 of your opponent's digivolution cards is not a requirement, you get +2000 DP when using this card even when your opponent has no digivoltion cards. From Card Rulings:BT1-090",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when my opponent has no digivolution cards to still get the +2000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cards get trashed at the same time the Digimon is returned to the hand. So it gets returned to hand before unsuspending a Digimon.",
      "question": "Q: When do the digivolution cards get trashed in the effect of [BT2-096 The Ray of Victory]? Does it get trashed before or after unsuspending a Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect can only be activated against 1 of your opponent's Digimon. You can't use a single copy of this card to reduce the DP of multiple Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 or more cards in hand when I use this effect, can I give 2 or more different Digimon -1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Hoewver, it cannot be taken from your trash by BeeleStarmon's [On Play] effect even if you have 2 Tamers.",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my hand, and I have exactly 2 Yellow Tamers. Can I play this card with [BT6-112 BeelStarmon]'s [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, in that case, since the usage cost of [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] has been changed to 1, it is not considered that an option card with a usage cost of 2 or more was used, so it will not be demonstrated.",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card while I have 8 or more of my own yellow tamers and a [EX2-003 Viximon] in my Digimon's digivolution cards, will that card's inherited effect be triggered?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to delete a Digimon in my breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't use this card's effect to digivolve from an [Impmon] in your breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 10 or more cards in my trash, can I digivolve one of my [Impmon] in the breeding area into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 10 or more cards in my trash, can I digivolve one of my [Impmon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT2-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers strictly to your opponent's Digimon with the highest DP they control. The effect doesn't check the DP of your Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Attacking] effect refers to \"your opponent's Digimon with the highest DP.\" Does this strictly refer to my opponent's Digimon with the highest DP, or does it refer to when I attack an opponent's Digimon with the highest DP out of all Digimon in play, including my own?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If your opponent has multiple Digimon tied for highest DP, attacking any of them allows you to unsuspend this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has multiple Digimon tied for highest DP. If I attack any one of them, does this card's [When Attacking] effect let me unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect only lets you unsuspend this Digimon when attacking your opponent's Digimon with the highest DP, regardless of whether it's suspended or not.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon with the highest DP is unsuspended. If I attack their unsuspended Digimon with the highest DP, can I unsuspend this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon with the text \"DRACOMON\" or Digimon with the text \"EXAMON\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the inherited effect of this card be activated if it is in the digivolution card of which card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT20-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated. When a Digimon is deleted and the [On Deletion] effect of the Digivolved card is triggered, it is the Digimon card that had the Digivolved card that is waiting to be activated. If a Digimon card that is pending activation leaves the area before it is activated, its effect cannot be activated. In this situation, if \"BT20-068 BAKEMON\" is deleted and the [On Deletion] effect of its digivolved source is triggered, it is the \"BT20-068 BAKEMON\" card that is waiting to activate its effect. If the deleted \"BT20-068 Bakmon\" card leaves the trash, the [When Deletion] effect of the digivolved effect that was pending activation cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card and \"BT20-068 BAKEMON\" with \"BT20-063 GOSMON\" as its digivolved source were deleted, the digivolved source effect of this card and the digivolved source effect of \"BT20-063 GOSMON\" triggered simultaneously. In this case, if I activate this card's inherited effect first and return \"BT20-068 BAKEMON\" from my trash to my hand, can I activate the digivolved effect of \"BT20-063 Gosmon\" after that?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. When a Digimon is deleted and the [On Deletion] effect of its Digivolved source is triggered, it is the Digimon card that had the Digivolved source that is waiting to be activated. If you return the BT20-063 Gosmon card to your hand, you can still activate the digivolution card BT20-063 Gosmon's digivolution effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card and \"BT20-068 BAKEMON\" with \"BT20-063 GOSMON\" as its digivolved source were deleted, the digivolved source effect of this card and the digivolved source effect of \"BT20-063 GOSMON\" triggered simultaneously. In this case, if I activate this card's inherited effect first and return \"BT20-063 Gosmon\" from my trash to my hand, can I activate the digivolved effect of \"BT20-063 Gosmon\" after that?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The cards are either \"cards with the text 'DRACOMON'\" or \"cards with the text 'EXAMON'\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What card must be trashed for this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT20-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not trigger. In the Breeding Area, no effects other than those of the [Breeding] icon can be triggered or activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card in the Breeding Area evolves into a \"Ginyumon\" or a Digimon card with \"Chronicle\" in its trait, does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. No. [Main] More than one effect cannot be activated at the same time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: There are two of these cards in the Battle Area. Can I activate the [Main] effect of these two cards to play a card whose name contains \"Sistamon\" or \"Gankumon\" with the total play cost I pay -4?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the total play cost to be paid is -6.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Main] effect to play \"BT20-057 Gancumon\", does it activate the first effect of \"BT20-057 Gancumon\" and the total play cost I pay is -6?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can be activated and played, but the play cost is not minus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Cannot minus the play cost you pay, such as \"ST12-03 Solarmon.\" Can I activate the [Main] effect of this card to play a card whose name contains \"Sistamon\" or \"Gankumon\" when a Digimon with the effect is in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can be activated, but it cannot be played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: BT9-047 Pormmon\" and so on, \"Cannot play Digimon under the effect.\" Can I activate the [Main] effect of this card to play a card with \"Sistamon\" or \"Gankumon\" in its name when a Digimon with the effect is in the Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I not attack with this card after this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect grants \"Penetrating\" and DP+4000 to one of my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot attack. While attacking, you cannot declare a new attack. In this situation, you can attack with \"BT16-077 Dino Beamon\" under the [When Digivolving] effect of \"BT16-077 Dino Beamon\". Before the Counter timing, the card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects can be activated, but you cannot declare an attack during the attack, so you cannot attack even if you activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With the [When Digivolving] effect of \"BT16-077 Dinobeamon\", I played this card [On Play] and attacked a player with \"BT16-077 Dinobeamon\" with \"Quick Attack\" as it is. After that, can I attack with this card by its [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they do not leave the Battle Area. DNA digivolves digivolve as a new Digimon, so it is a different Digimon than the one that leaves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [All Turns] effect is activated and two Digimon including the leaving Digimon digivolve, does the digivolved Digimon leave the Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects cause a Digimon in the Breeding Area to digivolve, does the Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to grant \"Immune to Opponent's Effect\" to one of my Digimon and attack with a Digimon different from that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect is not affected by effects. For example, \"Rest an opponent's Digimon.\" effect will not be rested, and \"DP-3000 an opponent's Digimon.\" will not be minus DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What is the effect of \"not taking effect?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with the \"no effect\" effect be selected for an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be granted. The effect is not affected, but can be granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with a \"no effect\" effect be given an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: From the point of no longer being affected by the effect, it is no longer affected by the effect being granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card with an effect is given an effect and later gets a \"no effect\" effect, what happens to the effect that is given?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: From the time it becomes subject to the effect, it is affected by the effect being granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card with a \"no effect\" effect that is granted an effect later loses the \"no effect\" effect, what happens to the granted effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not trigger. If you give an effect that triggers to a Digimon that does not receive the effect, the effect will not be triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I added a triggering effect such as [When Attacking] effect to a card with \"No Effect\" effect. If the card then satisfies the conditions for triggering that effect, does the effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I counter-timed this card to \"blast digivolve\", can I digivolve it under the DNA digivolution requirements for this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since they are triggered simultaneously, the player can choose the order in which they are to be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has multiple effects that are triggered when it attacks, in what order can they be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon is either a green Digimon with the text \"DRACOMON\" or a green Digimon with the text \"EXAMON\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when any card plays?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT20-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This [All Turns] effect is activated while this card is in the Battle Area. It cannot be treated as a \"Slayer Dramon\" in your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \"Blast Joggles\" of \"BT20-045 Examon ACE\" to treat this card in my hand as \"Slayer Dramon\" and DNA digivolves with this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One Digimon with the text \"DRACOMON\" or one Digimon with the text \"EXAMON\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card can be activated by this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The cards are either \"cards with the text 'DRACOMON'\" or \"cards with the text 'EXAMON'\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which digivolution card's inherited effect is triggered when it leaves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, all those Digimons will not leave. The digivolution card's inherited effect is an effect that affects the whole card, not just any card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When several of my Digimon with the text \"DRACOMON\" or \"EXAMON\" leave the Battle Area at the same time outside of battle, if I activate the digivolved effect of this card, will all of those Digimon not leave?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] [On Attacking] effect play a Digimon card of Lv.5 or lower from this Digimon's digivolution source even if there is no \"Metal Seadramon\" or \"X Antibody\" in the digivolution source?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All All Turns] effect trigger when this card itself plays from digivolved cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not trigger. In the Breeding Area, no effects other than those of the [Breeding] icon can be triggered or activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card in the Breeding Area evolves into a Digimon card that has \"Pulsemon\" text or \"Seekers\" in its trait, does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the inherited effect of this card be activated even if the opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card as its digivolved card are deleted at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the inherited effect of this card be activated even if the opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card as its digivolved card are deleted at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is an effect that prevents a card's [When Digivolving] effect from being activated. When a card digivolves and triggers the [When Digivolving] effect, or the \"Activate [When Digivolving] effect\" effect, etc., the card will no longer be able to activate the [When Digivolving] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"[When Digivolving] effect is not activated\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. If the effect is triggered by [When Attacking], it can be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked with a card that has \"No [When Digivolving] effect activated\". In this case, can I activate the card's [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"No [When Digivolving] effect\" activate its own [When Digivolving] effect with the \"Activate 1 [When Digivolving] effect\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"No [When Digivolving] effect\" activate another card's [When Digivolving] effect with the \"Activate one [When Digivolving] effect as this card's effect\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the [When Digivolving] effect of a card that does not have the [When Digivolving] effect activated by another card that has the [When Digivolving] effect activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"Does not activate [When Digivolving] effect\" handle only the \"By\" requirements of the [When Digivolved] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not consumed. No [X times per turn] is consumed because the [When Digivolving] effect cannot be activated at the time of digivolved.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card with \"[When Digivolved] Effect is not activated\" has evolved into a card with [When Digivolved] [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn]. In this case, the effect could not be activated at the time it digivolved to that card, but does it consume the [X times per turn] of the effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is an effect that prevents a card's [When Digivolving] effect from being activated. When a card digivolves and triggers the [When Digivolving] effect, or the \"Activate [When Digivolving] effect\" effect, etc., the card will no longer be able to activate the [When Digivolving] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"[When Digivolving] effect is not activated\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. If the effect is triggered by [When Attacking], it can be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked with a card that has \"No [When Digivolving] effect activated\". In this case, can I activate the card's [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"No [When Digivolving] effect\" activate its own [When Digivolving] effect with the \"Activate 1 [When Digivolving] effect\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"No [When Digivolving] effect\" activate another card's [When Digivolving] effect with the \"Activate one [When Digivolving] effect as this card's effect\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the [When Digivolving] effect of a card that does not have the [When Digivolving] effect activated by another card that has the [When Digivolving] effect activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"Does not activate [When Digivolving] effect\" handle only the \"By\" requirements of the [When Digivolved] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not consumed. No [X times per turn] is consumed because the [When Digivolving] effect cannot be activated at the time of digivolved.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card with \"[When Digivolved] Effect is not activated\" has evolved into a card with [When Digivolved] [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn]. In this case, the effect could not be activated at the time it digivolved to that card, but does it consume the [X times per turn] of the effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the inherited effect of this card be activated even if the opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card as its digivolved card are deleted at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect grant \"Inactive\" to a different card than the card rested by this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since they are triggered simultaneously, the player can choose the order in which they are to be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon digivolved by this card's [When End of Your Turn] effect and attacked with that Digimon. In this case, in which order can the [When Digivolving] effect and [When Attacking] effect of the Digimon be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot attack with the effect of the second card. While attacking, you cannot declare a new attack. In this situation, at the end of your Turn, the two [When End of Your Turn] effects of this card are triggered simultaneously, and you attack with the first [End of Your Turn] effect. Before the Counter timing, the second [When End of Your Turn] effect can be activated, but since you cannot declare an Attack during the Attack, the second card cannot attack even if you activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have two copies of this card in my Battle Area. At the End of Your Turn, I attacked with the first card's [End of Your Turn] effect. Can I attack with the second card's [End of Your Turn] effect after that?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, for each Lv.6 card from which this card digivolves, rest an opponent's Digimon/tamer and give it Memory +1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect rest 2 opponent's Digimon or Tamer and give them Memory +2 if this card has 2 Lv.6 cards in its inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents a card's [On Play] effect from being activated. When a card appears and triggers the [On Play] effect, or the \"Activate [On Play] effect\" effect, etc., the card will no longer be able to activate the [On Play] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"[On Play] the effect is not activated\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. If the effect is triggered by [When Attacking], it can be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked with a card that has \"No [On Play] effect activated\". In this case, can I activate the card's [On Play] and [When Attacking] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"No [On Play] effect\" activate its own [On Play] effect with the \"Activate 1 [On Play] effect\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"No [On Play] effect\" activate another card's [On Play] effect with the \"Activate one [On Play] effect as this card's effect\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the [On Play] effect of a card that does not have the \"No [On Play] effect\" option?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with \"Does not activate [On Play] effect\" handle only the \"By\" condition of the [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not consumed. No [X times per turn] is consumed because the [On Play] effect cannot be activated at the time of play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card with [On Play] [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] appeared while the \"[On Play] effect is not activated.\" was in effect. In this case, the effect could not be activated at the time the card played, but does it consume the [X times per turn] of the effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not trigger. In the Breeding Area, no effects other than those of the [Breeding] icon can be triggered or activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card in Breeding Area evolves into a Digimon card with \"Accel\" in its trait, does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It is either \"my blue Digimon with the text 'DRACOMON'\" or \"my blue Digimon with the text 'EXAMON'\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when any card plays?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT20-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect grant \"Inactive\" to a different card than the one rested by this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This [All Turns] effect is activated while this card is in the Battle Area. It cannot be treated as \"Break Drumon\" in your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the \"Blast Joggles\" in \"BT20-045 Examon ACE\" to treat this card in my hand as a \"Break Dramon\" with this card's [All Turns] effect to make a DNA digivolves digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the inherited effect of this card be activated even if the opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card as its digivolved card are deleted at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since they are triggered simultaneously, the player can choose the order in which they are to be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon digivolved by this card's [When End of Your Turn] effect and attacked with that Digimon. In this case, in which order can the [When Digivolving] effect and [When Attacking] effect of the Digimon be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot attack with the effect of the second card. While attacking, you cannot declare a new attack. In this situation, at the end of your Turn, the two [When End of Your Turn] effects of this card are triggered simultaneously, and you attack with the first [End of Your Turn] effect. Before the Counter timing, the second [When End of Your Turn] effect can be activated, but since you cannot declare an Attack during the Attack, the second card cannot attack even if you activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have two copies of this card in my Battle Area. At the End of Your Turn, I attacked with the first card's [End of Your Turn] effect. Can I attack with the second card's [End of Your Turn] effect after that?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The text is either \"My Digimon with the text \"DRACOMON\"\" or \"My Digimon with the text \"EXAMON\"\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Opponent's Turns] effect trigger when any card deletes an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [All Opponent's Turns] effect be activated even if the opponent's Digimon and this card are deleted at the same time?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The text is either \"My Digimon with the text \"DRACOMON\"\" or \"My Digimon with the text \"EXAMON\"\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which digivolved card's inherited effect is triggered when it deletes an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the inherited effect of this card be activated even if the opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card as its digivolved card are deleted at the same time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Your Turns] effect trigger when either you or your opponent's Digimon is rested?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it will not trigger. In the Breeding Area, no effects other than those of the [Breeding] icon can be triggered or activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card in Breeding Area evolves into a Digimon card with \"Cyborg type\" or \"Machine type\" as its trait, does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Turn the second card from the top of the security face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The situation is that only the top card of the opponent's security is face-up. If you activate the [When Digivolving] effect of this card, which card of the security should you turn face up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It becomes ostensible security and remains public. The rules are the same as for normal security, except that it is ostensible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to a card placed face up in security by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Checked as published. The rules are the same as for normal checks, except as published.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when checking a security placed face down?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a security placed face up is checked, does the card's [Security] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The security that was face up is turned back face down and then shuffled. After shuffling, the cards are not turned face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when shuffling a security that contains a security placed face up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Turn the second card from the top of the security face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The situation is that only the top card of the opponent's security is face-up. If you activate the [When Digivolving] effect of this card, which card of the security should you turn face up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It becomes ostensible security and remains public. The rules are the same as for normal security, except that it is ostensible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to a card placed face up in security by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Checked as published. The rules are the same as for normal checks, except as published.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when checking a security placed face down?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a security placed face up is checked, does the card's [Security] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The security that was face up is turned back face down and then shuffled. After shuffling, the cards are not turned face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when shuffling a security that contains a security placed face up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked with this card and checked the security face-up. At this time, if I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect and place one of the stacked cards from the top under the security, does it trigger the [End of Attack] effect of the Digimon that was under this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Turn the second card from the top of the security face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The situation is that only the top card of the opponent's security is face-up. If you activate the [When Digivolving] effect of this card, which card of the security should you turn face up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It becomes ostensible security and remains public. The rules are the same as for normal security, except that it is ostensible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to a card placed face up in security by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Checked as published. The rules are the same as for normal checks, except as published.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when checking a security placed face down?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a security placed face up is checked, does the card's [Security] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The security that was face up is turned back face down and then shuffled. After shuffling, the cards are not turned face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when shuffling a security that contains a security placed face up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked with this card and checked the security face-up. At this time, if I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect and place one of the stacked cards from the top under the security, does it trigger the [End of Attack] effect of the Digimon that was under this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects cause a Digimon in the Breeding Area to digivolve, does the Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon card with \"Machine type\" in its trait at a play cost of 11 or less or a Digimon card with \"Cyborg type\" in its trait at a play cost of 11 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect is not affected by effects. For example, \"Rest an opponent's Digimon.\" effect will not be rested, and \"DP-3000 an opponent's Digimon.\" will not be minus DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What is the effect of \"not taking effect?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with the \"no effect\" effect be selected for an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be granted. The effect is not affected, but can be granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card with a \"no effect\" effect be given an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: From the point of no longer being affected by the effect, it is no longer affected by the effect being granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card with an effect is given an effect and later gets a \"no effect\" effect, what happens to the effect that is given?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: From the time it becomes subject to the effect, it is affected by the effect being granted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card with a \"no effect\" effect that is granted an effect later loses the \"no effect\" effect, what happens to the granted effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not trigger. If you give an effect that triggers to a Digimon that does not receive the effect, the effect will not be triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I added a triggering effect such as [When Attacking] effect to a card with \"No Effect\" effect. If the card then satisfies the conditions for triggering that effect, does the effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they will not be deleted at that time. After all [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects of this card are resolved, all Digimon with DP 0 at that time will be deleted at the same time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect has reduced the Digimon's DP to 0. In this case, will the Digimon be deleted before the rest of this effect is processed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they do not leave the Battle Area. DNA digivolves digivolve as a new Digimon, so it is a different Digimon than the one that leaves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [All Turns] effect is activated and two Digimon including the leaving Digimon digivolve, does the digivolved Digimon leave the Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since it is triggered simultaneously, it is activated from the turn player's side of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which can be activated first, the [When Digivolving] effect of the opponent's Digimon digivolved by the effect or the [All Opponent's Turns] effect of this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digivolutions are triggered when Digimon are digivolved by effects such as \"P-103 Offense Training. The effects of BT4-011 Agunimon, which treats tamers as Lv.3 Digimon, and BT6-060 Deputymon, which ignores digivolution requirements, are not triggered because they do not cause digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When is the [All Turns] effect of this card triggered?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Since they are triggered simultaneously, the player can choose the order in which they are to be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has multiple effects that are triggered when it plays, in what order can they be activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I not attack with my Digimon after this card's [All Your Turns] effect activates this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect select one of my opponent's Digimon twice and make it -20,000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they will not be deleted at that time. After all [On Play] and [When Digivolving] effects of this card are resolved, all Digimon with DP 0 at that time will be deleted at the same time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect has reduced the Digimon's DP to 0. In this case, will the Digimon be deleted before the rest of this effect is processed?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The conditions of the [By] effect cannot be performed only in part. For the conditions of this [All Your Turns] effect, you must return the specified number of cards from your trash to the deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the condition for this card's [All Your Turns] effect be to return only two cards from your trash to the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect can be triggered and activated while the card is in the Breeding Area. It cannot be triggered or activated outside of the Breeding Area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What are the effects of the [nurturing] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can be played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon in my Breeding Area that has this card as its digivolution card. Can I use this card's inherited effect to rest that Digimon and play the digivolution card itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect can be triggered/activated while the card is in the trash. It cannot be triggered or activated outside of the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What is the [Trash] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since they are triggered simultaneously, the player can choose the order in which they are to be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my \"Sistamon Ciel\" appears, in what order can I activate the Digimon's [On Play] effect and this card's [Trash] [All Your Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my \"Sistamon Ciel\" appears, can I activate this card's [Trash] [All Your Turns] effect first, and then activate the [When Digivolving] effect of the \"Sistamon Ciel\" that played after that Digimon has digivolved into this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A black Digimon card with \"Cyborg type\" or \"Machine type\" in its trait and a black Digimon card with \"Machine type\" in its play cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card must be placed in digivolution requirements for this card's [When Start of Your Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Turn the second card from the top of the security face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The situation is that only the top card of the opponent's security is face-up. If you activate the [When Digivolving] effect of this card, which card of the security should you turn face up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It becomes ostensible security and remains public. The rules are the same as for normal security, except that it is ostensible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to a card placed face up in security by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Checked as published. The rules are the same as for normal checks, except as published.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when checking a security placed face down?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a security placed face up is checked, does the card's [Security] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The security that was face up is turned back face down and then shuffled. After shuffling, the cards are not turned face up.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when shuffling a security that contains a security placed face up?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimons can digivolve in both Breeding Area and Battle Area. Area\" refers to both the Breeding Area and the Battle Area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Your Turn] effect, \"Evolve Digimon in Area\", evolve Digimon in either the Breeding Area or Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [Your Turn] effect causes a Digimon in the Breeding Area to digivolve, does it trigger the [When Digivolving] effect of that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT20-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot attack with the effect of the second card. While attacking, you cannot declare a new attack. In this situation, at the end of your Turn, the two [When End of Your Turn] effects of this card are triggered simultaneously, and you attack with the first [End of Your Turn] effect. Before the Counter timing, the second [When End of Your Turn] effect can be activated, but since you cannot declare an Attack during the Attack, the second card cannot attack even if you activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have two copies of this card in my Battle Area. At the End of Your Turn, I attacked with the first card's [End of Your Turn] effect. Can I attack with the second card's [End of Your Turn] effect after that?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon card with the text \"DRACOMON\" or a Digimon card with the text \"EXAMON\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon card with the text \"DRACOMON\" or a Digimon card with the text \"EXAMON\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when any card leaves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they do not leave the Battle Area. DNA digivolves digivolve as a new Digimon, so it is a different Digimon than the one that leaves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If two Digimon including the leaving Digimon digivolved by the \"Delay\" effect of this card, does the Digimon that digivolved DNA digivolves leave the Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Security] effects are activated first. Security] effects, if checked, will be activated immediately without pending activation. Other triggered effects are activated from the turn player's side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Security] effect, the \"when security is checked\" effect, and the \"when security is reduced\" effect are triggered simultaneously, in which order do they activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect can be triggered/activated while the card is in the trash. It cannot be triggered or activated outside of the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What is the [Trash] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The [By] condition cannot be performed only in part. For the [Main] effect of this card, it must be returned to the bottom of the deck for the specified Lv. total.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to return cards in my opponent's trash to the bottom of the deck so that their Lv. total is 8 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon cards of Lv.3 and Lv.6 can be played. You can play one Digimon card of the same Lv. as the returned card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Main] effect of this card returns Lv.3 and Lv.6 Digimon cards from the opponent's Trash to the deck, which Lv. Digimon card can I play from my Trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can play. You can play one card of the same Lv. as the card you returned.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the [Main] effect of this card returns 3 Lv.3 Digimon cards from the opponent's trash to the deck, can I play 3 Lv.3 Digimon cards from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, triggered.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Your Turns] effect trigger when either you or your opponent's Digimon is rested?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be rested.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect be rested on either my or my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT20-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Digimon that are given \"Quick Attack\" by this effect will attack without rest as much as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to grant \"Quick Attack\" to one of my Digimon and then not attack with that Digimon without rest?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can attack with a Digimon in rest state.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When attacking with this card's [End of Your Turn] effect, can I attack with a Digimon in Rest state?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot attack with the effect of the second card. While attacking, you cannot declare a new attack. In this situation, at the end of your Turn, the two [When End of Your Turn] effects of this card are triggered simultaneously, and you attack with the first [End of Your Turn] effect. Before the Counter timing, the second [When End of Your Turn] effect can be activated, but since you cannot declare an Attack during the Attack, the second card cannot attack even if you activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have two copies of this card in my Battle Area. At the End of Your Turn, I attacked with the first card's [End of Your Turn] effect. Can I attack with the second card's [End of Your Turn] effect after that?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30c1\u30d3\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Vee\" (\u30d6\u30a4) in its name.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Vee]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you declared that you will be attacking your opponent, and your opponent decides to block your attack, resulting in a battle between Digimon, the effect does not activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked my opponent with a Digimon with this card as one of its digivolution cards, and it was blocked. In this situation, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you only reveal one or the other, you only get to add one card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include only either [RagnaLoardmon] or cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may add them both to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include 2 [RagnaLoardmon] cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I add both of those cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.  However, if the revealed [RagnaLoardmon] has the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, that card will be treated as a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait. By adding it to your hand, you can return other cards with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait to the bottom of the deck without adding them to your hand, and if there aren't any other [RagnaLoardmon] revealed, you can add just 1 [RagnaLoardmon] to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a [RagnaLoardmon] card and a card with [Legend-Arms] in its type, do I only get to add 1 to my hand and have to return the rest to the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since this Digimon is treated as both red and yellow during your turn, it can digivolve into a Digimon with a digivolution requirement of \"Yellow, Level 5.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon Digivolve into a Digimon which has a Digivolution requirement of \"Yellow, Level 5?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [Your Turn] effects don't activate from breeding areas, so the card isn't treated as a yellow card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a yellow Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a yellow Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The DP value printed on a card is its original DP. This card's [When Digivolving] effect causes a target Digimon's DP, regardless of what's written on the card, to be temporarily treated as having 1000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"Original DP\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent's Digimon's DP will be overwritten as 1000, and if a -1000 DP effect is being applied to it, its DP becomes 0, causing the Digimon to be deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated against an opponent's Digimon whose DP has been reduced by 1000 by an effect, what happens to that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose whether or not to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect if I have either [Durandamon] or [BryweLudramon] in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The relevant card is placed directly under this card, or at the very top of this card's digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [When Digivolving] effect, how are either the [Durandamon] or [BryweLudramon] cards in your hand placed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if the memory counter moves to 1 or greater on your opponent's side temporarily, if activating the effect moves the memory counter back to 0 or greater on your side, your turn continues.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Paying this Digimon's digivolution cost resulted in the memory counter being placed at 1 or above on my opponent's side. However, the [When Digivolving] effect allowed me to gain 3 memory, putting the memory counter at 0 or above on my side.  When this happens, does the turn end?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect is compulsory like [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode]. So, it was already used when the attack was declared and cannot put [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode] to active as the effect was already used on the 1st attack. [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode]'s effect is also compulsory, so both [BT3-027 Paildramon] and [BT3-111 Imperialdrmaon: Dragon Mode]'s effects cannot be used on the second attack.",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve this card into [BT3-111 Imperialdramon: Dragon Mode] and attack with it deleting an opponent's in battle and surviving. I unsuspend it with its own effect. When I attack again, can I use this card's effect to unsuspend it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to use it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [When Evolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect on a Level 4 Digimon card that's part of this card's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because the effect is only active during [Your Turn], the moment the Digimon becomes Level 5 or above, the effect no longer applies to the Digimon, and it will lose \uff1cJamming\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Will this card's [Your Turn] effect result in my Level 4 Digimon with \uff1cJamming\uff1e losing \uff1cJamming\uff1e when Digivolving to Level 5 or above?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can't activate this effect when digivolving a card in your breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving this card onto a [Paildramon] or [Dinobeemon] in my breeding area, can I reduce the digivolution cost by 2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It's placed at the top of the security stack, face down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After checking the top security card using this card's effect, if that card cannot be added to my hand, what happens to that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I check my top security card using this card's effect and add it to my hand, do I have to reveal it to my opponent?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e if you add a security card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 0 cards left in my security stack, can I still \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e as a result of this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the latter half of the effect, \"Look at the top card of your security stack. You may add that card to your hand to trigger...\" can still be activated even if you have 0 cards in your deck and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e cannot be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 0 cards left in my deck, can I still look at one of my security cards and add it to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since this Digimon is treated as both yellow and blue during your turn, it can digivolve into a Digimon with a requirement of \"Blue, Level 5.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon digivolve into a Digimon with a digivolution condition of \"Blue, Level 5\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [Your Turn] effects don't activate from breeding areas, so the card isn't treated as a yellow card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a blue Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a blue Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the moment your Digimon gains a digivolution card, it no longer counts as a \"Digimon with no digivolution cards,\" and loses <Security Attack -1>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I digivolve one of my Digimon that currently has no digivolution cards, does its <Security Attack -1> immediately disappear?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, when moving a card from your trash to your security stack, you must show the card to your opponent so they can confirm it's a yellow Digimon card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's effect to place a yellow Digimon card from your trash on your security stack, do I need to show that card to my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you end up with 4 or more security cards, the Digimon will have -6000 DP for the duration of the turn in which the effect was activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give my opponent's Digimon -6000 DP. Later in the turn, I end up with 4 cards in my security stack. Does the -6000 DP effect go away?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't use Option/Digimon card effects to gain memory, but you can still lose memory if a card effect specifies as such.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play when I activate the effect on a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain any memory from it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play. Do I gain memory from [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]'s [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The cards I reveal with this effect include only a level 5 or level 6 digimon, not both. Can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Its [Your Turn] effect is only active when this card is in play in the battle area.",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to suspend an opponent's Digimon for its own \uff1cDigisorption -3\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot.",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this Digimon, can I suspend 2 of my opponent's Digimon when I digivolve into 1 Digimon with \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.",
      "question": "Q: If I do not have any unsuspended Digimon, can I still suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon for \uff1cDigisorption\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: By activating this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I prevent my opponent's Digimon from becoming unsuspended during my opponent's next unsuspend phase by applying this effect to it while it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you still get BanchoStingmon's effect. \uff1cBlocker\uff1e happens after all [When Attacking] effects and BanchoStingmon's effect keeps the changes for the turn. (See more in Attack Resolution)",
      "question": "Q: My opponent blocks [BT3-058 BanchoStingmon]. Do I still get its effect off?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. This effect behaves the same way as an effect that reads \"When this Digimon attacks one of your opponent's Digimon with 12000 DP or more\". As such, the requirement for 12000 DP or more is checked at the time the attack is declared and determines whether or not the effect triggers. After the effect has triggered, this requirement does not impact the effect's activation.",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent's Digimon with 12000 DP or more with this Digimon, then one of my effects reduces that Digimon's DP to be under 12000. Does this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can still use BanchoStingmon's effect if the attack target's DP decreases before BanchoStingmon's effect activates as long as it was 12000 DP when it was targeted for the attack.",
      "question": "Q: I have activated [BT1-104 Golden Ripper] and attack with [BT3-058 BanchoStingmon]. If I attack with this card and use [BT1-104 Golden Ripper]'s effect to decrease the attack of the attack target from 12000 DP to 10000 DP before I use its effect, can I use this card's effect to give it 7000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect did not fulfill its trigger condition.",
      "question": "Q: If this card attacks a Digimon with less than 12000 DP and then one of my effects increases it to 12000 DP or more afterwards. Can I use this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't use Option/Digimon card effects to gain memory, but you can still lose memory if a card effect specifies as such.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play when I activate the effect on a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain any memory from it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play. Do I gain memory from [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]'s [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you only reveal one or the other, you only get to add one card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include only either [RagnaLoardmon] or cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you may add them both to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include 2 [RagnaLoardmon] cards with [Legend-Arms] in their types, can I add both of those cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect allows you to add both cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck include both a [RagnaLoardmon] card and a card with [Legend-Arms] in its type, do I only get to add 1 to my hand and have to return the rest to the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"Black Lv.5 or lower Digimon card\" or \"Red Lv.5 or lower Digimon card\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: In response to this Digimon attack, an opponent\u2019s Digimon cannot redirect this Digimon's attack when activating the \uff1cBlocker\uff1e effect.",
      "question": "Q: This card reads, \u2018This Digimon is unblockable.\u2019 What exactly does that mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon can still be suspended but the attack will not be redirected.",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent still suspend their Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Card text that uses \"delete,\" such as \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon,\" can't be used to delete your cards with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e They can still be deleted by losing battles or being reduced to zero DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"can't be deleted by your opponent's effects\" on this card's [All Turns] effect refer to, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't use Option/Digimon card effects to gain memory, but you can still lose memory if a card effect specifies as such.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play when I activate the effect on a card like [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], or [BT1-075 Digitamamon]. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't gain any memory from it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this card in play. Do I gain memory from [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]'s [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to use it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attacking Digimon was deleted, so the attack ends.  However, other \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects and effects activated at counter timing are activated before the attack ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. When this Digimon is deleted after this, what happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. After this Digimon is deleted, its other [When Attacking] effects can't be activated.  You can, however, activate other [When Attacking] effects prior to activating this card's [When Attacking] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. This Digimon is then deleted, but can I still activate any [When Attacking] inherited effects on this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, BT3-92 [MaloMyotismon] is in play when this card is deleted, so you gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. This Digimon is then deleted, but do I gain a memory from [MaloMyotismon]'s \"[All Turns] When another Digimon is deleted, gain 1 memory\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to use it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attacking Digimon was deleted, so the attack ends.  However, other \"when one of your Digimon attacks\" effects and effects activated at counter timing are activated before the attack ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. When this Digimon is deleted after this, what happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. After this Digimon is deleted, its other [When Attacking] effects can't be activated.  You can, however, activate other [When Attacking] effects prior to activating this card's [When Attacking] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. Can I then activate any [When Attacking] inherited effects on this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, BT3-92 [MaloMyotismon] is in play when this card is deleted, so you gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card, and use its [When Attacking] effect to play [MaloMyotismon]. This Digimon is then deleted, but do I gain a memory from [MaloMyotismon]'s \"[All Turns] When another Digimon is deleted, gain 1 memory\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It happens after activating the Option card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's inherited effect to delete an opponent's level 3 Digimon. Does this happen before or after activating the Option card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the opponent's Digimon is level 3 at the time the Option card's effect activates, you can delete it with this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use an Option card with \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards), like BT2-105 [Spider Shooter], to reduce an opponent's level 4 or greater Digimon to level 3. Can I then use this card's inherited effect to delete that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't have a level 4 or lower purple or yellow Digimon card in my trash, do both players still trash the top card of their security stack from this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do the [Security] effects on cards trashed by this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, just because there are no security cards to trash doesn't mean you win the game.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect when my opponent has an empty security stack, do I win the game?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If either or both players have empty security stacks, can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to play a level 4 or lower purple or yellow Digimon card from my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, please trash.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect trash one of each other's security from the top, even if there is no purple or yellow Lv.4 or lower Digimon card in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not activate.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the [When Digivolving] effect of this card activate the security effect that the card you trash has?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, just because you cannot trash a security card does not mean you win the game.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated when the opponent has 0 security, does it win the game?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can play.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated when I or my opponent or both have 0 security, can I still play a purple or yellow Lv.4 or lower Digimon card from my trash without paying cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"Purple Lv.4 or lower Digimon card\" or \"Yellow Lv.4 or lower Digimon card\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You gain the memory after activating the Option card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain +2 memory from this card's [Your Turn] effect before or after activating the Option card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both you and your opponent's Digimon were deleted, so you gain two memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon in play when one of my other Digimon attacks, deletes an opponent's Digimon, and is deleted in return. Do I gain two memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Security Digimon aren't considered to be Digimon, so you don't gain any memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 1 memory from this Digimon's effect when a Security Digimon is deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the +1 memory effect activates twice, earning you two memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I had this Digimon, another of my Digimon attacked, and both my Digimon and my opponent's Digimon were deleted in the battle. Do I gain 2 memory at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the turn player gains a memory first, followed by the non-turn player gaining a memory, returning the memory gauge to its original position.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent and I both have this Digimon in play. If another Digimon is deleted, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This Digimon was deleted, so the [All Turns] effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks an opponent's Digimon and both Digimon end up being deleted, can I gain a memory off this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"Blue Digimon card\" and one \"Green Digimon card.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Security Digimon aren't considered to be Digimon, so this Tamer's effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My green or blue Digimon deletes an opponent's Security Digimon in battle and survives. Can I suspend this Tamer to gain a memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Security Digimon are not treated as Digimon, so this tamer cannot be activated.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon in green or blue deletes only the opponent's security Digimon in battle, can I rest this tamer and get Memory +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It's either 'my green Digimon' or 'my blue Digimon.'[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Your Turn] effect be activated when which card deletes it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. No matter how many Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e you have, you only gain 1 memory from this Tamer's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e in play, do I gain memory for each one?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You gain the memory after activating the Option card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When do I gain a memory from this card's effect? Before I activate an Option card, or after?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an Option card through a \"use an Option card\" effect, can I activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Flipping over an Option card from your security stack isn't considered to be using an Option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During a security check, one of my Option cards with a [Security] effect is flipped over. Can I activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Activating the \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect on Option cards in your battle area isn't considered to be using an Option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate the \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect on an Option card placed in my battle area. Can I then activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card only prevents the [Security] effects on Option cards from being activated. [Security] effects on Digimon and Tamer cards activate as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect prevent the [Security] effects on checked Digimon and Tamer security cards from activating?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect prevent my Digimon from being deleted when it loses a battle against my opponent's Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only prevents Digimon from being deleted as a result of battle. [When Attacking] effects, other card effects, and being reduced to 0 DP will still delete Digimon as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect prevent me from deleting an opponent's Digimon using a [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you don't have a green Digimon in play when you activate the card's effect, you can't activate the part of the effect that suspends an opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I play a green Digimon. Can I suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent chooses. If they decide not to trash any security cards, the player who used this card receives the benefits of the <Recovery +1 (Deck)> effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card, does my opponent get to decide whether or not they trash one of their security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Your opponent doesn't have a security card to trash, which means you get the <Recovery +1 (Deck)> effect automatically.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card if my opponent's security stack is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve from a Digimon that was suspended by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect only applies when digivolving a Digimon that's already green.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the same turn I used this card, I digivolve a non-green Digimon into a green Digimon. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. As long as you're digivolving from a green Digimon, the effect applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the same turn I used this card, I digivolve a green Digimon into a non-green Digimon. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, can I reduce the digivolution cost of my green Digimon digivolving by suspending 1 of my Digimon when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you don't have a blue Digimon in play when you activate the card's effect, you can't activate the part of the effect that returns your opponent's suspended Digimon to their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card, then play a blue Digimon later in the turn, can I return an opponent's suspended Digimon to its owner's hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's security effect affects all of your opponent's Digimon, including Digimon that enter the battle area after the effect is activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After my opponent activates this card's security effect, they use [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa] to move a Digimon from their breeding area to their battle area. Can that Digimon attack me immediately?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if the Digimon has both \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and \uff1cReboot\uff1e, the card's effect can only be used once to grant \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card give <Security Attack +2> to a Digimon with both \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and \uff1cReboot\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon that loses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e or \uff1cReboot\uff1e also loses \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, as it is no longer affected by this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e to one of my Digimon, but if digivolution and <De-Digivolution> causes that Digimon to lose either \uff1cBlocker\uff1e or \uff1cReboot\uff1e, what happens to the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) causes it to become a Digimon with a play cost of 4 or less, you can delete it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card on one of my opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 5 or more, and \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) causes it to become a Digimon with a play cost of 4. Can I use this card's effect to delete that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to delete an opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 4 or less that doesn't have any digivolution cards, or on an opponent's level 3 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Its digivolution cards don't return to play, and remain in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon affected by this card was deleted. What happens to its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It loses all effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon affected by this card comes back into play after being deleted, does it retain any effects that were on it prior to deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's considered to have just entered play, so it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon affected by this card comes back into play after being deleted, can it attack that same turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT3-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can't activate this effect when digivolving a card in your breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving this card onto a [Paildramon] or [Dinobeemon] in my breeding area, can I reduce the digivolution cost by 2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's inherited effect is applied even during times where the Digimon can't activate <Digi-Burst>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is a digivolution card of a Digimon with <Digi-Burst> that activates at [On Play] or [When Digivolving] timings, is this card's inherited effect not applied outside of those timings?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's inherited effect is applied even if the Digimon doesn't have enough digivolutions to activate <Digi-Burst>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is a digivolution card of a Digimon with <Digi-Burst> that requires a certain number of digivolution cards to activate, is this card's inherited effect not activated unless the Digimon can activate <Digi-Burst>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You lose this card's inherited effect when it is placed in the trash, so it can't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 9 cards in my trash and a Digimon with this card as a digivolution card is deleted in battle. The deleted cards, including this one, are sent to my trash, and now I have over 10 cards in my trash. Does this card's \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you had 10 or more cards when it was deleted, you can activate \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 10 or more cards in my trash and a Digimon with this card as a digivolution card is deleted in battle. Before this card's effect has a chance to activate, another effect activates and reduces the number of cards in my trash to 9 or less. Does this card's \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After <Digi-Burst> activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by <Digi-Burst>, when does this card return to hand: before or after <Digi-Burst> activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"Digimon card with \"Hybrid Body\" in its traits\" and one \"Red Tamer card\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a tamer card as a digivolution card, does the [Security] effect of that tamer card become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve on top of a Level 3 Digimon that meets its requirements instead of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as playing, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I played a tamer card if I then digivolve this card on top of it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a tamer card as a digivolution card, does the [Security] effect of that tamer card become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve on top of a Level 3 Digimon that meets its requirements instead of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as playing, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I played a tamer card if I then digivolve this card on top of it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if it has both of those cards as digivolution cards, it only gets +4000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card get +8000 DP if it has a Digimon card with [Hybrid] in its form and a red tamer as digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If the digivolves have both a Digimon card with \"hybrid body\" as a trait and a red tamer card, they will only be DP+4000.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon digivolves from a Digimon card that has both a Digimon card with \"Hybrid Body\" as a trait and a red tamer card, does it get DP+8000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon card with \"Hybrid Body\" in its trait\" or \"Red tamer card\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate while any card is in digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When a card is in any area other than your battle area, [Your Turn] effects do not apply. So this card is not treated as a yellow card and is treated only as a red card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my hand, deck, or trash and another copy is revealed in a security check, is this Digimon treated as a yellow card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [Your Turn] effects do not apply in the breeding area, so this card is not treated as a yellow card and is treated only as a red card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in the breeding area, can I digivolve a Digimon on top of it that requires a yellow Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When it is outside of the Battle Area, it does not activate the effect of [Your Turn], so it does not activate the effect of treating it as a yellow card, but only as a red card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this Digimon treat this card as a yellow card when it is in hand, deck, trash, or when it is turned over by a check from security?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Your Turn] effect is not activated in the Breeding Area, so it is not treated as a Yellow card and cannot be evolved from a Yellow Digimon to a Digivolution-ready Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in the Breeding Area, can it evolve from a Yellow Digimon to a Digimon that can digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The card is either a \"Red tamer card with a play cost of 4 or less\" or a \"Yellow tamer card with a play cost of 4 or less\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [Main] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple of your red and/or yellow tamers are suspended at the same time, there is still only one instance of cards being suspended, so this card only gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If 2 of my red and/or yellow Tamers are suspended at the same time, does this Digimon gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e twice?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If your red and/or yellow tamers are suspended at 2 different timings, this card would gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e twice, allowing you to check two extra cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If 2 of my red and/or yellow Tamers are suspended at different timings, does this Digimon gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e twice?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After <Digi-Burst> activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by <Digi-Burst>, when does this card return to hand: before or after <Digi-Burst> activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: As long as one or the other is in the cards you revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Am I unable to add cards to my hand with this card's effect if a Digimon card with [Hybrid] and a blue tamer aren't both in the cards I've revealed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"Digimon card with \"Hybrid Body\" in its traits\" and one \"Blue Tamer card\".[2]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if there was only either a Digimon card with \"Hybrid Body\" in its trait or a blue tamer card, it will be added to your hand.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card require both a Digimon card with \"Hybrid Body\" in its trait and a blue tamer card among the three cards revealed to be added to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a tamer card as a digivolution card, does the [Security] effect of that tamer card become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve on top of a Level 3 Digimon that meets its requirements instead of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as playing, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I played a tamer card if I then digivolve this card on top of it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a tamer card as a digivolution card, does the [Security] effect of that tamer card become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve on top of a Level 3 Digimon that meets its requirements instead of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as playing, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I played a tamer card if I then digivolve this card on top of it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It is trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that as long as you meet the conditions for the skill, the card can't be targeted by your opponent's Digimon for attacks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"this card can't be attacked\" [Opponent's Turn] skill mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's effect only prevents your opponent's Digimon from attacking you, so blocking will work as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card activates \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and blocks the attack of one of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect is that this card does not become a target of attacks from opposing Digimon while it meets the conditions.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does it mean that this card has the effect of not being attacked on the opponent's turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the effect of this card is only not to be attacked by the opponent, blocking can be performed as usual, and it becomes a battle.[3]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this Digimon blocks an attack by an opponent's Digimon when it has gained \"Blocker\" by some effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon card with \"Hybrid Body\" in its trait\" or \"Blue tamer card\".[4]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate while any card is in the digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck instead of the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"return 1 of your other Digimon to its owner's hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to return my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] from the battle area to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your token is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be removed from the game instead of being returned to the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by returning 1 of your Digimon to the hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to return my token that was played as a Digimon from the battle area to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Since there's no color specified in the effect, it will work with any color tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect work with any color of tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you didn't trash any digivolution cards with the [When Attacking] effect, you don't get to trigger \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e or gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon attacked, my opponent didn't have any Digimon with digivolution cards, and I wasn't able to use the [When Attacking] effect to trash digivolution cards. Do I still get to trigger \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and gain 1 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I digivolved into this card, my opponent had 3 or less cards in their hand. Do I still gain memory from the [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have a Digimon with this effect, your opponent's Digimon can't block against its attacks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does \"this Digimon is unblockable\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Attacking suspended Digimon isn't blocking, so you can attack them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"this Digimon is unblockable\" mean this Digimon can't attack my opponent's suspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You don't have any security cards to trash, so you can't activate this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have no cards left in my security stack, can I use this card's [On Play] effect to decrease the DP of 1 of my opponent's Digimon by 2000?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect only trashes cards from your security stack and isn't the same as you taking an attack. If you have no cards left in your security stack at the end of your opponent's turn, you continue the game as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [At End of Opponent's Turn] effect mean that if I have no cards left in my security stack, at the end of my opponent's turn I lose the game?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do the [Security] effects on cards trashed by this card's [At End of Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple copies of this Digimon in my battle area, do I trash multiple security cards at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I always have to activate this card's effect when I attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you can't add cards from your security stack to your hand, you can't activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [When Attacking] effect if I have no cards left in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect has [Once Per Turn], so it doesn't activate on any attacks past the first one.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this Digimon, then activate its [When Attacking] effect to unsuspend it and give 1 of my opponent's Digimon -6000 DP. If I attack again on the same turn, can I give 1 of my opponent's Digimon an additional -6000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Digimon played after the effect's activation also lose DP.",
      "question": "Q: Does [BT4-049 Varodurumon]'s \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect also decrease the DP of Digimon that were played after the activation of its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After <Digi-Burst> activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by <Digi-Burst>, when does this card return to hand: before or after <Digi-Burst> activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect targets \"1 of your opponent's suspended Digimon,\" so you can't target unsuspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect be activated against my opponent's unsuspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect on [Orochimon] itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, since there's no color specified.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect be activated no matter what color my Tamer is?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as it's a level 4 or lower Digimon, you can suspend it -- including your own Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend one my own Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving doesn't count as the card being played, so you can't suspend it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend a level 4 Digimon when it Digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Moving from the breeding area doesn't count as the card being played, so you can't suspend it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend a level 4 or lower Digimon when it moves from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to return Digimon that were already suspended to their owners' decks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After <Digi-Burst> activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by <Digi-Burst>, when does this card return to hand: before or after <Digi-Burst> activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also activate for [BT4-66 Golemon] itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effects for both copies are triggered, but since the cards themselves have been deleted and sent to the trash, they're no longer in the battle area, which means their effects can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this Digimon in my battle area, and both are deleted at the same time by an opponent's skill. Do both copies activate their [On Deletion] skills?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose [BT4-072 Gogmamon] itself as the target for this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The order you return cards in is public information.",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to return multiple cards to my deck, do I need to tell my opponent the order I return the cards in? "
    }
  ],
  "BT4-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When this Digimon attacks, no matter what its target is, this effect allows your opponent to choose any of their unsuspended Digimon. If they do, this Digimon is forced to attack it instead.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What exactly does this card's [When Attacking] effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you are.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When attacking with this card, am I required to announce the target of attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't announce that you're attacking an opponent's unsuspended Digimon, but your opponent can force this Digimon to attack one of their unsuspended Digimon if they choose to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to attack my opponent's unsuspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the player who is currently being attacked gets to decide whether or not to switch the target. If they choose not to, the attack proceeds as it was originally declared.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with [BT4-075 Blastmon]. If I have an unsuspended Digimon in play, am I forced to switch the target of attack to it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After <Digi-Burst> activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card and is trashed by <Digi-Burst>, when does this card return to hand: before or after <Digi-Burst> activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only trash 1 Option card per attack, so you can only gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to trash 2 Option cards in my hand to gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if your opponent suspends multiple Tamers simultaneously, this card's inherited effect treats all of it as a single timing instance, so you only gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent uses the effect on a card like [BT2-041 ShineGreymon] to suspend 2 or more of their Tamers, does this card's inherited effect allow me to gain a memory for each Tamer suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [On Play] effect can delete [Cerebusmon], which is a different card from [Cerberusmon: Werewolf Mode]. As such, you can't use it to delete this card itself.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to delete this card itself to gain 9 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [On Play] effect can delete [Cerebusmon], which is a different card from [Cerberusmon: Werewolf Mode]. As such, you can't use it to delete this card itself.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to delete one of my other [Cerberusmon: Werewolf Mode] cards to gain 9 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do Digimon played from the trash with this card's [When Digivolving] effect also gain \uff1cRush\uff1e from this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Digimon that gain \uff1cRush\uff1e from this card's effect keep it after Digivolving, and can attack the turn they come into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon from the trash, then digivolve that Digimon during the same turn, does that Digimon gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: You use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to trash a card in your opponent's security stack. Does that card's [Security] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses the 2 cards to trash from their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the cards to trash from your opponent's hand with this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, a card was removed from your security stack, so it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While this Digimon is in my battle area, my opponent's Digimon checks my security stack and flips over [BT1-107 Holy Wave]. Its [Security] effect activates, adding a card to my security stack. I ended up with the same number of cards in my security stack, but does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they both activate, trashing 2 of your opponent's security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this Digimon in my battle area when an opponent's Digimon does a security check, removing a card from my security stack. Do the [Opponent's Turn] effects on both copies activate, trashing 2 of my opponent's security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent uses a card like [BT2-020 Gallantmon] to trash a card in my security directly, can I activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. It doesn't become your opponent's turn until the attack ends or you declare that you're not making an attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I pay memory to digivolve into this Digimon. Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to attack even though my memory gauge is now at 1 or greater on my opponent's side?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't ignore the ironclad rule that Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play, so you can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Digimon, then digivolve into this card on the same turn. Can I attack with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect first and announce your attack, but you must activate all other effects before making the attack itself.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have other effects that activate on digivolution, can I attack before activating those effects after digivolving into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack my opponent's unsuspended Digimon with this card when not attacking through its [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [When Digivolving] skill against the same Digimon twice in a row?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [When Digivolving] skill once, take a different action, then activate it a second time?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This Tamer will be able to attack in the same way as a Digimon, and will also receive effects that target Digimon. It will also be deleted in battles with Digimon or Security Digimon.",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect treat this Tamer as a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it will be deleted.",
      "question": "Q: If the DP of this card, which is treated as a Digimon due to the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, is reduced to 0 by an opponent's effect, will it be deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, When this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] activates, this card is treated as both a Digimon and a Tamer, so when it is suspended, it is considered to meet the conditions \"When this Tamer is suspended\".",
      "question": "Q: When this card, treated as a Digimon due to the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, is suspended, this card's [Your Turn] effect of \"When this tamer is suspended\" activate because it's currently a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it does not. The effect of this card is only treated as a \"Digimon\", and when it is placed in the evolution source of another Digimon, it is treated as a Tamer card and the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect that was activated is lost.",
      "question": "Q: If this card, which is treated as a Digimon due to the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect, is chosen for the effect of \"Place 1 Digimon as a digivolution card of another Digimon\". Does that count as \"digivolving from this Digimon\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, there's no color specified, so the +1000 DP is granted no matter what color your Digimon are.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect grant +1000 DP no matter what color my Digimon are?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can activate it when digivolving into any Digimon with <Digi-Burst>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I only activate this card's [Your Turn] effect when digivolving into a Digimon with [When Digivolving] <Digi-Burst>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The order you return cards in is public information.",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect to return multiple cards to my deck, do I need to tell my opponent the order I return the cards in? "
    }
  ],
  "BT4-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as long as there are attacks and effects that have triggered but haven't finished resolving yet, the attack continues regardless of the memory gauge's current position.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent's Digimon attacks and checks my security, I activate this card's effect to gain 1 memory, moving the memory counter to 1 on my side. Does the attack end, even if my opponent's Digimon has checks remaining from \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because a card was removed from your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While this Tamer is in my battle area, my opponent's Digimon checks my security stack and flips over [BT1-107 Holy Wave]. Its [Security] effect activates, adding a card to my security stack. The number of cards in my security stack remained the same, but can I still suspend this card to gain 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because a card was removed from your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While this Tamer is in my battle area, I use [BT1-087 Matt Ishida]'s effect to add a yellow card from my security stack to my hand, triggering <Recovery +1 (Deck)> and adding a card to my security stack. The number of cards in my security stack remained the same, but can I still suspend this card to gain 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent uses a card like [BT2-020 Gallantmon] to trash a card in my security directly, can I activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate an effect like [BT4-104 Blinding Ray] to remove cards from my own security stack, can I activate this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"No, you can't. Since this card hasn't been played when it is revealed from your security, the condition for [When a card is removed from your security stack] can't be triggered, so this card's effect can't be activated.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is played by its [Security] effect, can I suspend it to gain 1 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, your opponent has to use \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block the attack in order for you to gain 3 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card on one of my Digimon, which I use to attack an opponent's Digimon. Does this count as the Digimon being blocked? Do I gain 3 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect applies to all of your Digimon, including those that enter the battle area after the start of your turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's [Security] effect. I move a Digimon from my breeding area to the battle area, then play a Digimon from my hand. Do these Digimon get \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when my opponent doesn't have a Digimon with 6000 DP or less in play to play a Tamer card with a play cost of 4 or less from my hand without paying its memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's deleted by this card's effect, not by battle.  As such, effects that read, \"deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives,\" and effects like \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e don't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to grant my Digimon this card's effect. I then use one of my Digimon to attack an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards. Does my opponent's Digimon get deleted in battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect deletes your Digimon before blocker timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses this card during their turn, then attacks one of my Digimon with no digivolution cards. Can I block with one of my other Digimon to prevent that Digimon from being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The Digimon that was a target of the attack will still be deleted by the effect of this card, but you can still block as counter timing and blocker timing will occur normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses this card during their turn, then attacks one of my Digimon with no digivolution cards. Can I block with one of my other Digimon to force it to attack that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect granted by this card will only delete the Digimon that was the target of the attack. If you block to force the target of attack to change, the blocking Digimon won't be deleted, and the battle will occur normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses this card during their turn, then attacks one of my Digimon with no digivolution cards. If I block with one of my other Digimon, will it be deleted by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can delete your opponent's Digimon with this card's effect before the battle begins. The attacking Digimon is not deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon has been granted the effect from this card. If I use it to attack an opponent's Digimon with higher DP, is my Digimon deleted after losing the battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, a Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e has to attack and delete an opponent's Digimon and survive the battle, but this card's effect deletes the opposing Digimon before the battle begins. As such, \uff1cPiercing\uff1e does not apply.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then attack an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards using a Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e take effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Dimension Scissor requires the Digimon to attack and delete an opponent's Digimon and survive the battle. This card's effect deletes the opposing Digimon before the battle begins, so the effect doesn't apply.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use [BT-112 Dimension Scissor], which allows 1 of my Digimon to unsuspend every time it deletes an opponent's Digimon. If I then use this card and attack an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards, can I unsuspend my Digimon using Dimension Scissor's effect after deleting the opponent's Digimon using this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The opposing Digimon isn't deleted by the effect granted by this card. If the opponent's Digimon has 1 or more digivolution cards at the time you declare the attack, it can't be targeted by the effect granted by this card, even if it loses all of its digivolution cards later.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then attack an opponent's Digimon with 1 digivolution card. If I use a [When Attacking] effect to trash the opposing Digimon's digivolution card, what happens?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck instead of the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by returning 1 of your Digimon to the hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to return my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] from the battle area to the hand, then return up to 2 of my opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon to their owners' hands?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your token is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be removed from the game instead of being returned to the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by returning 1 of your Digimon to the hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to return my token that was played as a Digimon from the battle area to the hand, then return up to 2 of my opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon to their owners' hands?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect already returned the Digimon to their hand. The effect doesn't activate again, and the Digimon you chose remains in your opponent's hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 7 cards in hand. I use this card to return their Digimon to their hand, resulting in them having 8 cards in hand. Does my opponent place that Digimon at the bottom of their deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When your security stack is empty, you gain 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card when my security stack is empty, do I gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It wasn't deleted, so [On Deletion] effects don't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to place a Digimon on top of my security stack. Does that Digimon's [On Deletion] effect(s) activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If your [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] is chosen as the target to place in the security stack, according to the rules it will be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck instead of the security stack.  A card isn't actually added to the security stack, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the security stack\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to place my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] on top of my security stack from the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If your token is chosen as the target to place in the security stack, according to the rules it's removed from the game instead of being placed in the security stack.  A card isn't actually added to the security stack, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the security stack\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to place my token that was played as a Digimon on top of my security stack from the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] or token that is treated as a Digimon in the battle area as the target for this card's effect, it isn't placed in the security stack. In such cases, do \"when a card is removed from the security stack\" effects trigger because a card wasn't added to the security stack even though it normally should have been added?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, both are possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when I have no Digimon to suspend an opponent's Digimon, or when my opponent has no Digimon to unsuspend my own Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Even if the Digimon's original DP is less than 16000, if it becomes 16000 or greater after getting +3000 DP from this card's effect, it gains \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give a Digimon +3000 DP. If that Digimon now has 16000 DP or more, does it gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Once the Digimon meets the conditions to gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, it keeps them until the end of your opponent's next turn, even if its DP is reduced to 15000 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give one of my Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e. If another effect reduces that Digimon to 15000 or less, does it lose \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. The Digimon must have 16000 DP at the time this card's effect is activated for it to gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to give a Digimon +3000 DP, but it still has less than 16000 DP. If I then use another DP-boosting effect to raise its DP to 16000 or more, does it gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, \uff1cReboot\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: BT4-110[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that reads, \"For each of your Digimon with [D-Brigade] in its type, add +1 to the maximum play cost of the Digimon you can choose with this effect.\" What does this mean?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Option cards go to the trash after their effects activate, so you still have 9 cards in your trash when the effect checks to see how many cards there are. You don't gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card when I have 9 cards in my trash, does this card become the 10th card in my trash, allowing me to gain 1 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT4-114": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect on [AncientGarurumon] itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect target \"BT4-114 Ancient Garurumon\" itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Up to two Digimons in total, either \"my Digimon with 'Garurumon' in its name\" or \"my Digimon with 'Hybrid Body' in its trait\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is activated by this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon this card is a digivolution card in counts towards the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card, does the Digimon it's part of count towards this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The Digimon is reduced to 0 DP and deleted before this card's inherited effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is a digivolution card in one of my Digimon. An opponent's effect causes that Digimon and another one of my Digimon to reach 0 DP simultaneously. Does this card's inherited effect give the Digimon it's a part of +2000 DP, protecting it from being deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can add one of the cards to your hand. As long as one of the Digimon cards revealed has either [Greymon], you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed with this card's effect don't include both a Digimon card with [Greymon] and a Digimon card with [Omnimon], am I allowed to add one of the cards to my hand, or do both cards have to be present?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It negates effects that read, \"reduce the memory cost of the digivolution by X,\" like <Digisorption> and [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]. Even if your opponent activates effects like these, it won't reduce the memory cost of their digivolutions. They have to pay the digivolution cost on the card in order to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"can't reduce digivolution costs\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I activate <Digisorption> on a card in my hand, can I reduce digivolution costs with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. [BT2-111 Beelzemon]'s effect doesn't reduce digivolution costs--it allows you to ignore digivolution requirements and digivolve for a specific memory cost, so you can still activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. Can I use effects like [BT2-111 Beelzemon]'s \"digivolve into this card in your hand for a memory cost of X, ignoring this card's digivolution requirements\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can add a card to your hand. As long as one of the Digimon cards revealed has either [Shoutmon] or \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 5 cards revealed with this card's effect don't include both a Digimon card with [Shoutmon] and a Digimon card with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, am I allowed to add one of the cards to my hand, or do both cards have to be present?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT5-019 ShoutmonDX] has [Shoutmon], and it also has \uff1cBlitz\uff1e. The effect is looking for \"1 Digimon card with [Shoutmon] and 1 Digimon card with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e,\" which means you can add both to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 5 cards revealed with this card's effect include 2 copies of [BT5-019 ShoutmonDX], can I add both copies to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if there was only one Digimon card with either \"Shoutmon\" in its name or a Digimon card with \"Advancement\", it will be added to your hand.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card require both a Digimon card with \"Shoutmon\" in its name and a Digimon card with \"Advance\" in its name among the 5 cards revealed to be added to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"BT5-019 Shoutmon DX\" contains \"Shoutmon\" in its name and has \"Advance\", so you can put both cards in your hand as \"a Digimon card containing \"Shoutmon\" in its name and a Digimon card with \"Advance\".[2]",
      "question": "Q: If there are two \"BT5-019 Shoutmon DX\" among the five cards revealed, can the effect of this card put both of those cards into my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One card with \"Shoutmon\" in its name and one card with \"Advancement\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a [Shoutmon] in your breeding area using this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve into this card from a [Shoutmon] in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. As long as the Digimon this card is a digivolution card in has \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, it gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, regardless of whether it attacks or not.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e to get \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my [Shoutmon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect requires you to be currently attacking with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon has an effect \"[When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e.\" but is not currently activating the effect of \uff1cBlitz\uff1e. Is it possible to attack my opponent's unsuspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect persists during the same turn, so the Digimon gains a total of +4000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this Digimon, and use its [When Attacking] effect to trash a red Digimon card with 3000 DP in my hand to give this Digimon +3000 DP. If I use an effect to attack again in the same turn and use this card's effect to trash a red Digimon with 1000 DP in my hand, does this Digimon gain a total of +4000 DP? Or does it go from getting +3000 DP to just +1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a level 5 Digimon into this card. Can I place a red level 4 or lower Digimon card or level 7 Digimon card from my hand at the top of this card's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It becomes a level 3 Digimon. The digivolution cards placed below it remain, and their inherited effects can still be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to place a level 3 Digimon card at the top of its digivolution cards. This Digimon is then targeted with a \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) effect, trashing this card. What happens to the Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) effect trashes this card, and the Digimon becomes a level 3 Digimon. \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) can't be used to trash any more cards once the Digimon it's targeting becomes level 3, and the effect ends. Any digivolution cards placed below it remain, and their inherited effects can still be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to place a level 3 Digimon card at the top of its digivolution cards. This Digimon is then targeted with a \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 2 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) effect. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first, after activating any [When Attacking] or [When a Digimon attacks] effects, you activate the other [When Digivolving] effect before the reaction timing occurs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has 2 [When Digivolving] effects. If \uff1cBlitz\uff1e resolves first, does the other [When Digivolving] effect resolve after the attack ends?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first, after activating any [When Attacking] or [When one of your Digimon attacks] effects, you activate the other [When Digivolving] effect before the counter timing occurs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has 2 [When Digivolving] effects. If \uff1cBlitz\uff1e resolves first, does the other [When Digivolving] effect resolve after the attack ends?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. [BT5-017 ZeigGreymon]'s inherited effect allows you to attack an opponent's unsuspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to place [BT5-017 ZeigGreymon] at the top of its digivolution cards. If I then activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and attack, can I use [BT5-017 ZeigGreymon]'s inherited effect to attack an opponent's unsuspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When a Lv.5 Digimon digivolved into this Digimon, can I put a red Lv.4 or lower or Lv.7 Digimon card from my hand on top of the digivolved card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be a Lv.3 Digimon. The digivolution card that was under it will remain stacked, and the digivolution card can still activate the inherited effect.[2]",
      "question": "Q: With this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect, I placed a Lv.3 Digimon card on top of the first Digivolution card. If this Digimon then receives the <De-Digivolve 1> effect and this card is trashed, what happens to the Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \u226aThe effect of <De-Digivolve> causes this card to be trashed and become a Lv.3 Digimon. \u226aSince <De-Digivolve 3> cannot be further trashed, <De-Digivolve> ends there. The digivolution card remains stacked and the inherited effect can be activated.[2]",
      "question": "Q: With this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect, I placed a Lv.3 Digimon card on top of the first Digivolution card. After that, when this Digimon receives the <De-Digivolve 2> effect, how is it handled?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you activate the [When Attacking] effect or the [When Digivolving] effect [When your Digimon attacks] first, the other [When Digivolved] effect will be activated before the Counter timing.[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card has two [When Digivolving] effects. If I resolve [When Attacking] first, do I resolve the other [When Digivolved] effect after finishing the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution card effect of \"BT5-017 ZeigGreymon\" can attack Digimon in active state.[2]",
      "question": "Q: With the [When Digivolving] effect of this card, I put \"BT5-017 ZeigGreymon\" on the top of the digivolution card. After that, if I activate the [Advance] effect and attack, can I attack the opponent's Digimon in the active state with the digivolution source effect of \"BT5-017 ZeigGreymon\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can add one of the cards to your hand. As long as one of the Digimon cards revealed has either [Garurumon], you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed with this card's effect don't include both a Digimon card with [Garurumon] and a Digimon card with [Omnimon], am I allowed to add one of the cards to my hand, or do both cards have to be present?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It negates effects that read, \"reduce the memory cost of the digivolution by X,\" like <Digisorption> and [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]. Even if your opponent activates effects like these, it won't reduce the memory cost of their digivolutions. They have to pay the digivolution cost on the card in order to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"can't reduce digivolution costs\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I activate <Digisorption> on a card in my hand, will I be able to reduce digivolution costs with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. [BT2-111 Beelzemon]'s effect doesn't reduce digivolution costs--it allows you to ignore digivolution requirements and digivolve for a specific memory cost, so you can still activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. Can I use effects like [BT2-111 Beelzemon]'s \"digivolve into this card in your hand for a memory cost of X, ignoring this card's digivolution requirements\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When you return a Digimon to its owner's hand, the game doesn't treat the digivolution cards as being trashed, so you don't gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's inherited effect to return an opponent's Digimon to its owner's hand, can I gain 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you trash the digivolution cards of 2 of your opponent's Digimon at the same time, you can only use this effect to gain 1 memory per turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's inherited effect to trash the digivolution cards of 2 of my opponent's Digimon at the same time, can I gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Battle occurs as normal. This card's effect essentially means \"this Digimon can't be chosen as a target of attack by your opponent,\" which means that if you block with this Digimon, the target of attack can still be switched to this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon gains \uff1cBlocker\uff1e by an effect. If I block with this Digimon in response to an opponent's attack, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. Can I use [BT4-090 Chaosmon]'s [When Digivolving] effect to attack it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. If your opponent uses [Blastmon]'s effect to switch the target of attack, a battle occurs as if this Digimon was attacked normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon in play, unsuspended, when my opponent attacks with [BT4-075 Blastmon]. Can [Blastmon]'s effect be used to switch the target of attack to this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, that Digimon does not have [On Deletion].",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has [On Deletion] has an inherited effect, can this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect target it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that Digimon was given [On Deletion] while in the battle area.",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon was given [On Deletion] from its digivolution card's inherited effect, can this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect target it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that Digimon was given [On Deletion] while in the battle area.",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon was given [On Deletion] from an Option card's effect, can this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect target it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If this card's [When Attacking] effect results in an opponent's Digimon having no digivolution cards, this card gains \uff1cJamming\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this Digimon when my opponent has no Digimon in play with no digivolution cards. I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to trash the digivolution cards of an opponent's Digimon. If this results in my opponent having a Digimon card with no digivolution cards in play, can I activate \uff1cJamming\uff1e on the same attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You've already declared the attack, so even if your attacking Digimon loses its digivolution card, [Hexeblaumon]'s effect doesn't end the attack midway.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. I attack my opponent with a Digimon that has \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, and flip over [BT1-101 Howling Crusher] from their security stack. If its [Security] effect results in the attacking Digimon having no digivolution cards, does the attack end immediately?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's [When Attacking] effect has already finished resolving. Even if a Digimon with no digivolution cards enters play afterwards, this card doesn't gain \uff1cJamming\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon, which has \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, and flip over a Digimon card with a [Security] effect during the first security check. If this results in a Digimon with no digivolution cards entering my opponent's battle area, does this Digimon gain \uff1cJamming\uff1e starting with the next security check?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It negates effects that read, \"reduce the memory cost of the digivolution by X,\" like <Digisorption> and [BT3-103 Hidden Potential Discovered!]. Even if your opponent activates effects like these, it won't reduce the memory cost of their digivolutions. They have to pay the digivolution cost on the card in order to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"can't reduce digivolution costs\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I activate <Digisorption> on a card in my hand, will I be able to reduce digivolution costs with it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. [BT2-111 Beelzemon]'s effect doesn't reduce digivolution costs--it allows you to ignore digivolution requirements and digivolve for a specific memory cost, so you can still activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. Can I use effects like [BT2-111 Beelzemon]'s \"digivolve into this card in your hand for a memory cost of X, ignoring this card's digivolution requirements\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can have up to two yellow Digimon cards, one with \"Warrior type\" in its trait and the other with \"Holy Knight type\" in its trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. This Digimon counts toward this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect count this Digimon itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The effect only targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 Digimon in play. Can I use this card's effect to give -1000 DP each to 2 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The [On Play] effect has already finished activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After playing this Digimon, I play another Digimon during the same turn. Since I now have more Digimon in play, can I give my opponent's Digimon an additional -1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means you can look at all of the cards in your security stack, without revealing them to your opponent. When you choose a card in your security stack to add to your hand, reveal it to your opponent. The other cards should remain hidden.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"Look at your security stack\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: <Security +1 (Deck)> doesn't occur. Shuffle your security stack, and the effect ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if there are no cards in my security stack that can be added to my hand with this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if a Security Digimon is reduced to 0 DP, it still battles with the Digimon performing the security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I flip over an opponent's Security Digimon during a security check, and this card's inherited effect reduces its DP to 0. Is the Digimon deleted on the spot, without a battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect activates normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's inherited effect reduces a Security Digimon's DP to 0, but it has a [Security] effect. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It's no longer a Security Digimon once it enters play, so it doesn't have its DP reduced by this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Security Digimon has its DP reduced by this card's inherited effect and is later played due to its [Security] effect, does it still have its DP reduced when it enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if a Security Digimon is reduced to 0 DP, it still battles with the Digimon performing the security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I flip over an opponent's Security Digimon during a security check, and this card's inherited effect reduces its DP to 0. Is the Digimon deleted on the spot, without a battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect activates normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's inherited effect reduces a Security Digimon's DP to 0, but it has a [Security] effect. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It's no longer a Security Digimon once it enters play, so it doesn't have its DP reduced by this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Security Digimon has its DP reduced by this card's inherited effect. If that Security Digimon is later played by its [Security] effect, does it still have its DP reduced when it enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates during the breeding phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent moves a Digimon from their breeding area to their battle area during the breeding phase. Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if a Security Digimon is reduced to 0 DP, it still battles with the Digimon performing the security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During a security check, my opponent's Security Digimon has its DP reduced to 0 by this card's [Your Turn] effect. Is the Security Digimon deleted on the spot, without a battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect activates normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [Your Turn] effect reduces a Security Digimon's DP to 0, but it has a [Security] effect. What happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It's no longer a Security Digimon once it enters play, so it doesn't have its DP reduced by this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Security Digimon has its DP reduced by this card's [Your Turn] effect. If that Security Digimon is later played by its [Security] effect, does it still have its DP reduced when it enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A \"Yellow Lv.3 Digimon card\" or a \"Yellow Digimon card with \"Warrior type\" in its trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [On Play] effect [When Attacking]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is being deleted. Can I use this card's effect to place it at the bottom of 1 of my green Digimon's digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The [On Deletion] effect is activated while treated as [Sukamon], but the name changing effect is lost when the card is deleted and placed in the trash, so you can treat this card as a [Palmon] card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card that was targeted by [BT11-043 KingSukamon]'s effect and had its name changed to [Sukamon] is deleted. If I have no other [Palmon] in the trash, can I place this same card at the bottom of the digivolution cards of one of my green Digimon from the trash with it's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve [BT5-056 Rafflesimon] on top of another [BT5-056 Rafflesimon]. Can I use the [Once Per Turn] effect of the new Rafflesimon if the old Rafflesimon used it before?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect is applied as a Global Effect. If it satisfies the condition afterwards, it gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect, one of my Digimon without \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e becomes a Digimon with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, does that Digimon gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect is applied as a Global Effect. So if it no longer satisfies the condition then it no longer has the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect, one of my Digimon with \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e becomes a Digimon without \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e, does that Digimon keep the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as it has already resolved and applied a Global effect, the Global effect continues applying even after Rosemon leaves the battle area.",
      "question": "Q: If after using this card's \uff1cDigi-Burst\uff1e effect, this card leaves the battle area does the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e continue being applied?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can add a card to your hand. As long as one of the cards revealed is either a Digimon card with [Unidentified] in its type or an [Arata Sanada] card, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 5 cards revealed with this card's effect don't include both a Digimon card with [Unidentified] in its type and an [Arata Sanada] card, am I allowed to add one of the cards to my hand, or do both cards have to be present?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if there was only either a Digimon card with \"race unknown\" in its trait or \"Arata Sanada\", it will be added to your hand.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card require both a Digimon card with \"race unknown\" in its trait and \"Arata Sanada\" among the 5 cards revealed to be added to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One Digimon card with the trait \"race unknown\" and one card with the name \"Arata Sanada\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is added to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: After checking the card, place it back on top of your deck face down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [On Play] effect to check the top card of my deck. What happens to that card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. The Digimon loses \uff1cRush\uff1e when its name changes, so it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon has \uff1cRush\uff1e thanks to this card's inherited effect. If that Digimon digivolves into a Digimon with a different name, can that Digimon attack the same turn it entered play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon ends, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a [Keramon] in your breeding area using this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve into this card from a [Keramon] in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens are special cards that some effects put into play to represent Digimon or Tamers. This card's effect, for example, plays a token that's treated as a Digimon named [Diaboromon]. For a more detailed explanation of how tokens work, check the official rule manual.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What's a token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my [Keramon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"If no Digimon was deleted by this effect\" refers to times where, when <Digi-Burst> is activated, your opponent doesn't have a Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less in play, or an effect makes it so that there are no Digimon you can delete. Essentially, it means there was no Digimon in play that could be deleted by \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's <Digi-Burst> effect reads, \"Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less. If no Digimon was deleted by this effect...\" How does this effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you use this card's <Digi-Burst> and your opponent has a Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less, you must target that Digimon when you activate the effect. If a valid target exists, you must choose it as part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less in play, can I activate this card's <Digi-Burst> and choose not to delete my opponent's Digimon in order to trash the top card of their security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digimon with play costs of 6 or less are valid targets. If you choose it, the \"can't be deleted by your opponent's effects\" will prevent it from being deleted, allowing you to trash the top card of your opponent's security stack instead.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 2 Digimon in play with play costs of 6 or less. One of them has an effect that reads, \"This Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent's effects,\" while the other does not. If I activate this card's <Digi-Burst>, can I choose the Digimon that \"can't be deleted by your opponent's effects\" in order to trash the top card of my opponent's security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When a Digimon is deleted at 0 DP, it's deleted by the game rules, not a card effect, so the game doesn't treat it as if it was deleted by an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon's DP is reduced to 0 by an opponent's effect. Does this card's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect can't be used to return a level 3 Digimon card with an [On Deletion] inherited effect from your trash to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect be used to return a level 3 Digimon card with an [On Deletion] inherited effect from my trash to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have another Digimon in play, can I choose any one of this card's three effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The owner of the card gets to decide the order they activate in.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't have another Digimon in play, what order do I activate this card's three effects in?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A token is a special card played from an effect that is treated as a Digimon or Tamer. This card's effect can play tokens treated as Digimon named \"Diaboromon.\" For detailed rules pertaining to tokens, check the rule manual.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What's a token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do Diaboromon tokens meet the white color requirement?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When playing this card, can I delete one of my [Diaboromon] tokens to reduce its play cost by 12?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Depends on the timing. It can't be activated at the [When Digivolving] timing due to this card's effect. It can be activated at the [When Attacking] timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [All Turns] effect prevent the activation of the [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect of [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If you activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first, you declare the attack and suspend the Digimon at that point in time. If you then activate the \"Unsuspend this Digimon\" effect, you can unsuspend this Digimon itself.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card digivolves, can I activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e first to attack, then use the \"Unsuspend this Digimon\" effect to unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's [All Turns] effect prevents other effects from deleting this Digimon or returning it to its owner's hand or deck, so it isn't treated as being deleted by the game rules.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon is deleted, I activate this card's [All Turns] effect to have this Digimon remain in the battle area. Does this cause \"When another Digimon is deleted\" effects to activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Any cards in your trash that are black and/or purple Digimon cards with play costs of 8 or less can be returned to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This [When Digivolving] effect returns up to 2 black and/or purple Digimon cards with play costs of 8 or less from my trash. Can I return cards that weren't trashed using this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, a Digimon card with a play cost of 8 or less can be played with a black or purple Digimon card that was originally in the trash.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect play 2 black or purple Digimon cards of play cost 8 or less in my trash without paying the cost, even if they are not the cards I discarded with this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can have up to two \"Black Digimon cards with a play cost of 8 or less\" or \"Purple Digimon cards with a play cost of 8 or less\" in total.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect apply even if my opponent only has 1 Digimon with no digivolution cards and the rest of their Digimon have digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect apply if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Your opponent has to have a Digimon in their battle area for it to activate.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect apply when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon in their battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is a \"Do <X> to <Y> effect. As such, it follows the rules detailed in the Detailed Rules. (Found in Effect Resolution/Related Information#Costs)",
      "question": "Q: When my blue Digimon attacks, can I suspend this Tamer even if my opponent has no Digimon in the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. [Start of Your Turn] effects activate before your unsuspend phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's suspended Digimon unsuspends during my unsuspend phase using \uff1cReboot\uff1e. Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \"you may,\" so you can choose not to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with a green level 5 Digimon, and use this card's [Your Turn] effect to reveal a green level 6 Digimon card. Do I have to digivolve into that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you get to choose which card to digivolve into.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [Your Turn] effect revealed 2 or more green level 6 Digimon. Can I choose which card to digivolve into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with a green level 5 Digimon, and use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve it. Do I get to draw a bonus card from digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [Your Turn] effect revealed a non-green level 6 Digimon card. Can I digivolve into that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"You can choose to activate this card's effect twice off a single attack, but you can't activate both effects simultaneously. Instead, you activate each Tamer's effect one at a time. First, activate the first Tamer's effect, reveal 3 cards from your deck, and choose whether or not to digivolve the attacking Digimon. From there, you can decide whether or not to activate the second Tamer's effect. Furthermore, if you digivolve into a card revealed from the first Tamer's effect, the card revealed from the second Tamer's effect must be a green level 6 card that can digivolve from a level 6 Digimon. (i.e. [BT5-056 Rafflesimon])\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this Tamer in play, and attack with a green level 5 Digimon. Can I suspend both Tamers, reveal 6 cards from my deck, and choose a card to digivolve into from among them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It activates immediately after you draw the bonus card for digivolving. Even if there are other [When Attacking] or \"When one of your Digimon attacks\" effects, the [When Digivolving] effect activates first as a newly triggered effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve into a level 6 Digimon with a [When Digivolving] effect, when does that effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The window for activating [When Attacking] effects has already passed, so the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve into a level 6 Digimon with a [When Attacking] effect, does that effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens are special cards that some effects put into play to represent Digimon or Tamers. This card's effect, for example, plays a token that's treated as a Digimon named [Diaboromon]. For a more detailed explanation of how tokens work, check the official rule manual.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What's a token?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also give \"[When Attacking] Lose 1 memory\" to my level 3 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Each effect activates separately, resulting in you losing a total of 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 copies of this Tamer in play and attack with a level 3 Digimon, do I lose 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving Digimon in your breeding area doesn't trigger the effect that reduces digivolution cost by 1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon in my breeding area into a Digimon card with [Greymon]/[Garurumon]/[Omnimon]\u00a0in its name. Can I use this Tamer's effect to reduce the digivolution cost by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, each copy of this Tamer may be be suspended to reduce the digivolution cost by 1 each.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the second effect of this Tamer stack if there are multiple copies in play in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [ST5-04 ToyAgumon] is not named [Agumon]/[Gabumon]. The effect to play a Digimon does not have \"in its name\" in the card text.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play [ToyAgumon]/[Agumon Expert] with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card is meant to have a [Your Turn] effect.[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card's printing in BT-05: Booster Battle Of Omni has [Main] as its effect and its RB-01: Reboot Booster Rising Wind printing uses [Your Turn]. Which version is correct?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer card. Can I use this card's effect to place a red level 4 or lower Digimon card from my hand at the bottom of one of my Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It remains stacked on top of the digivolution cards, but since it's no longer a Digimon, it can no longer activate inherited effects. If it digivolves back into a Digimon, it will be able to use inherited effects again.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to place a Digimon card under one of my Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer card. If \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) causes that card to become a Tamer card again, what happens to the digivolution cards under it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When choosing which Digimon to trash a digivolution card from and which Digimon to return to its owner's deck with this card's effect, can I choose different cards for each one?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 Digimon in play, can I activate this card's effect to give an opponent's Digimon -3000 DP twice, for a total of -6000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. There are no security cards to trash, but this doesn't allow you to win the game.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a level 7 Digimon in play and I use this card when my opponent's security stack is empty, do I win the game?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's possible to attack your opponent's Digimon, which means you can perform checks off of \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates this card's [Security] effect. If I then attack with a Digimon that has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e and delete an opponent's Digimon in battle, do I check my opponent's security cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent doesn't have a Digimon I can target with \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 2 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) in play. Can I still use this card to create a [Diaboromon] token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I only have a [Diaboromon] token in my battle area. Can I use this card to create a new [Diaboromon] token?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent doesn't have a Digimon I can target with \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 3 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) in play. Can I still use this card to delete all of my opponent's Digimon with play costs of 3 or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Your purple Digimon has already been deleted when [ChaosGallantmon] enters play, so it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to play a card like [BT5-081 ChaosGallantmon], which has an effect that reads, \"delete 1 of your other Digimon to...\" Does deleting the purple Digimon for this card's effect cause the \"delete 1 of your other Digimon\" effect to activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As long as your opponent has either an unsuspended level 4 or level 5 in Digimon in play, you can activate this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect if my opponent doesn't have both an unsuspended level 4 and level 5 Digimon in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It is activated even when only one of the opponent's Digimon is in active state, either Lv.4 or Lv.5.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have to have both Lv.4 and Lv.5 opponent's Digimon in active state for it to be effective?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One Digimon of the opponent in the active state of Lv.4 and one Digimon of the opponent in the active state of Lv.5.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which card is deleted by the [Main] effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, can I reduce the digivolution cost of my level 6 Digimon digivolving to level 7 when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect delete all of my Digimon and Tamers, too?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't digivolve from a Digimon in your breeding area that has [Omnimon] using this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve into this card from a Digimon in my breeding area that has [Omnimon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The target of attack is no longer in play, so the attack ends without a battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon with this Digimon, and use its [When Attacking] effect to delete the opposing Digimon. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You didn't delete the opponent's Digimon in battle, so \uff1cPiercing\uff1e doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon with this Digimon, and use its [When Attacking] effect to delete the opposing Digimon. If this Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e, can I check the opponent's security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do, the blocking Digimon will battle this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks one of my Digimon with this Digimon, using its [When Attacking] effect to delete my Digimon. Can I use another Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect is activated at counter timing, which means it only activates after the [When Attacking] effect has finished activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon attacks. Can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect be used to to end the attack before the attacking Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activates?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The [On Deletion] effect activates immediately after the deletion occurs, so it activates before this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon used a [When Attacking] effect to delete one of my Digimon with an [On Deletion] effect. If I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to end the attack, does the [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon. After activating my [BT1-082 Rosemon]'s effect, can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to end the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The battle has already concluded, which means the counter timing window for activating the effect has passed, so you can't activate this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon. After comparing DP in battle, can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to end the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [When Attacking] effects will activate as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect, will the game treat the attack as if it never occurred?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my Digimon with [Omnimon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT5-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If this card is flipped over as a Security Digimon, it's played in its owner's battle area without battling the attacking Digimon. Even if the attacking Digimon has lower DP than this card, no battle occurs, and the attacking Digimon is not deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"without battling\" in this card's [Security] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After playing this Digimon, the remaining checks are performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check. If the attacking Digimon has extra security checks remaining from <Security Attack +>, what happens?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect be used to delete a Digimon that digivolved from a Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if the Digimon is blocked, if you declared an attack against your opponent, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.  Trash all of the digivolution cards of those Digimon\"\" is an explanation of what happens to the digivolution cards of the Digimon when it returns to their hand. It doesn't count as trashing digivolution for the purposes of this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate an effect that reads \"Return 1 of your opponent's Digimon to their hand. Trash all of the digivolution cards of that Digimon\" to return an opponent's Digimon to their hand. When your opponent's digivolution cards are trashed as a result, can you activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you declared an attack against your opponent, this card's effect doesn't activate, even if they use another Digimon to block it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate an effect that reads \u201c\uff1cDraw 1\uff1e (Draw 1 card from your deck.) Then, trash 1 card in your hand.\u201d Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effects on both Digimon activate, so you gain 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this Digimon in my battle area. If I play a Tamer with [Tai Kamiya], can I activate the effects on both Digimon to gain a total of 2 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The turn doesn\u2019t switch over until the attack completely finishes resolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer with [Tai Kamiya] from my security using its security effect. If this Digimon\u2019s effect causes the memory gauge to move to 1 or greater on my side, does it immediately become my turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As long as a Digimon with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e is in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e will activate even if you make a normal, non-\uff1cBlitz\uff1e attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I make a normal, non-\uff1cBlitz\uff1e attack with this Digimon. Can I use this card\u2019s inherited effect to draw a card with \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 2 copies of the same card with [Huckmon], [Jesmon], or [Sistermon] from the top of my deck. Can I add both copies to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you have multiple Digimon with [Sistermon] in play, you can only use this Digimon\u2019s effect to delete 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 Digimon with [Sistermon] in play, can I use this card\u2019s effect to delete 2 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon with 5000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. During your turn, this Digimon is treated as both a red and black Digimon, so it can digivolve into a Digimon with black digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon digivolve into a Digimon with \u201cBlack/Level 5\u201d digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [Your Turn] effects don't activate from breeding areas, so the card isn't treated as a black card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a black Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a black Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] effect to play a Digimon card with [Sistermon]. Does this Digimon\u2019s [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose not to use an Option card. If you don\u2019t use one, you can delete 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves, can I intentionally choose not to use a 7-cost Option card in my hand to delete 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon with 4000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect to delete 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon with 13000 DP or less, can I use this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect to trash the top card of my opponent\u2019s security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effects on both Digimon activate, so you gain 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this Digimon in my battle area. If I play a Tamer with [Matt Ishida], can I activate the effects on both Digimon to gain a total of 2 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The turn doesn\u2019t switch over until the attack completely finishes resolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer with [Matt Ishida] from my security using its security effect. If this Digimon\u2019s effect causes the memory gauge to move to 1 or greater on my side, does it immediately become my turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when my opponent has no Digimon in play in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't use Option/Digimon card effects to gain memory, but you can still lose memory if a card effect specifies as such. At the end of the turn, you\u2019ll lose memory as specified by each effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. What happens if an effect is activated that causes you to gain memory on activation and lose memory at end of turn? (i.e. [BT1-090 Gravity Crush], [BT1-021 MetalGreymon], [BT1-040 WereGarurumon], [BT1-058 Chirinmon], [BT1-075 Digitamamon], etc.)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon prevents you from gaining memory from security effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. Can I gain memory from the security effect of [ST2-13 Hammer Spark]?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s effect activate when my opponent has no Digimon in play in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when my opponent has no Digimon in play in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you attack with a Digimon, your opponent's Digimon can\u2019t change the target of attack by blocking.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \u201cYour Digimon can't be blocked by your opponent's Digimon this turn.\u201d How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from its effect and updates its security attack value. You re-calculate its security attack and continue checking security based on its new security attack. (For more information see Attack Resolution)",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has no Digimon in play but reveals a [ST8-06 Coredramon] from this card's security check, does this card check another Security card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It ends when the current turn ends.",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Deletion] effect is activated on my opponent's turn, when does the \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e end?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Both effects activate, so you can draw a total of 2 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 Digimon with this card in their digivolution cards in my battle area, and a card is removed from my security stack. Do the inherited effects on both Digimon activate, activating \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e twice and drawing me 2 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card\u2019s [On Play] effect allows you to trash any number of cards, from zero cards, up to however many cards you need to trash for you to have 3 cards left in your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I play this card, does its [On Play] effect force me to trash cards from my security stack until there are 3 cards left?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can\u2019t trash any security cards, so the effect does nothing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect work if I have 3 or fewer cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 5 cards in my security stack. Can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to only trash 1 security card and gain 1 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when a security card is removed from my security stack by one of my own effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when a security card is removed from my security stack by one of my own effects?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must trash a card from your security stack in order to have one of your opponent\u2019s Digimon get -5000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s effect when my security stack is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect reads \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether or not to trash the top card of your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect force me to trash the top card of my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must trash a card from your security stack in order to activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect when my security stack is empty?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to trash a card from my security stack. If there are 3 or fewer cards left in my security stack, does this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Fundamentally, this is possible. However, the effects don\u2019t activate simultaneously, but one at a time in order. Once <Recovery> results in you having 4 cards in your security stack, any remaining copies of the effect don't activate.  Any [BT6-044 Dynasmon] whose effects don\u2019t activate can still be activated later in the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 or more copies of this Digimon in play. My opponent attacks with a Digimon, removing a card from my security stack. Do all of the effects on copies of this Digimon activate simultaneously, activating <Recovery +1 (Deck)> for each one?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Security] effect activates first.   After the [Security] effect and any effects triggered by its activation have finished activating, this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent\u2019s Digimon performs a security check, flipping over a card with a [Security] effect. Which activates first: This card\u2019s [All Turns] effect, or the [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. As long as either a card with [Menoa Bellucci] or a Digimon card with [Eosmon] are among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to reveal 5 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Menoa Bellucci] or a Digimon card with [Eosmon], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a tamer card as a digivolution card, does the [Security] effect of that tamer card become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve on top of a Level 3 Digimon that meets its requirements instead of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.   However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a tamer card as a digivolution card, does the [Security] effect of that tamer card become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card digivolve on top of a Level 3 Digimon that meets its requirements instead of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to make a tamer card into a digivolution card, is that card affected by effects that say \"trash digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, Eldradimon's effect prevents the reduction of DP. But it does not prevent its original DP from being set to another number.",
      "question": "Q: Can [BT1-105 Blast Fire] to set the DP of Eldradimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the new Digimon has -3000 DP.",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses [BT3-101 Bifrost] and targets this card. Eldradimon is then hit by a \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e. Does the new Digimon have the decreased DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the new Digimon has -3000 DP.",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses [BT3-101 Bifrost] and targets this card. I digivolve Eldradimon into a new Digimon. Does the new Digimon have the decreased DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates at the end of the battle, regardless of outcome.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Security] effect activate even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon\u2019s [Security] effect activates after the battle with the attacking Digimon ends, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Does this Digimon\u2019s effect activate first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. As long as either a Digimon card with [Three Musketeers] in its type or a 7-cost Option card are among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to reveal 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a Digimon card with [Three Musketeers] in its type or a 7-cost Option card, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this Digimon in the battle area into a card with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. During your turn, this Digimon is treated as both a red and black Digimon, so it can digivolve into a Digimon with black digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon digivolve into a Digimon with \u201cRed/Level 5\u201d digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [Your Turn] effects don't activate from breeding areas, so the card isn't treated as a red card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a red Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a red Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As soon as your opponent no longer has an unsuspended Digimon in play, your attacking Digimon loses \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent only has 1 unsuspended Digimon in play, and I attack with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards. When my opponent blocks and suspends their unsuspended Digimon, does my attacking Digimon immediately lose \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect reads \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether or not to use the Option card.  If you don\u2019t use it, you delete 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon with a play cost of 4 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to reveal cards from the top of my deck. If I reveal a 7-cost Option card, do I have to use it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Reveal as many cards from your deck as you can, then perform the rest of the effect as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 or fewer cards in my deck, does this Digimon\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect deletes your opponent\u2019s Digimon with the lowest play cost. If multiple Digimon are tied for lowest, all of them are deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \u201cDelete all of your opponent's Digimon with the lowest play cost\u201d mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As soon as your opponent no longer has an unsuspended Digimon in play, your attacking Digimon loses \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent only has 1 unsuspended Digimon in play, and I attack with this Digimon. When my opponent blocks and suspends their unsuspended Digimon, does my attacking Digimon immediately lose \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card\u2019s effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect reads \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether or not to trash the card.  If you don't trash a card, you don\u2019t get to return a Digimon card with [Seven Great Demon Lords] or [Three Musketeers] in its type from your trash to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I play this card, do I have to trash 1 card in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must trash a card in your hand in order to activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s effect when my hand is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the Digimon does not have its [Your Turn] effect at the time of trashing a card in the hand.",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card into a Level 5 Digimon while under the effects of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%]. Does the [Your Turn] effect of the Digimon on top of this card activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card\u2019s [On Play] effect can only be used to place cards whose names match either [Kinkakumon] or [Ginkakumon] exactly, therefore you can't place [Ginkakumon Promote] in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to place a [Ginkakumon Promote] from my trash in this card\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"You may place...\" means that you can choose if you want to place them as digivolution cards or not. However, if you choose to place, you must place as many digivolution cards as possible. So, if you have both [Kinkakumon] and [Ginkakumon], you can't choose to place only one of them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have both [Kinkakumon] and [Ginkakumon] in my trash, does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect force me to place both cards in this card\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Effects don't activate from breeding areas, so the card isn't treated as a black card. You can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a black Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my breeding area. Can I digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a black Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must trash a card in your hand in order to activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s effect when my hand is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they both trigger at the same time. So you can choose which effect to activate first.",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve my Level 5 Purple Digimon into [BT4-087 Anubismon] while under the effects of [EX1-071 Win Rate 60%], and trash this card from the hand. Can I use the [When Digivolving] effect of [BT4-087 Anubismon] before the \"when this card is trashed from your hand\" effect of SkullGreymon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The [On Deletion] effect activates after the card moves to your trash, meeting the requirement for you to have 10 cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 9 cards in my trash when this Digimon is deleted. If this results in my having 10 cards in my trash, does this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If possible, you must trash 1 card in your hand for this card\u2019s effect. \u201cThen, you may play 1 purple Level 4 or lower Digimon card from your trash without paying its memory cost\u201d is phrased \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether or not to play a card using the effect.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect force me to trash 1 card in my hand when this card digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to trash a purple Level 4 or lower Digimon card in my hand, then play it with this effect? "
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to trash a card in my hand. Does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can\u2019t trash a card in your hand, but since you don\u2019t need to trash a card to activate the second part of the effect, you can still play a purple Level 4 or lower Digimon card from your trash without paying its memory cost.",
      "question": "Q: When happens when this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activates while my hand is empty?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you choose not to play a Tamer, your opponent can still use this card\u2019s effect to play a Tamer of their own.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don\u2019t play a Tamer using this card\u2019s [On Play] effect, does that prevent my opponent from playing a Tamer card, as well?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the name [Sistermon Noir] and the [Virus]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"Also treated as Name: [Sistermon Noir] and Trait: [Virus]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Also treated as Name: [Sistermon Noir] and Trait: [Virus]\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a specific rule that allows you to include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"You can include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck\" has been changed to \"(Rule) You can include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If you do, trash as many cards from your security stack as you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I only have 1 or fewer cards left in my security stack. Can I activate this card\u2019s [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card\u2019s [Main] effect only affects cards whose names are [Agumon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [Main] effect on cards with [Agumon] in their name? (For example, [Agumon Expert], [ToyAgumon], etc.)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you had 1 or more cards in your security stack at the time the effect finished activating, [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] will be deleted at the end of the turn, regardless of how many cards are in your security stack at that time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated this card\u2019s [Main] effect to digivolve into [Agumon - Bond of Bravery]. I had 1 or more cards in my security stack at the time of activation, but another effect causes my security stack to become empty later that same turn. Do I get to keep [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] in play at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The first copy\u2019s effect was used to digivolve into [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] while your security stack had 1 or more cards in it, so [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] will be deleted at the end of the turn.  The second copy\u2019s effect was used to digivolve into [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] while your security stack was empty, so [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] stays in play at the end of the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this card in play. I use the first copy\u2019s [Main] effect to digivolve a Digimon into an [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] while there are 1 or more cards in my security stack. I use the second copy\u2019s [Main] effect to digivolve a different Digimon into [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] while my security stack is empty.    What happens to each [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] at the end of the turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If you do, trash as many cards from your security stack as you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I only have 1 or fewer cards left in my security stack. Can I activate this card\u2019s [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you had 1 or more cards in your security stack at the time the effect finished activating, [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] will be deleted at the end of the turn, regardless of how many cards are in your security stack at that time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated this card\u2019s [Main] effect to digivolve into [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship]. I had 1 or more cards in my security stack at the time of activation, but another effect causes my security stack to become empty later that same turn. Do I get to keep [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] in play at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The first copy\u2019s effect was used to digivolve into [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] while your security stack had 1 or more cards in it, so [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] will be deleted at the end of the turn.  The second copy\u2019s effect was used to digivolve into [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] while your security stack was empty, so [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] stays in play at the end of the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"I have 2 copies of this card in play. I use the first copy\u2019s [Main] effect to digivolve a Digimon into a [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] while there are 1 or more cards in my security stack. I use the second copy\u2019s [Main] effect to digivolve a different Digimon into [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] while my security stack is empty.    What happens to each [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] at the end of the turn?\""
    }
  ],
  "BT6-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect only activates \u201cif you have fewer security cards than your opponent,\u201d so if you and your opponent both have the same number of security cards, it won\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: The number of cards in my security stack is equal to the number of cards in my opponent\u2019s security stack. Does this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect allow me to gain 2 memory if my opponent has no Digimon in play in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have a Digimon with [Three Musketeers] in its type in play in your battle area, you can use this Option card even if you don\u2019t have a red Digimon or Tamer in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"If you have a Digimon with [Three Musketeers] in its type in play, you may use this Option card without meeting its color requirements.\u201d How does this effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect deletes your opponent\u2019s Digimon with the lowest DP. If multiple Digimon are tied for lowest, all of them are deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \u201call of your opponent's Digimon with the lowest DP\u201d mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card\u2019s effect is already activated, so the affected Digimon can\u2019t attack or block until the effect ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to prevent one of my opponent\u2019s Digimon with no digivolution cards from attacking or blocking. If that Digimon later gains a digivolution card, can it attack and block?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to trash 2 digivolution cards from the bottom of 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon. For the part of this card\u2019s effect that reads \u201c1 of your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards can't attack or block until the end of your opponent's next turn,\u201d can I choose a different Digimon with no digivolution cards other than the one I trashed digivolution cards from using the first part of this card\u2019s effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 3 Digimon in play. Can I choose to put a Level 6 or higher Digimon on the bottom of my opponent's deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-099": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The second half of the effect still occurs even if you don\u2019t have a security card to trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card if I have 0 cards left in my security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You're revealing cards from your deck, which means they\u2019re public information until you choose one to place face down on top of your security stack. You must show the card you place in your security stack to your opponent first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card\u2019s effect to place a card on top of my security stack, do I need to show it to my opponent?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Reveal as many cards from your deck as you can, then perform the rest of the effect as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card if I have 1 or fewer cards left in my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent loses 2 memory, which means you gain 2 memory.  If you use this card to give \u201c[On Deletion] Lose 2 memory\u201d to an opponent\u2019s Digimon, you gain 2 memory when that Digimon is deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to give \u201c[On Deletion] Lose 2 memory.\u201d to an opponent\u2019s Digimon. What happens when that Digimon is deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have a Digimon with [Three Musketeers] in its type in play in your battle area, you can use this Option card even if you don\u2019t have a black Digimon or Tamer in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"If you have a Digimon with [Three Musketeers] in its type in play, you may use this Option card without meeting its color requirements.\u201d How does this effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Both your and your opponent delete all Digimon with play costs of 7 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s effect also delete all of my Digimon with play costs of 7 or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect deletes your opponent\u2019s Digimon with the highest play cost. If multiple Digimon are tied for highest, all of them are deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \u201call of your opponent's Digimon with the highest play cost\u201d mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The second half of the effect still occurs even if you don\u2019t have a Digimon card to return from your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card if I don't have any Digimon cards in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have a Digimon with [Three Musketeers] in its type in play in your battle area, you can use this Option card even if you don\u2019t have a purple Digimon or Tamer in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"If you have a Digimon with [Three Musketeers] in its type in play, you may use this Option card without meeting its color requirements.\u201d How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If a DP-boosting effect activates when you play a Digimon, the Digimon\u2019s modified DP value is referenced by this card\u2019s effect. You can delete 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon with DP less than or equal to [Eosmon]\u2019s boosted DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card while I have 1 [ST1-12 Tai Kamiya] in play, and play a [BT6-085 Eosmon] from my hand. [ST1-12 Tai Kamiya]\u2019s effect gives [BT6-085 Eosmon] +1000 DP, bringing it up to a total of 7000 DP. Can I delete 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon with 7000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates at the end of the battle, regardless of outcome.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Security] effect activate even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Even after using this card\u2019s [Security] effect to prevent your opponent\u2019s Digimon from attacking players, it only prevents them from declaring further attacks. The current attack proceeds normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card\u2019s [Security] effect to prevent my opponent\u2019s currently attacking Digimon from attacking players, does the attack end immediately, or does my opponent get to perform their remaining security checks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses this card\u2019s [Security] effect to prevent one of my Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from attacking players. If that Digimon attacks and deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives, do I still get to perform security checks with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  This card\u2019s [Security Effect] only affects Digimon that are in play at the time it\u2019s activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 11 or fewer Digimon in play, and my opponent activates this card\u2019s [Security] effect, preventing all of my Digimon from attacking players for the turn. If I later play a Digimon with \uff1cRush\uff1e during that same turn, can that Digimon attack players?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks and is deleted in battle, does its [End of Attack] effect activate at the end of the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT6-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore its color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to use an Option card, can I use any 7-cost Option card, regardless of its color requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t. Since those options are cards that have effects that \u201creduce the cost by\u2026\u201d or \u201cits memory cost is equal to\u2026\u201d when they would be used, their cost has not actually changed when activating this card\u2019s [On Play] effect, so they can\u2019t be used with this card\u2019s effect. However, since [BT2-099 Glorious Burst] always has the effect of reducing its use cost when used from the hand, if you have 2 yellow Tamers, it can be used with this card\u2019s effect as its use cost will be 7.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use option cards that can change their cost to 7 on certain conditions such as [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast] or [BT11-108 DG Dimension] with this card\u2019s [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. No color is specified, so you can activate the effect of any Tamer, regardless of color.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do Tamers of any color make the effect of this card active?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The <Digi-Burst> effect activates first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which activates first: This card\u2019s inherited effect, or the effect that activates when you trash this card with <Digi-Burst>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When a Digimon digivolves, even if it happens due to an effect, it is not counted as an effect placing digivolution cards under that Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my effects digivolves a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple cards are added to the Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, if they were added by a single effect, you only draw 1 card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of my effects places 2 or more cards at the same time under a Digimon that has this card's inherited effect, can I draw that many cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can choose whether or not to reveal cards from your deck, but if any Tamer cards are revealed among the cards, you must trash 1 of them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are Tamer cards among the cards revealed with this card's inherited effect, do I have to trash 1 of them?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you play this card with no Tamers in play, you only get to play 1 red Tamer card from your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play this card while I have no Tamers in play, and play a red Tamer from my hand with this card's effect, do I then also gain 2 memory from this effect since I now have a Tamer in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple Digimon are deleted, if they were deleted by a single effect, you only gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I delete 2 or more of my opponent\u2019s Digimon at the same time, does this card\u2019s inherited effect allow me to gain 1 memory for each Digimon deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. All [Security] effects on non-Option cards activate normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards performs a security check, if the checked card is a Digimon card or a Tamer card, does its [Security] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, its play cost is reduced by the total number of Option cards in both you and your opponent's trashes.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card\u2019s play cost reduced by 1 for each Option card in ONLY my trash or my opponent\u2019s trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who activated the effect decides the order in which their cards and their opponent's cards are returned to the bottom of each player's decks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to return cards from both players\u2019 trashes to the bottom of their owners\u2019 decks. Who decides which order the cards are placed in?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The [Your Turn] effect is activated immediately after this Digimon is blocked and it's attack target is changed. So, since the effect is triggered by your opponent blocking this Digimon, it will finish resolving before the battle against the blocking Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this Digimon, and it is blocked by an opponent's Digimon at the blocker timing. At what timing does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place 1 red or black level 5 card with [Cyborg] in its traits from my hand or trash on top of this Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's [When Digivolving] effect even if my opponent has no Digimon with 6000 DP or less in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my [Machinedramon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card become a Digimon as a result of \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) doesn\u2019t count as playing it, so you can\u2019t draw any cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is targeted with \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) by my opponent, resulting in this card now being the Digimon\u2019s top card. Do I draw 2 cards with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Once a Digimon is targeted by this card's [When Digivolving] effect, it becomes unable to attack or block until the end of your opponent\u2019s turn, even if it gains a digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect prevents a Digimon from attacking or blocking, if that Digimon gains a digivolution card afterwards, can it attack or block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you play this card with no Tamers in play, you only get to play 1 blue Tamer card from your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play this card while I have no Tamers in play, and play a blue Tamer from my hand with this card's effect, do I then also gain 2 memory from this effect since I now have a Tamer in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] effect places a Digimon card from my hand under 1 of my Digimon. Can I place it under this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It enters play as a new Digimon, unsuspended. Additionally, it does not carry over any effects on the source Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] effect plays a level 3 Digimon card from the digivolution cards of a suspended Digimon. Does the level 3 Digimon enter play suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having a digivolution card become a Digimon as a result of \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) does not count as playing that card, so this card's [Your Turn] effect does not trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon with digivolution cards is targeted by my opponent\u2019s \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards), resulting in it becoming one of the Digimon in its digivolution cards. When this happens, can I return 1 of my opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon to its owner's hand with this card's [Yout Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the effect can be activated both [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking].  You can activate it as a [When Digivolving] effect when you digivolve this Digimon, then activate it again on following turns as a [When Attacking] effect by attacking with this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that activates at both [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking] timings. What does this mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. No matter which timing the effect is triggered at, it is still the same effect and can only be activated [Once Per Turn]. If the effect has been triggered at [When Digivolving] and activated, it can not be activated again on the same turn, even if it's triggered [When Attacking].[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has a [When Digivolving][When Attacking][Once Per Turn] effect, but can I activate it twice in the same turn by both digivolving and attacking?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Return this card to its owner\u2019s hand after <Digi-Burst> activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I trash this card from a Digimon's digivolution cards to activate <Digi-Burst>. Do I return this card to its owner's hand before or after the <Digi-Burst> effect activates?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a suspended Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and this card in its digivolution cards, and my opponent attacks me with a Digimon. I unsuspend the Digimon with this card's inherited effect. Can I now block the opponent\u2019s Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The <Digi-Burst> effect activates first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use <Digi-Burst> to trash this card from a Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Which activates first: This card\u2019s inherited effect, or the effect that activates when you trash this card with <Digi-Burst>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution cost is equal to the number of cards in your security stack minus the amount reduced by the effect.  If you have 4 security cards and activate an effect that reduces digivolution costs by 2, the final digivolution cost will be 2. (4 minus 2.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card from my hand, I activate an effect on another card that reduces digivolution costs. What happens to this card\u2019s digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. This card's <Digi-Burst up to 4> allows you to choose any number of digivolution cards to trash, from 1 to 4. If you have 3 or fewer digivolution cards, you can activate the effect as long as you can trash 1 or more of them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s <Digi-Burst> reads \u201cup to 4.\u201d Can I activate the effect if I have 3 or fewer digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect can only target 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I trash 2 digivolution cards to activate this card's <Digi-Burst>. Can I have 2 of my opponent's Digimon both get -3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you digivolve into this card while at 2 or fewer security cards, you only go up to 3 security cards with <Recovery>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect when I have 2 or fewer security cards to go up to 3 security cards with <Recovery>. Do I now gain 2 memory for being at 3 or more security cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you revealed only a card with [Hybrid] in its traits or [J.P. Shibayama], you still add that card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 5 cards with this card's [When Digivolving] effect. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Hybrid] in its traits or [J.P. Shibayama], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It is too late to trigger those [When Attacking] effects because it did not have them when the attack was declared.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve into a green level 6 Digimon with this card's [When Attacking] effect. Can I activate that Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect is mandatory. You reveal as many cards as you can, up to 3.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When attacking, do I have to reveal 3 cards from my deck with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \u201cYou may digivolve,\u201d so you can choose not to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a green level 6 Digimon card is among the cards revealed with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, do I have to digivolve into it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can digivolve into the Digimon of your choosing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If 2 or more green level 6 Digimon cards are among the cards revealed with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, can I choose either card to digivolve into?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, do I draw a card as a digivolution bonus?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \u201cThis Digimon can digivolve,\u201d so you can choose not to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a card with [Hybrid] or [Insectoid] in its traits in this Digimon's digivolution cards. Does this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect force me to digivolve this Digimon into a Digimon card with [Insectoid] or [Ten Warriors] in its traits in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues. The turn doesn\u2019t switch over just yet. If the memory gauge is still at 1 or more on your opponent\u2019s side after the attack ends and any effects triggered by it finish activating, only then does the turn switch over.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with this card's [When Attacking] effect, paying the digivolution cost moves the memory gauge to 1 or more on my opponent\u2019s side. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is too late to trigger this card's [When Attacking] effect, since the Digimon didn't have it when the attack was declared.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with [EX1-035 Kabuterimon] and digivolve into this card with its [When Attacking] effect. Can I then digivolve again on the same attack with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore its digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into a Digimon card in my hand with [Insectoid] or [Ten Warriors] in its traits with this card's [When Attacking] effect, can I ignore that card's digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.",
      "question": "Q: Using this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I prevent my opponent's Digimon from becoming unsuspended during my opponent's next unsuspend phase by applying this effect to it while it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Your opponent must trash 1 card in their hand for each Digimon they unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent unsuspends 2 or more of their Digimon. Does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect allow my opponent to unsuspend all of their Digimon by trashing 1 card in their hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The [Opponent's Turn] effect cannot force the opponent to trash cards in their hand. However, no matter how the Digimon would become unsuspended, whether from an effect or your opponent's unsuspend phase, the Digimon cannot unsuspend unless the opponent trashes a card in their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an effect would cause an opponent\u2019s Digimon to unsuspend, does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect force my opponent to trash a card in their hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose which of your Digimon to unsuspend, and trash a card in your hand for each one.  Digimon will not unsuspend unless you choose to trash a card in your hand, so even if you have fewer cards in hand than suspended Digimon in play, you can still choose to unsuspend specific Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I have 3 suspended Digimon in play, do I need to have 3 or more cards in hand during my unsuspend phase in order to unsuspend my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect only affects Digimon. Your opponent can unsuspend their Tamers normally, without trashing cards in their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect require my opponent to trash cards in their hand to also unsuspend their Tamer cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Your opponent\u2019s Digimon now have two copies of \u201c[Your Turn] You must trash 1 card in your hand to unsuspend this Digimon\u201d on them, which means they have to trash 2 cards in their hand to unsuspend 1 of their Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have two of these Digimon in play. Does my opponent have to trash 2 cards in their hand for each Digimon they want to unsuspend?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you revealed only a card with [X Antibody] in its traits or [Kota Domoto], you still add that card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 3 cards with this card's [On Play] effect. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [X Antibody] in its traits or [Kota Domoto], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When a Digimon digivolves, even if it happens due to an effect, it is not counted as an effect placing digivolution cards under that Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my effects digivolves a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple cards are added to the Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, you only gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: f one of my effects places 2 or more cards at the same time under a Digimon that has this card's inherited effect, do I gain that much memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.  This card's inherited effect is a [Your Turn] effect, so it can be activated when this card becomes a digivolution card under a Digimon in the battle area. Therefore, when this card itself is added, the effect is triggered as an inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is placed in one of my Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose a [DeadlyAxemon] with no digivolution cards with this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect place one of my [DeadlyAxemon] with no digivolution cards at the bottom of this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, [DeadlyAxemon] becomes a different Digimon, so the [BT9-109 X Antibody] in its digivolution cards is send to the trash according to the rules.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect place one of my [DeadlyAxemon] with [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards at the bottom of this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: WWhen this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You don't have to place both a [SkullKnightmon] and a [DeadlyAxemon]. You can also place either of them on their own from either your hand or trash in this Digimon's digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect place cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards if I don\u2019t have both a [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] in either my hand or trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can mix and match [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] from both your hand and trash to place in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect place a [SkullKnightmon] in my hand and a [DeadlyAxemon] in my trash in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether to play them. However, if both [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] are in digivolution cards, you must choose to either play both of them or play none of them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have both [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect require me to play both?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [All Turns] effect triggers and activates immediately prior to the Digimon being deleted. In this way, the [All Turns] effect has the same timing as effects that say, \u201cwhen this Digimon would be deleted\u201d.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When does the [All Turns] effect of the Digimon trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you only had either \"Skull Knightmon\" or \"Deadly Axmon\", you can still place them on the digivolution card.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect be placed in the digivolving card unless I have both \"Skull Knightmon\" and \"Deadly Axmon\" in my hand or trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can put \"Skull Knightmon\" and \"Deadly Axmon\" from both hand and trash to digivolution card.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] effect put \"Skull Knightmon\" from my hand and \"Deadly Axmon\" from my trash to digivolving card respectively?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is \"can appear\" and you can choose whether or not to have it play. However, if you have both \"Skull Knightmon\" and \"Deadly Axmon\" as digivolution cards, you can either play both of them or none of them.[4]",
      "question": "Q: For this card's [All Turns] effect, if there are both \"Skull Knightmon\" and \"Deadly Axmon\" as digivolves, do I always have to play both?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's Japanese name (\u30c9\u30eb\u30b0\u30ec\u30e2\u30f3) does not have \"Greymon\" (\u30b0\u30ec\u30a4\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Greymon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may,\u201d so you can choose not to activate it. However, after revealing a card from your deck, you must perform the rest of the effect to the best of your ability.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect when digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Once you choose to reveal cards, you must trash all Tamer cards you reveal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If Tamer cards are among the 5 cards revealed by this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, am I required to trash them?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I don\u2019t have [Eyesmon: Scatter Mode] in my trash. If I trash both this card and [Eyesmon: Scatter Mode] in my hand with an effect, can I play this card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Tamer cards' [Security] effects aren't inherited effects. Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon digivolves onto a Tamer card, does the Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 3 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  However, if the effect specifies Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't be targeted by that effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve using a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with that Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-075": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A purple Tamer card is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. If this Digimon is deleted, can its [On Deletion] effect play that purple Tamer card from my trash without paying its memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-078": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I delete this card itself with its [When Digivolving] effect to delete 1 of my opponent's level 6 or lower Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you don\u2019t play a Tamer from your trash, everything following \u201cThen,\u201d still activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I do not play a purple Tamer card from my trash with this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect. Does the \u201cfor each Tamer you have in play, delete 1 of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon\u201d part of the effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Tamer card is in a Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. If that Digimon is deleted, can this card's [All Turns] effect play the Tamer card that used to be in that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards from my trash without paying its memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you revealed only a card with [Hybrid] or [Ten Warriors] in its traits or a Tamer card, you still add that card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I reveal 5 cards with this card's [On Play] effect. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Hybrid] or [Ten Warriors] in its traits or a Tamer card, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect can only place [Sistermon Blanc].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place a [Sistermon Blanc (Awakened)] from my hand or trash at the bottom of this Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Those cards have [Huckmon] and/or [Sistermon], so you can add one of them to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect return [BaoHuckmon], [SaviorHuckmon], or [Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)] from my trash to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect can only place [Sistermon Ciel].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place a [Sistermon Ciel (Awakened)] from my hand or trash at the bottom of this Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Those cards have [Huckmon] and/or [Sistermon], so you can add one of them to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect return [BaoHuckmon], [SaviorHuckmon], or [Sistermon Blanc (Awakened)] from my trash to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the name [Sistermon Noir (Awakened)] and the [Virus]\u00a0trait.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"Also treated as Name: [Sistermon Noir (Awakened)] and \"Also treated as Trait: [Virus]\" have been changed to \"(Rule) Also treated as Name: [Sistermon Noir (Awakened)] and Trait: [Virus]\") \""
    }
  ],
  "BT7-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The card text reads, \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose to only place 5 cards with [Hybrid] in their traits under this Tamer without digivolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 5 cards with [Hybrid] in their traits under this Tamer from my trash, and then choose not to digivolve into [EmperorGreymon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I only have 4 cards in my trash with [Hybrid] in their traits, can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 4 cards from my trash under this Tamer without digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this Tamer to a [EmperorGreymon] in my hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon other than this card's is activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can be activated after the tamer has evolved into a Digimon card that can digivolved from the tamer and this card is the digivolution card from the tamer to the digivolved Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: This card has a digivolution card effect, how can I activate it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is \"can digivolve\", so it is possible to put 5 cards with \"Hybrid Body\" in the trait from the trash under this tamer without digivolving to \"EmperorGreymon\".[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to put 5 cards with \"Hybrid Body\" in their traits from my trash under this tamer and dare not digivolve to \"EmperorGreymon\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, I cannot.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When there are only 4 cards with \"Hybrid Body\" in the trait in my trash, can I use this card's [Main] effect to put only 4 cards from my trash under this tamer, even though it cannot digivolution?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-086": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Once a Digimon is targeted by this card's inherited effect, it becomes unable to attack or block until the end of your opponent\u2019s turn, even if it gains a digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect prevents a Digimon from attacking or blocking, if that Digimon gains a digivolution card afterwards, can it attack or block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an opponent's effect returns one of my Digimon to its owner's hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The card text reads, \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose to only place 5 cards with [Hybrid] in their traits under this Tamer without digivolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 5 cards with [Hybrid] in their traits under this Tamer from my hand, and then choose not to digivolve into [MagnaGarurumon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I only have 4 cards in my hand with [Hybrid] in their traits, can I activate this card's [Main] effect to place 4 cards from my hand under this Tamer without digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it still has it. If this Digimon digivolves into a Digimon again during this turn, that Digimon can't be blocked for the turn.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have P-153 [MagnaGarurumon] with this card in digivolution cards in the battle area.  I activated this card's inherited effect, then I used P-153 [MagnaGarurumon]'s [End of Attack] effect to place P-153 [MagnaGarurumon] as my top security card, and this card became the Digimon's top card.  At such times, does this card still have \"this Digimon can't be blocked for the turn\"?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this Tamer to a [MagnaGarurumon] in my hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon other than this card's is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-091": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Some Digimon cards can digivolve onto Tamers. Digivolve such a Digimon onto this card, and it will become part of that Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How do I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if a Security Digimon\u2019s DP is reduced to 0, they still battle the Digimon performing the security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then, during a security check, I flip one of my opponent\u2019s Security Digimon, whose DP is reduced to 0 by this card\u2019s [Main] effect. Is the opponent\u2019s Security Digimon deleted without a battle taking place?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When your security stack is empty, this card\u2019s memory cost is 0.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My security stack is empty. Can I use this card without paying any memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You didn\u2019t have a [Rasenmon] in play when you used this card, so it's too late to give it \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to have an opponent\u2019s Digimon get -3000 DP, then play a [Rasenmon]. Can I have that [Rasenmon] gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can use this card, but no effect will occur.  This will still trigger any effects that trigger when you use Option cards, however.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card when I don\u2019t have a Digimon with [Hybrid] or [Ten Warriors] in play? If I can, what does the effect do?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.",
      "question": "Q: Using this card's [Main] effect, can I prevent my opponent's Digimon from becoming unsuspended during my opponent's next unsuspend phase by applying this effect to it while it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Whether or not you play a Digimon with this card\u2019s effect is irrelevant. You still place it in your battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect, but there are either no black Digimon cards with play costs of 4 or less among the revealed cards, or there is one, but I choose not to play it. Do I discard this card instead of placing it in my battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I don\u2019t have a Digimon with 5 or more digivolution cards and [X Antibody] in its traits in play. Can I delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less and [X Antibody] in its traits with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with 5 or more digivolution cards and [X Antibody] in its traits in play. Can I delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less and [X Antibody] in its traits with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to delete 1 of my purple Digimon. Can I then return that Digimon card to my hand with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [On Deletion] effect is triggered, but it cannot activate because the Digimon card leaves the trash before that.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to delete 1 of my purple Digimon with an [On Deletion] effect and return it to my hand. What happens to the [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The number of Digimon you can delete is equal to the total number of Digimon with [Hybrid] in their traits and Tamers you have in play.  For example, if you have 2 Digimon with [Hybrid] in their traits and 1 Tamer in play, you can choose a total of 3 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \u201cFor each Digimon with [Hybrid] in its traits and each Tamer you have in play, delete 1 of your opponent's level 5 or lower Digimon\u201d mean that I can delete 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon for each pair of [Hybrid] Digimon and Tamer I have in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 10 or more cards in my trash. Can I use this card\u2019s effect to play 1 purple level 5 Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have a Digimon with [Hybrid] in its traits in your battle area, you can use this Option card even if you don\u2019t have a white Digimon or Tamer in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \u201cIf you have a Digimon with [Hybrid] in its traits in play, you may use this Option card without meeting its color requirements.\u201c How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the effect can be activated both [On Play] and [When Digivolving].[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that has both [On Play] and [When Digivolving] timings. What does this mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my [Lucemon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT7-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card\u2019s digivolution requirement icon refers to all colors.  Currently, this Digimon can digivolve onto a level 6 Digimon that\u2019s red, blue, yellow, green, black, purple, or white.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What color cards does this card\u2019s digivolution requirement icon refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can mix and match cards from your hand and trash. As long as you return a total of 10 cards to the bottom of your deck, you can activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201c10 Tamer cards and/or cards with [Hybrid] in their traits from your hand and/or trash,\u201d but does this mean I can only activate the effect by returning 10 cards in my hand or 10 cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. A Tamer card's [Security] effect isn't an inherited effect.  Some Tamer cards do have inherited effects, and those can be activated when such cards are placed in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has a Tamer card in its digivolution cards, does that Tamer card\u2019s [Security] effect become an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Instead of a Tamer card, can I digivolve this card onto a level 6 Digimon that meets the digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: es, it is. However, if the effect specifies that it trashes Digimon cards, Digi-Egg cards, or any other type of card that isn't a Tamer card, it can't affect Tamer cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After a Tamer card ends up in this Digimon's digivolution cards, is that card affected by effects that trash digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. Even if you digivolve onto a Tamer card, make sure to draw 1 card as the digivolution bonus.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card, do I still get the digivolution bonus?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolution doesn't count as \u201cplaying\u201d a card, so you can attack that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack the turn I digivolve this card on top of a Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it's the first turn the Tamer was played, the limitation for attacking on the first turn a card is played still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play a Tamer card, then digivolve it into this Digimon. Can I then attack with this Digimon during that same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I've digivolved this card on top of a Tamer card and the Digimon is deleted, what happens to the Tamer card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must reveal this card from your hand in advance.  You must perform the \u201cplacing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with [Hybrid] in their traits from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\u201d part of the effect before the digivolution takes place, so you must reveal the card from your hand first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s \u201cplacing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with [Hybrid] in their traits from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\u201d effect while this card is still in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may digivolve,\u201d so you can choose not to.  If you choose not to digivolve, this card is trashed after you reveal it.  Note that the game will not view this as you trashing a card in your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s \u201cplacing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with [Hybrid] in their traits from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\u201d effect but choose not to digivolve this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In this case, you can\u2019t digivolve even after performing the actions described by the effect. After revealing this card, it is trashed.  Note that the game will not view this as you trashing a card in your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s \u201cplacing 10 Tamer cards and/or cards with [Hybrid] in their traits from your hand and/or trash at the bottom of your deck\u201d effect when I have no Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my Tamers in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s effect activate when my opponent has no Digimon in play in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. This effect can't be used on Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are 6 cards in my security stack, does this card\u2019s effect grant +2000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is placed in one of my Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when one of my own effects trashes a card from my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the top of your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s inherited effect doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my effects reveals cards from the top of my deck and trashes one or more of them. Does this cause this card\u2019s inherited effect to activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s effect add a\uff12-color Option card to my hand if one of its colors is red?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Effects don't activate for cards revealed from your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s effect add a card with a \"this Digimon is also treated as red\" effect to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you have 2 yellow Digimon in play, this effect can only reduce the play cost by a maximum of 1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 yellow Digimon in play, does this effect reduce this card\u2019s play cost by 2?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect has already been activated, so the +3000 DP effect persists for the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this Digimon gets +3000 DP from the [When Attacking] effect, its \uff1cArmor Purge\uff1e activates. What happens to the +3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect also count this Digimon itself as a Digimon with [Tyrannomon], granting it \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses 1 of their Digimon. Next, delete all Digimon in play, from both you and your opponent, except for this Digimon and the Digimon your opponent chose. Then you gain 1 memory for every Digimon that was deleted by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas cannot be affected by effects, so they aren't deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect delete Digimon in breeding areas, too?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas cannot be affected by effects, so they can't be chosen. Additionally, note that this effect doesn't delete Digimon in breeding areas, regardless of whether they could be chosen or not.[1]",
      "question": "Q: For this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, can my opponent choose a Digimon in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: All of your other Digimon besides this one are deleted, and you gain 1 memory for each Digimon deleted in this way.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect work if my opponent has no Digimon in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect deletes Digimon in play, can you and your opponent activate \uff1cDecoy (nocategory)\uff1e (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion), \uff1cArmor Purge\uff1e, and similar effects to prevent their deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you to DNA digivolve a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon in your hand that has [DNA Digivolution]. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can't ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn't have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn't have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect add a 2-color Option card to my hand if one of its colors is blue?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Effects don't activate for cards revealed from your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s effect add a card with a \"this Digimon is also treated as blue\" effect to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you can't trash any of your opponent\u2019s digivolution cards, you still get to give -3000 DP to 1 of their Digimon with no digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent doesn't have any Digimon with digivolution cards in play, meaning this card's [When Digivolving] effect can't trash the bottom digivolution card of 1 of my opponent's Digimon. Do I still activate the \"1 of your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards gets -3000 DP for the turn\" part of the effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect triggers \"when this Digimon would digivolve,\" so it occurs after declaring the digivolution, but before paying the digivolution cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [Your Turn] effect activates and I <Recovery +1 (Deck)>, when exactly does this happen?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect also activate when DNA digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card's effect reads \"when this Digimon would digivolve\", so it activates. In that case, the effect activates even if the digivolution fails, so the <Recovery +1 (Deck)> activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 3 or fewer security cards and this Digimon would digivolve, but the digivolution cost can no longer be paid due to the inherited effect of my opponent's [EX3-016 SnowAgumon], [EX3-019 Paledramon] or other cards and the digivolution fails, can this card's <Recovery +1 (Deck)> activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-026 Halsemon] can digivolve from [Hawkmon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Hawkmon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-026 Halsemon], as an effect? Can [BT8-026 Halsemon] digivolve from [Hawkmon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, digivolving doesn't count as playing a card, so the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s effect activate when your opponent\u2019s Digimon digivolves to level 5 or higher?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, moving a Digimon from your breeding area doesn't count as playing it, so the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s effect activate when your opponent moves a level 5 or higher Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digimon in breeding areas aren\u2019t counted by the effect, so this Digimon can attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with digivolution cards in their breeding area, can this Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when my opponent activates <Digi-Burst>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both blue and green cards are in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, do I activate both parts of this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a single blue and green multicolor card is in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, do I activate both parts of this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s effect to add a two-color Option card to my hand if one of its colors is yellow?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Effects don't activate for cards revealed from your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s effect add a card with a \"this Digimon is also treated as yellow\" effect to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself blue, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect has already been activated, so the DP boost persists for the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to gain +2000 DP for each card with [Armor Form] in its traits in my trash, I use \uff1cArmor Purge\uff1e to trash this card. What happens to the DP boost?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. No matter how many Tamers you have in play, the effect gives -5000 DP to up to 3 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 Tamers in play, can this card's [When Digivolving] effect give up to 6 of my opponent's Digimon -5000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon is now treated as having two colors, so you \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect trashes a red card in my hand. Does this make this Digimon a red/yellow 2-color Digimon, allowing me to \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the Digimon is now treated as having three colors.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect trashes a blue/green multicolor card in my hand. Does this make this Digimon a yellow/blue/green 3-color Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect activates for each Tamer you have in play, and you can choose a different target for each activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple Tamers in play, can this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect give <Security Attack -2> to a different one of my opponent\u2019s Digimon for each Tamer I have in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it\u2019s treated as a single timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I activate this card\u2019s [On Play][When Digivolving] effect multiple times, is each activation treated as its own timing?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. This Digimon's [Your Turn] effect only triggers when your other Digimon digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve one of my suspended Digimon into this Digimon. Does this card's [Your Turn] effect let me unsuspend this Digimon itself?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Once a Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e is targeted by this card's [When Digivolving] effect, it becomes unable to attack or block until the end of your opponent\u2019s next turn, even if it loses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose an opponent's Digimon for this card's [When Digivolving] effect, and that Digimon loses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e due to digivolving, \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards), or some other reason, can that Digimon now attack and block again?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's [When Digivolving] effect, can I suspend this Digimon itself in order to suspend 1 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-051 Digmon] can digivolve from [Armadillomon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Armadillomon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-051 Digmon], as an effect? Can [BT8-051 Digmon] digivolve from [Armadillomon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [BT8-053 Lighdramon] can digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area. Special digivolutions are a digivolution requirements with reference to special conditions, not effects. Therefore, special digivolution conditions can be fulfilled even in the breeding area. (From Card Rulings:BT8-012)",
      "question": "Q: Do you treat the special digivolution requirements of \"<Digivolve: 2 from [Veemon]>\", written in the text for [BT8-053 Lighdramon], as an effect? Can [BT8-053 Lighdramon] digivolve from [Veemon] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Digimon with \uff1cReboot\uff1e unsuspend at the same time as the current player's turn. This effect activates \"if this Digimon is unsuspended\", so it activates immediately after.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect before my opponent's Digimon unsuspends in the unsuspend phase due to \uff1cReboot\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You already used the Option cards and activated their effects, so this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect can\u2019t negate them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. During my turn, I use an Option card like [BT1-109 Smashed Potatoes] or [EX1-071 Win Rate: 60%!] which has an effect that activates \u201cthe next time one of your Digimon digivolves\u201d. After that, all of my opponent\u2019s Digimon become suspended.  If I then digivolve one of my Digimon, are the effects from the Option cards I used earlier negated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Activating \uff1cDelay\uff1e on Option cards that are already in your battle area doesn't count as using an Option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has this Digimon in play. If I have an Option card with \uff1cDelay\uff1e that I used from my hand earlier, can I activate its \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents all players from digivolving with effects that say \"ignoring digivolution requirements\" or otherwise digivolving from Digimon without meeting digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Those effects don't mention \u201cignoring digivolution requirements,\u201d and require you to follow the specified digivolution requirements when digivolving a Tamer as if they were a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also prevent the effects on [Hybrid] cards like \"You may digivolve this card from your hand onto one of your red Tamers as if the Tamer is a level 3 red Digimon\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. DNA and special digivolutions are treated as a card\u2019s digivolution requirements, so you can still perform both as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s effect prevent DNA and special digivolutions?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect doesn't ignore digivolution requirements\u2015it just lets you skip paying the memory cost\u2015so you can activate it as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, can I activate an effect that reads, \u201cyou may digivolve...without paying its memory cost\u201d?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents digivolves from ignoring digivolution requirements. This effect affects both players.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What is the effect of \"neither party can ignore digivolution requirements?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be DNA digivolves or burst digivolutions.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I DNA digivolve or burst digivolve while the \"neither of us can ignore the digivolution requirements\" effect is active?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can digivolve. If you digivolve without paying the cost, you are not ignoring the digivolution requirements.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve without paying the cost while the \"each other can't ignore digivolution requirements\" effect is active?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot ignore any part of the digivolution requirements to digivolve.[2]",
      "question": "Q: While the \"Mutual cannot ignore digivolution requirements\" effect is activated, can I ignore some of the digivolution requirements, such as the \"Ignore Lv."
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot digivolve.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the [When Attacking] effect of \"BT10-067 Justimon: Critical Arm\" to digivolve it while the \"Mutually cannot ignore digivolution requirements\" effect is activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can digivolve. The effect of digivolving a card with additional information is not an effect that ignores the digivolution requirements.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the first effect of BT4-011 Agunimon to digivolve from tamers while the \"Mutually cannot ignore digivolution requirements\" effect is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Mamemon] name.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [Mamemon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Mamemon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] names.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself red, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add up to 4 cards in any combination from your hand and/or trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's effect add a total of up to 4 Digimon cards with [Mamemon] from both my hand and/or trash to the top of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Digivolution requirements cannot be ignored unless an effect explicitly instructs you to ignore them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Your Turn] effect digivolve it into any Digimon card regardless of digivolution requirements, so long as it has [X Antibody] in its traits?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can reveal 3 cards, then trash all of them.  Note that the effect reads, \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether or not to activate the effect when digivolving, regardless of whether or not your opponent has any Digimon in play. If you choose not to activate it, you don't reveal or trash any cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect work if my opponent has no Digimon in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Play cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \u201cmemory cost of 10 or less\u201d refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has both red and black digivolution cards, can this card's [When Digivolving] effect delete both Digimon and Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The total play costs of the chosen Digimon and Tamers must add up to 6 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card has both red and black digivolution cards, can this card's [When Digivolving] effect delete both 6 play cost worth of my opponent\u2019s Digimon, and 6 play cost worth of my opponent\u2019s Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a single red and black multicolor card is in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, can I activate both parts of this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It prevents effects that reduce play costs. Even if you or your opponent activates an effect that reduces play costs, the cost that is paid cannot actually be reduced. Players must pay the full play cost printed on cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s \u201cPlayers can\u2019t reduce play costs\u201d effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that play cards without paying their memory costs are skipping the costs entirely, not reducing them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, can I activate an effect that reads, \u201cplay <a card>...without paying its memory cost\u201d?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't be reduced. This card's effect does not target Digimon, so even if your opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] is in the breeding area, its effect to reduce play costs can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the play cost of a Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait be reduced due to the [Your Turn] effect of my opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] if this Digimon is in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: That's correct. Such effects can no longer reduce play costs.  This card's effect also prevents play cost-reducing effects from activating when Tamer cards are played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Digimon, can my opponent no longer use [BT14-046 Togemon]'s [Your Turn] effect or inherited effect to reduce the play cost of green Tamer cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card\u2019s effect can only trash purple Digimon cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal a non-purple Digimon card with this card\u2019s [On Play] effect, can I trash it?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the top of your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card\u2019s effect triggered by the activation of an effect that reads, \u201cReveal the top X cards of your deck... Trash the remaining cards.\u201d?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the top of your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card\u2019s inherited effect triggered by the activation of an effect that reads, \u201cReveal the top X cards of your deck... Trash the remaining cards.\u201d?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If both purple and yellow cards are in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, can I activate both parts of this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a single purple and yellow multicolor card is in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, can I activate both parts of this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect allows this card to be treated as both white (its original color), and as the colors of its digivolution cards.  For example, if a red card and green card are in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, this card is treated as a 3-color white/red/green card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect can only be activated if the Digimon itself has 2 or more colors.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that reads, \u201cWhen one of your Digimon with 2 or more colors attacks\u201d\u2015does this include the colors of the attacking Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect only triggers when your opponent chooses one of your blue Digimon as a target of attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect triggered when I block an opponent\u2019s attack with one of my blue Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate both parts of this card\u2019s [Start of Your Main Phase] effect if I have both a blue Digimon and green Digimon in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a single blue and green multicolor Digimon in play, can I activate both parts of this card\u2019s [Start of Your Main Phase] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect can only be activated if the Digimon itself has 2 or more colors.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that reads, \u201cWhen one of your Digimon with 2 or more colors attacks\u201d\u2015does this include the colors of the attacking Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect activate when an effect from a card like [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa] moves a level 3 Digimon from your opponent's breeding area to their battle area outside of their breeding phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the main phase doesn't take place and the turn ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the breeding phase, I move a Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area and due to this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect of my opponent, and the memory gauge moves to 1 or more on my opponent's side. In this case, do I have a main phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  The effect is looking for a Digimon with a digivolution card that has 2 or more colors.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s \u201cIf you have a Digimon in play with...2 or more colors in one of its digivolution cards\u201d count a Digimon that has both a red card and a blue card in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  Effects that grant additional colors don't do anything as digivolution cards, so the card is only treated as a single color.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s \u201cIf you have a Digimon in play with...2 or more colors in one of its digivolution cards\u201d count a Digimon with a card like [BT3-040 Shakkoumon]\u2019s \u201cThis Digimon is also treated as blue\u201d in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It just reduces the cost of the card to 0.  Note that in general, costs can\u2019t be reduced to less than 0.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has 7 or more Digimon in play, does this card\u2019s effect get reduced to negative 1, effectively gaining me a memory for using it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After the battle between the attacking Digimon and Security Digimon, the effect prevents the Digimon from being played, so it's placed in the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then attack my opponent. During the security check, I flip over a Digimon card with the effect, \u201c[Security] At the end of the battle, play this card without paying its memory cost.\u201d  What happens to this Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can't be played.  This card's [Main] effect was changed to \"Your opponent can't play Digimon by effects until the end of their turn. Delete all of your opponent's Digimon with 6000 DP or less.\" Therefore, first the effect that prevents playing Digimon is applied, then Digimon with 6000 DP or less are deleted.  Please see the notices regarding changes to the rules/rulings on the official website.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent used this card on my [BT7-063 DarkKnightmon].  [DarkKnightmon]'s [All Turns] effect is a \"when this Digimon would be deleted\" effect that interrupts deletion when it activates, but can I use this card's \"your opponent can't play Digimon by effects until the end of their turn\" effect to prevent [SkullKnightmon] and [DeadlyAxemon] from being played from [DarkKnightmon]'s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only specify Digimon that can't attack or block at the time this card\u2019s effect is activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, but my opponent has no Digimon without digivolution cards in play, so I can't specify any Digimon that can't attack or block.  If my opponent later plays a Digimon without digivolution cards to their battle area, can I make that Digimon unable to attack or block?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  The effect is looking for a Digimon with a digivolution card that has 2 or more colors.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s \u201cIf you have a Digimon in play with...2 or more colors in one of its digivolution cards\u201d count a Digimon that has both a red card and a blue card in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  Effects that grant additional colors don't do anything as digivolution cards, so the card is only treated as a single color.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s \u201cIf you have a Digimon in play with...2 or more colors in one of its digivolution cards\u201d count a Digimon with a card like [BT3-040 Shakkoumon]\u2019s \u201cThis Digimon is also treated as blue\u201d in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 1 card with [Armor Form] in its traits in my trash, can I use this card's effect to give an opponent's Digimon -4000 DP, and then give it an additional -1000 DP with the second part of the effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can choose 1 of your opponent\u2019s suspended Digimon or Tamers with this card's effect, but if you didn't use this effect to suspend that card, the \u201ccan't unsuspend until the end of their next turn\u201d part of the effect doesn't apply.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to prevent 1 of my opponent's suspended Digimon or Tamers from unsuspending until the end of their turn?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can choose any number of your opponent's Digimon, as long as the play costs of the chosen Digimon add up to 15 or less. For example, you could choose 1 Digimon with a play cost of 3 and 1 Digimon with a play cost of 12, or 1 Digimon with a play cost of 2 and 2 Digimon with play costs of 6.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \u201cChoose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose play costs add up to 15 or less\u201d mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As long as the total play costs of the chosen cards is less than 15, you can choose as many or as few cards as you like. However, note that you must choose a minimum of 1 Digimon with a play cost of 15 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose fewer cards than possible, even if the play costs of the chosen cards add up to less than 15?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Regardless of how a Digimon was played, only the play cost printed on the card is counted for this card\u2019s effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses effects to reduce play costs or play Digimon for free. Are Digimon played with these effects counted as having reduced play costs or play costs of 0 by this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As long as the total play costs of the chosen cards is less than 15, you can choose as many or as few cards as you like.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose fewer cards than possible, even if the play costs of the chosen cards add up to less than 15?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Digimon's play cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reads, \"Digimon with a memory cost of 6 or less,\" but which cost is this referring to?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has no Digimon in play or no Digimon with a level less than or equal to one of my Digimon, can I still use this card\u2019s effect to delete 1 of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even though it will have 0 DP the Digimon will not be deleted until the effect of Flame Hellscythe is over. As such, you cannot play a Digimon via the effect of Flame Hellscythe. (Rules Processing)",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has [BT9-047 Pomumon] or [BT9-033 Pillomon] in play. If I target that Digimon with the -6000 DP effect of this card. Can I still play a Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you do, only the Digimon you chose to digivolve will unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to trash the top card of 1 of my Digimon with [Armor Form] in its traits. Can I then digivolve one of my other Digimon into a Digimon card in my hand with [Armor Form] in its traits?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you choose this option, however, no Digimon will be unsuspended with this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to trash the top card of 1 of my Digimon with [Armor Form] in its traits. Can I then choose NOT to digivolve one of my other Digimon into a Digimon card in my hand with [Armor Form] in its traits?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Digivolution requirements cannot be ignored unless an effect explicitly instructs you to ignore them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card\u2019s effect to digivolve into a Digimon  in my hand with [Armor Form] in its traits, can I ignore its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you trash more than 4 cards with the effect, you can only play 1 level 5 or lower purple Digimon card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Digivolving] effect trashes 8 cards from the top of my deck, can I play 2 level 5 or lower purple Digimon cards from my trash without paying their memory costs?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cFor every 10 cards in your trash,\u201d so if you have 20 cards in your trash, you would trash the top 6 cards of your opponent\u2019s deck and get +6000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 20 cards in my trash, does this card's [When Attacking] effect trash the top 6 cards of my opponent\u2019s deck and give this Digimon +6000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT8-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will activate in both timing [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking]. When you digivolving into this Digimon, it will activate as a [When Digivolving] effect, and for the following turns when this Digimon attacks, it will then activate again as a [When Attacking] effect.",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect has 2 timing, [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking]. What does that mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. If you do not do <X> you cannot do the rest of the effect. (See more in Effect Structure#Optional and Mandatory Effects",
      "question": "Q: This card has \"you may <X> to <Y>. Then, <Z>\" If I do not do <X>, am I still allowed to do <Z>?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an effect returns one of my Digimon to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate an effect that reads \u201c\uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, trash 1 card in your hand.\u201d Even though I trashed a card in my hand, does the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e allow me to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate an effect that reads, \u201cAdd 1 card from your security to your hand. Then, <Recovery +1 (Deck)>.\u201d Even though I lost a card from my security, does the <Recovery +1 (Deck)> allow me to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Greymon] or [X Antibody] is among the cards revealed, you add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Greymon] or [X Antibody], do I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. In this case, you must add both 1 card with [Greymon], and 1 [X Antibody] to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If both a card with [Greymon] and [X Antibody] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to add only one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect requires you to trash two cards in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards that are the same level as each other. The level of this Digimon doesn't matter.  For example, if there are two level 5 cards in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, you can trash both to prevent this Digimon from being deleted or returned to your hand or deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s inherited effect reads, \u201cyou may trash 2 cards of the same level\u201d. Does this mean I have to trash 2 cards that are the same level as this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s inherited effect reads, \u201cyou may trash 2 cards of the same level\u201d. If this card is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, can I include it as one of the trashed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When a Digimon is deleted after its DP is reduced to zero, it's considered to be deleted by the game rules, not an effect. This card\u2019s effect only activates when the card is deleted by an effect, so it won't activate in this instance.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent\u2019s effect reduced this Digimon\u2019s DP to zero, deleting it. Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [OmniShoutmon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cWhile this Digimon has [OmniShoutmon] or [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [WarGrowlmon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif [WarGrowlmon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [MetalGreymon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif this Digimon has [MetalGreymon] or [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If a [MetalGreymon] or [X Antibody] isn\u2019t in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards at the time its [When Digivolving] effect activates, it doesn\u2019t gain +3000 DP from its effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After having digivolved into this card, I place an [X Antibody] card in this card\u2019s digivolution cards later that turn. Does this Digimon get +3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [WarGreymon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cIf [WarGreymon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Performing the check causes a card to be removed from your opponent\u2019s security stack, causing this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect to trigger. If you flip over a card with a [Security] effect, however, the [Security] effect will trigger afterwards, which means it will activate first.  After that, if there are no other triggered effects, you'll gain 1 memory before the battle with the Security Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent and perform a security check. Does this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect cause me to gain 1 memory first, before the [Security] effect of the card I flipped over activates, or before the battle with my opponent's Security Digimon occurs?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If no Digimon was deleted by this effect\u201d refers to a state in which, when resolving this Digimon\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, your opponent doesn't have a Digimon in play, or you try to delete an opponent's Digimon that can't be deleted with the effect. Essentially, if you didn't delete a Digimon with the effect \u201cDelete 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon with the lowest DP,\u201d follow the instructions listed after \u201cIf no Digimon was deleted by this effect...[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect reads, \u201cDelete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with the lowest DP.\u201d What situations does \u201cIf no Digimon is deleted by this effect\u201d refer to, specifically?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect reads, \u201cDelete,\u201d not \u201cYou may delete,\u201d so if there\u2019s a valid target in play, you must choose it with the effect. You can't choose to NOT activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon in play. Can I choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon with this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect in order to unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When there are multiple Digimon tied for lowest DP, you can choose any of them. This means you can choose the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion to get the \u201cif no Digimon was deleted by this effect\u201d part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent\u2019s effects,\u201d and another Digimon with no effect (both Digimon have the same DP). Can I intentionally choose the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion for this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, in order to unsuspend this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [Gallantmon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif [Gallantmon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect gain me 1 memory per each of my opponent's Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You\u2019ll gain 1 memory for each of your opponent\u2019s Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has multiple Tamers but only 1 Digimon in play, do I gain 1 memory for each of my opponent's Tamers even though only 1 Digimon will be suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may delete that Digimon,\u201d so you can choose not to.  If you choose not to, the effect\u2019s [Once Per Turn] requirement won\u2019t be used up, either.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent\u2019s Digimon with 6000 DP or less becomes suspended, can I choose NOT to delete it with this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When your opponent activates \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, the target of the attack is switched to the Digimon that activated \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, and that Digimon is then deleted by this Digimon's [All Turns] effect.  Since the Digimon that activated \uff1cBlocker\uff1e was deleted, no battle occurs, and the attack ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with a Digimon, and my opponent activates \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend their Digimon with 6000 DP or less. I then activate this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect to delete that Digimon. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes you can, as long as they are simultaneously suspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used an effect like [BT6-103 Blasted Disaster] that suspends multiple DIgimon to simultaneously suspend 2 of my opponent's Digimon with 6000 DP or less.  In such cases, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to delete those 2 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that is correct.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect get Memory +1 for each opponent's tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, memory +1 for the number of tamers on the opponent.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When [When Digivolving] effect of this card, if the opponent has multiple tamers and the opponent has only one Digimon, only one Digimon will be rested, but will the number of tamers be Memory +1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is a \"can be\" effect, so it does not have to be deleted. In that case, the [Once Per Turn] limit is also not consumed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [All Opponent's Turns] effect intentionally not delete when an opponent's Digimon with DP6000 or less is rested?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After blocking, the target of the attack is changed to the blocked Digimon because it is deleted by the card's effect. Since the blocked Digimon has been deleted, no battle takes place and the attack is over.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Against my Digimon's attack, an opponent's Digimon with DP6000 or less blocked and rested, so I deleted that opponent's Digimon with this card's [All Your Turns] effect. In this case, what happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you rested at the same time, it is possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I have rested two opponent's Digimon with DP6000 or less at the same time by an effect that rests multiple Digimon, such as \"BT6-103 Blasted Disaster\". In that case, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to delete those two Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be deleted.[4]",
      "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, an opponent's Digimon with DP6000 or less attacked and this card's [All Opponent's Turns] effect and my opponent's effect triggered at the same time. If the opponent's effect is activated first, and the attacking Digimon reaches DP7000 or more, can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect, which is triggered, delete the Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Garurumon] or [X Antibody] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Garurumon] or [X Antibody], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. In this case, you must add both 1 card with [Garurumon], and 1 [X Antibody] to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If both a card with [Garurumon] and [X Antibody] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an effect returns one of my Digimon to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate an effect that reads \u201c\uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, trash 1 card in your hand.\u201d Even though I trashed a card in my hand, does the \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e allow me to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect requires you to trash two cards in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards that are the same level as each other. The level of this Digimon doesn't matter.  For example, if there are two level 5 cards in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, you can trash both to prevent this Digimon from being deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s inherited effect reads, \u201cyou may trash 2 cards of the same level\u201d. Does this mean I have to trash 2 cards that are the same level as this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s inherited effect reads, \u201cyou may trash 2 cards of the same level\u201d. If this card is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, can I include it as one of the trashed cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [WereGarurumon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif [WereGarurumon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When this card is in your hand, you can activate it by revealing it from your hand during your main phase.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What timing can I activate this card\u2019s [Hand][Main] effect at?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [MetalGarurumon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif [MetalGarurumon] or [X Antibody] is in its digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect activate when this card becomes unsuspended during my unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Option card effects are effects just like any other, so you can't use them to play Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also prevent me from using Option card effects to play Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that only reduce play costs can still be activated.  Effects that reduce play costs AND play Digimon can\u2019t be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, can I activate effects that reduce play costs?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Place it on top of your security stack face down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card's effect to look at the top card of my security stack, and choose not to add it to my hand. What happens to that card?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [Angewomon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif [Angewomon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [RizeGreymon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif [RizeGreymon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will be activated during the Main Phase, by revealing this card from your hand.",
      "question": "Q: When is the timing of this card effect [Hand] [Main] activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reveal this card and not pay the cost. The card will be returned to your hand.",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't want to pay 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must fulfil the condition to reveal this card from your hand.",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't have a Digimon [Justimon]/[Raidenmon]\u00a0in its name in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [Magnadramon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cIf [Magnadramon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cif a card with [Armor Form] in its traits or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. In such cases, this card will be unsuspended when it battles with your opponent's attacking Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect also activate when this card is unsuspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. This card's [Opponent's Turn] effect isn't considered blocking.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect for an attack by an opponent's Digimon with a \"this Digimon can't be blocked\" effect and switch the target of the attack to this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When there are no digivolution cards, you can't perform \"you may place the top card of this Digimon on top of your security stack face down,\" so you can't activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when this card has no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name. You can only add a card whose name is specifically [X Antibody] to your hand. A card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. Can I add a card with [X Antibody] in its traits among those cards to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Insectoid] or [Machine] in its traits or [X Antibody] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Insectoid] or [Machine] in its traits, or [X Antibody], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. In this case, you must add both 1 card with [Insectoid] or [Machine] in its traits, and 1 [X Antibody] to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If both a card with [Insectoid] or [Machine] in its traits and [X Antibody] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Moving a Digimon out of your breeding area does not count as playing a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, can I move one of my level 3 or higher Digimon from my breeding area to my battle area with [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]'s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that only reduce play costs can still be activated.  Effects that reduce play costs AND play Digimon can\u2019t be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in play, can I activate effects that reduce play costs?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Option card effects are effects just like any other, so you can't use them to play Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also prevent me from using Option card effects to play Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name. You can only play a card whose name is specifically [Leomon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s effect play a [Leomon (X Antibody)] from this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also includes the [Leomon] name.  This (Rule) allows this card to be chosen for text that specifies cards with [Leomon].  This (Rule) allows this card to be chosen for text that specifies cards with the name [Leomon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"Treat this card/Digimon as if it also has [Leomon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Leomon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t because this effect specifies the card name and it\u2019s required to meet the condition you have cards with [Okuwamon]/[X Antibody] in its digivolution cards. It does not refer to the traits of the cards.",
      "question": "Q: The effect of \"If you have [Okuwamon]\n"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will be activated during the Main Phase, by revealing this card from your hand.",
      "question": "Q: When is the timing of this card effect [Hand] [Main] activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can reveal this card and not pay the cost. The card will be returned to your hand.",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't want to pay 1 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must fulfil the condition to reveal this card from your hand.",
      "question": "Q: Can I reveal this card in my hand if I don't have a Digimon [Justimon]/[Raidenmon]\u00a0in its name in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect in the middle of an attack to suspend an opponent's Digimon. Can this card's effect then switch the target of attack to one of my opponent\u2019s other suspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is either [GranKuwagamon] or [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cIf [GranKuwagamon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. A \"this Digimon can't be attacked\" effect prevents a Digimon from being chosen as the target upon an attack declaration, therefore an attack can be switched to a Digimon with such an effect by using an effect that switches the target after the attack declaration.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I switch the target of attack to an opponent's Digimon with a \"this Digimon can't be attacked\" effect when I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect during an attack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect specifies a card name, so you must have a card whose name is [X Antibody] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. Having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits doesn't count.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads, \u201cIf a card with [Leomon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards\u201d. Does having a card with [X Antibody] in its traits count?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in the digivolution cards of a Digimon with an effect that adds colors, such as \u201cThis Digimon is also treated as red,\u201d does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's Japanese name (\u30ed\u30fc\u30c0\u30fc\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) has \"Leomon\" (\u30ec\u30aa\u30e2\u30f3) in its name.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have [Leomon]\u00a0in its name?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As long as you have at least 1 of any of the cards listed, you can place 1 of each from your trash under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s [On Play][When Digivolving] effect if I don't have exactly 1 [Raijinmon], 1 [Fuijinmon], and 1 [Suijinmon] in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If there are 4 or more colors present, this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect grants both +3000 DP to this Digimon and <De-Digivolves 1> 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the level 6 cards in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards have 4 or more colors among them, does this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect also grant +3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also includes the [Greymon] name.  This card can be chosen for text that specifies cards with [Greymon].  This card can't be chosen for text that specifies cards with the name [Greymon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"This card/Digimon is also treated as having [Greymon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Greymon].\")"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If both black and red cards are in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, do I get both \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) and \uff1cBlitz\uff1e from this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect unsuspend an opponent\u2019s suspended Digimon or Tamer?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect unsuspend both 1 of my Digimon or Tamers and 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon or Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect lets you unsuspend up to 2 in any combination.  You can unsuspend 1 of each, or 2 Digimon, or 2 Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect let me unsuspend up to 2 Digimon or Tamers in any combination, or does it have to specifically be either 2 Digimon or 2 Tamers only?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Add up the total number of unsuspended Digimon and Tamer cards your opponent has in play, then divide by two to determine how many security cards to trash.  For example, if your opponent has 3 unsuspended Digimon and 1 unsuspended Tamer, this adds up to 4 cards total, which means you get to trash 2 of your opponent\u2019s security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When determining the number of cards to trash from my opponent\u2019s security stack with this card's [End of Your Turn] effect, do I only trash a card for each pair of unsuspended Digimon and Tamer cards my opponent has in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Both the card you add to hand and the card you trash must have [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in their traits.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [On Play] effect reveals cards from the top of my deck. Can I only trash a card that has [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in its traits?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose to either add it to your hand or trash it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [On Play] effect reveals cards from the top of my deck. If only one card has [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in its traits, can I choose whether to add it to my hand or trash it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements. When activating this effect, you can only digivolve into a card with [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in its traits if it also meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have cards in my trash with [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in their traits, does this card's inherited effect let me digivolve any card into any of them, regardless of digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The [When Attacking] effect wasn't present when you declared the attack, so it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect to digivolve into a card with a [When Attacking] effect. Does that effect activate immediately?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements. When activating this effect, you can only digivolve into a card with [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in its traits if it also meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have cards in my trash with [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in their traits, does this card's inherited effect let me digivolve any card into any of them, regardless of digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The [When Attacking] effect wasn't present when you declared the attack, so it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect to digivolve into a card with a [When Attacking] effect. Does that effect activate immediately?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in the digivolution cards of a Digimon with an effect that adds colors, such as \u201cThis Digimon is also treated as red,\u201d does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-076": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. A 2-color card is treated as both colors, so you can activate both effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card\u2019s [On Play][When Digivolving] effect trashes a card that\u2019s both purple and yellow, can I both delete 1 of my opponent\u2019s level 3 Digimon and give 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon -3000 DP for the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is in the digivolution cards of a Digimon with an effect that adds colors, such as \u201cThis Digimon is also treated as red,\u201d does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card can\u2019t digivolve into a card from your trash on its own.  When some other card\u2019s effect digivolves this card into a card from your trash, this card\u2019s effect will then reduce the digivolution cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect let me digivolve into a card in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-079": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements. When activating this effect, you can only digivolve into a card with [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in its traits if it also meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have cards in my trash with [Undead] or [Dark Animal] in their traits, does this card's [End of Attack] effect let me digivolve any card into them, regardless of digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-080": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 1 or fewer security cards, can I still play a purple or yellow Digimon card with 6000 DP or less from my trash with this card\u2019s [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 1 or fewer security cards and activate this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to play a level 6 or lower Digimon card with [Angel] or [Fallen Angel] in its traits, do I play it from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-081": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my trash, is it counted as a card with [Dex] by this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are 5 or more cards with [Dex] in my trash, can I still activate this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect to play a purple or black level 3 Digimon card from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-082": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only this card itself is returned to play. Any digivolution cards it had are placed in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When playing this card from my trash with this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect, does it return to the battle area with any digivolution cards it had prior to being deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It\u2019s treated as a new Digimon that just entered play. Any effects it had prior to being deleted are not carried over.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When playing this card from my trash with this card's [On Deletion] effect, do any effects it had prior to being deleted persist once it re-enters play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-083": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player who controls this card decides.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When placing cards from my opponent's trash at the bottom of their deck with this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, who gets to decide the order of the cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digi-Egg cards in your opponent\u2019s trash can be chosen as part of the effect, but they\u2019re returned to the bottom of your opponent\u2019s Digi-Egg deck instead of their normal deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect let me place Digi-Egg cards from my opponent's trash at the bottom of their deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you have multiple cards with [Mega] in their traits, this effect will only place 10 cards from your opponent's trash at the bottom of their deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are 2 cards with [Mega] in their traits in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, do I get to place 20 cards from my opponent\u2019s trash at the bottom of their deck with this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Place as many cards as you can at the bottom of your opponent\u2019s deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has 9 or fewer cards in their trash, does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must activate this effect at the start of your turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect to avoid trashing any cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.  While there are no cards in your opponent\u2019s security stack to trash, you still perform the part of the effect that reads, \u201cTrash the top card of this Digimon.\u201d[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect activate even when my opponent\u2019s security stack is empty?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When there are no digivolution cards, you can't perform \"trash the top card of this Digimon,\" so it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect activate when this card has no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The [Start of Your Turn] effect on the [BT9-083 Omnimon: Merciful Mode] that was a digivolution card isn't yet in a state where it can activate at the start of your turn, therefore it doesn't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My turn starts when I have this card with [BT9-083 Omnimon: Merciful Mode] as its top digivolution card. If I use this card's [Start of Your Turn] effect to trash this card, then activate the [Start of Your Turn] effect on the [BT9-083 Omnimon: Merciful Mode] that was a digivolution card, can I trash a total of 2 cards from my opponent's security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-084": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you gain 2 memory if both of the conditions are met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 2 memory for this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect if both me and my opponent have 3 or fewer security cards?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you gain 2 memory if both of the conditions are met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 2 memory for this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect if both me and my opponent have 8 or more cards in hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect when one of my blue or red Digimon becomes unsuspended during the unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you gain 2 memory if both of the conditions are met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 2 memory for this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect if both me and my opponent have a level 5 or higher Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you gain 2 memory if both of the conditions are met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 2 memory for this card\u2019s [Start of Your Turn] effect if both me and my opponent have a suspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-090": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Tapirmon] or a 2-color black card is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a [Tapirmon] or a 2-color black card, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Effects don't activate for cards revealed from your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a black Digimon with an effect such as \"this Digimon is also treated as red\" that treats it as a different color is among the cards revealed for this card's effect, can I add that card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait or an Option card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 3 cards. If the cards revealed only include a Digimon card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait or an Option card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. In this situation, you must add both 1 Digimon card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait and 1 Option card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 3 cards. If both a Digimon card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait and an Option Card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the other at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-093": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Main] effect digivolve a Digimon that doesn't meet the digivolution requirements into a Digimon card with [Shoutmon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-094": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to delete my opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 11000 or less with an \"add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-095": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's effect doesn't let you attack with a Digimon that's in a state where it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to attack my opponent with 1 of my Digimon with [Greymon] that is suspended or was played in the same turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [X Antibody] in this effect's text refers to the card name, therefore only a card with [X Antibody] as its card name will meet the condition. It doesn't refer to the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a digivolution card has the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait, does it meet this card's \"if you have a Digimon with [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards in play\" condition?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to attack, does the attacking Digimon's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's effect only allows you to attack a player.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to have one of my opponent's Digimon attack when one of my Digimon with [Greymon] has a \"this Digimon can also attack your opponent's unsuspended Digimon\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [X Antibody] in this effect's text refers to the card name, therefore only a card with [X Antibody] as its card name will meet the condition. It doesn't refer to the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a digivolution card has the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait, does it meet this card's \"if you have a Digimon with [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards in play\" condition?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-100": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's effect doesn't let you attack with a Digimon that's in a state where it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to attack an opponent's Digimon with my Digimon with the [Insectoid]\u00a0trait that was played that turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack one of my opponent's unsuspended Digimon with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to attack an opponent's Digimon with a \"this Digimon can't be attacked\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you activate as many of the effects as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect when my opponent only has a suspended Digimon or a Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect applies to all of your Digimon that meet the conditions, therefore this effect will also affect Digimon that later enter the battle area as long as they meet the conditions.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, do level 6 Digimon with the [Machine]\u00a0trait that are newly played or digivolved in the same turn gain \uff1cRush\uff1e and \uff1cBlitz\uff1e from this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards can't be added to security stacks by your opponent's effects regardless of the card type or level (the effects will activate, but cards still can't be added to security stacks). The \"your opponent's Digimon with play costs of 7 or less\" refers to the \"can't attack players\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"cards can't be added to security stacks by your opponent's effects\" mean that effects that add cards to security stacks on \"your opponent's Digimon with play costs of 7 or less\" can't be activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Due to this card's effect, cards can't be placed in security stacks, therefore [ST10-14 Chaos Degradation]'s \"place 1 of your opponent's Digimon face down at the top or bottom of your opponent's security stack\" can't be activated, and the target Digimon will be left as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if my opponent activates this card's effect and I use [ST10-14 Chaos Degradation]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the rest are placed in the security stack.  When returning cards that were revealed from a private area such as the deck or security stack by an effect, it isn't considered adding cards to such areas, therefore this card's effect doesn't apply.[1]",
      "question": "Q: While my opponent has this card's effect activated, I used [BT10-086 Omnimon (X Antibody)]'s effect to reveal all of my opponent's security cards.  After choosing and trashing 1 card among them, can the rest be placed in the security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into any of the cards revealed from my deck as long as they have the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When choosing the target for \"then, place 1 card with [X Antibody] in its traits from your trash under 1 of your Digimon with [X Antibody] in its traits as its bottom digivolution card\" can I choose a card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait that was revealed from my deck and trashed for this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card from your trash that meets the digivolution requirements and has [Dex].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into any Digimon card from my trash as long as it has [Dex]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the activation conditions are met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate an effect that reduces the digivolution cost when digivolving using this card's [Main] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect only activates \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) on 1 of your opponent's Digimon. For the part of the effect after \"then,\" you can also choose a Digimon other than the target Digimon for \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards).[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Main] effect to trash 2 cards in my hand, can I activate \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) on 2 of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) activates twice, \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 2 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) doesn't activate once.  Even if a Tamer card or Option card becomes the top card after trashing the top card, \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) can trash a card regardless of its card category, therefore you go on to trash the 2nd card. However, if a card with an \"isn't affected by effects\" becomes the top card after the first \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards), it won't be affected by the second \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) and won't be trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to trash 2 cards in my hand, does \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) activate twice or does \uff1cDe-Digivolve  2\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to 2 cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) activate once?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's [Main] effect can place it in a Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, and it has inherited effects.  As with Digi-Egg cards and Digimon cards, this card's inherited effects can activate while it's placed in a Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have inherited effects even though it's an Option card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect digivolve a Digimon that doesn't meet the digivolution requirements into a Digimon card with [X Antibody] in its traits in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the activation conditions are met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate an effect that reduces the digivolution cost when digivolving using this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Trashing by <Digi-Burst> is also trashing by an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card be trashed by <Digi-Burst> effects on Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As with Digimon without DP, this card can't exist in the battle area as the top card, therefore it's trashed. This isn't considered deletion.  If this card has other digivolution cards under it, they are also trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card becomes the top card after a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is affected by \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Effects can't trash this card, therefore only the digivolution card on top of this card is trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if a \"trash the bottom 2 digivolution cards of your opponent's Digimon\" effect activates on a Digimon with this card as its bottom digivolution card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can activate in such cases if you declare to trash 8 cards and then trash 7 cards except for [BT9-109 X Antibody].[1]",
      "question": "Q: There are 8 digivolution cards under [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper], and this card is the bottom card. Does the \"you may trash 7 or more digivolution cards from the bottom of 1 of your [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper]s to set this Digimon's play cost to 0\" effect activate when my [EX2-055 Reaper] is played?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-110": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"if there are 3 or more Digimon in play\" refer to 3 or more total Digimon in play by both me and my opponent?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  When there are 3 or more Digimon in play, you must delete all Digimon without [X Antibody] in their traits.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate just the \"delete 1 Digimon without [X Antibody] in its traits\" effect when there are 3 or more Digimon in play?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. In this case, your turn simply continues without switching over.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card\u2019s [End of Your Turn] effect gains me enough memory to bring the memory gauge to 0 or greater on my side, does it briefly become my opponent\u2019s turn before switching back to my turn again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You're not trashing it, so there\u2019s nothing preventing you from returning it to your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [BT9-109 X Antibody] is in this card\u2019s digivolution cards, can this card\u2019s [End of Your Turn] effect return [BT9-109 X Antibody] from this card\u2019s digivolution cards to the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "BT9-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you reduce its memory cost by 3 based on the total number of Digimon and Tamer cards your opponent has in play.  For example, if your opponent has 2 Digimon and 1 Tamer, this adds up to 3 cards total, which means you get to reduce the play cost by 9.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When playing this card, do I reduce its memory cost by 3 for each pair of Digimon and Tamer cards my opponent has in play?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only add one or the other.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon card with [Agumon] and a Tamer card are among the cards revealed with this card\u2019s inherited effect, can I add both to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I add a non-red Digimon card with [Agumon] or a non-red Tamer card to my hand off this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.   [When Attacking] effects activate before your opponent gets to activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.   [When Attacking] effects activate before your opponent gets to activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect can only play cards specifically named [Tai Kamiya].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play cards that include [Tai Kamiya], like [BT5-093 Tai Kamiya & Matt Ishida], with this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card\u2019s effects aren't activated when you reveal it from your deck with an effect. As such, the card isn't considered to be a green Digimon card, and can\u2019t be added to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is revealed from my deck with an effect like the one on [ST4-03 Tentomon], can I add it to my hand as if it was a green Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If it\u2019s your turn, then yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in my battle area, can I digivolve it into a Digimon with \u201cGreen/Level 4\u201d digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Effects don't activate from breeding areas, so this Digimon isn't treated as green, and you can't digivolve it into a Digimon that requires a green level 4 Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is in my breeding area, can I digivolve it into a Digimon with \u201cGreen/Level 4\u201d digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.   [When Attacking] effects activate before your opponent gets to activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. \uff1cPiercing\uff1e has already activated. Perform the additional check, assuming your Digimon still has \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon that gained \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from another card\u2019s effect, and which also gained \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from this card\u2019s inherited effect. I attack an opponent's Digimon with it, and perform a security check with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. The first card checked has a \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) [Security] effect, which trashes the top card of my attacking Digimon, turning it into a Digimon without [Machine] or [Dragonkin].   This causes the Digimon to also lose \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. Do I still perform the second check?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.   [When Attacking] effects activate before your opponent gets to activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.   [When Attacking] effects activate before your opponent gets to activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon gains \uff1cBlocker\uff1e from an effect or as an inherited effect from one of its digivolution cards, can I delete that Digimon with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.   [When Attacking] effects activate before your opponent gets to activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can only add one or the other.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon card with [Gabumon] and a Tamer card are among the cards revealed with this card\u2019s inherited effect, can I add both to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I add a non-blue Digimon card with [Gabumon] or a non-blue Tamer card to my hand off this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The Digimon is already unsuspended, so this card\u2019s inherited effect doesn\u2019t activate. The Digimon must go from suspended to unsuspended for the effect to activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my main phase, I have an unsuspended Digimon in play with this card in its digivolution cards. If one of my effects unsuspends that Digimon, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect can only play cards that are named [Matt Ishida].",
      "question": "Q: Can I play card with [Matt Ishida]\u00a0in its name like [Tai Kamiya & Matt Ishida] with this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you attack with a Digimon that has this inherited effect while the effect is active, your opponent's Digimon can't change the target of the attack by blocking.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s inherited effect reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be blocked.\u201d How does this effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with [Imperialdramon] and this card in its digivolution cards. Can it attack an opponent\u2019s suspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If your Digimon has the \"...can't be blocked\" effect, your opponent's Digimon can't block or suspend to block. [1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon with [Imperialdramon] and this card in its digivolution cards. Even though I can't block it, can I still try to block with my Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e just to suspend my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 5 cards in hand when activating this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, how much memory do I gain?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon gains an [On Deletion] effect from an effect or as an inherited effect from one of its digivolution cards, can this card's [When Attacking] effect target that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. \u201cFor each color\u201d refers to unique colors.   Blue is a single color, so the effect only grants +1000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 blue cards in my digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect grant +4000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. So long as you had 3 or more security cards at the time you activated this card\u2019s inherited effect, the -2000 DP will persist until the end of the turn, even if you end up with 2 or fewer security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon gets -2000 DP from this card's inherited effect. During the same turn, I end up with 2 or fewer cards in my security stack. Does the -2000 DP granted by this card\u2019s inherited effect go away?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Flipping this card from your security stack reduces your total security cards from 4 to 3, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 4 security cards left. My opponent attacks me with a Digimon, and flips this card from my security stack during their security check. Does <Recovery +1 (Deck)> activate off this card\u2019s [Security] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. So long as you had 3 or more security cards at the time you activated this card\u2019s inherited effect, the +1000 DP will persist until the end of your opponent\u2019s next turn, even if you end up with 2 or fewer security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon gets +1000 DP from this card's inherited effect. During the same turn, I end up with 2 or fewer cards in my security stack. Does the +1000 DP granted by this card\u2019s inherited effect go away?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. <Recovery +1 (Deck)> added a card to your security, so you gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon in play with this card in its digivolution cards. [BT1-087 T.K. Takaishi]\u2019s effect adds a yellow card from my security stack to my hand, and adds a card to my security stack with <Recovery +1 (Deck)>. The number of cards in my security stack ultimately remained the same, but can I still gain 1 memory from this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. So long as you had 3 or more security cards at the time you activated this card\u2019s inherited effect, the effect will persist until the end of your opponent\u2019s next turn, even if you end up with 2 or fewer security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon gets +4000 DP from its effect. During the same turn, I end up with 2 or fewer cards in my security stack. Does the +4000 DP granted by this card\u2019s effect go away?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect gives \u201call of your opponent\u2019s Security Digimon -3000 DP for the turn,\u201d so every Security Digimon flipped over for the duration of the turn gets -3000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon\u2019s attack ends and I attack my opponent with another Digimon. Does this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect still give my opponent\u2019s Security Digimon -3000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. So long as you had 3 or more security cards at the time you activated this card\u2019s effect, the effect will persist until the end of the turn, even if you end up with 2 or fewer security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After giving 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon and all of my opponent\u2019s Security Digimon -3000 DP, I end up with 2 or fewer security cards. Does this card\u2019s -3000 DP effect go away?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve this card while it\u2019s unsuspended. Can I still trash the top card of my security stack with this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When any one of your Digimon digivolves, as long as it meets the requirements, the memory cost of the digivolution is reduced by 1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect reduce the digivolution costs of my other Digimon, or just the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. As long as it\u2019s the same turn, the effect will persist until you digivolve into a Digimon card with [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in its traits.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect, then digivolve into a Digimon without [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in its traits. Does this waste the inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Reduce the digivolution cost by 1 for each time that Digimon attacked during the same turn. However, once you digivolve into a Digimon card that has [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in its traits, the accumulated digivolution cost reductions from this effect will be reset.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards somehow attacks 2 or more times in the same turn, does the -1 digivolution cost reduction stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't reduce the memory cost of digivolutions performed in your breeding area with this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I reduce the memory cost of digivolutions in my breeding area with this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only reduces the memory cost by 1 when digivolving one of your Digimon into a Digimon card in your hand with [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect].[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I digivolve a Digimon with [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in my battle area into another Digimon, does this card\u2019s inherited effect reduce the memory cost of that digivolution by 1?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the time to trigger [When Attacking] effects has already passed, so the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve using this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect. If the Digimon I digivolve into has a [When Attacking] effect, does that effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues. The turn doesn\u2019t switch over until the attack has ended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with this card's [When Attacking] effect, paying the digivolution cost moves the memory gauge to 1 or more on my opponent\u2019s side. What happens to the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \uff1cPiercing\uff1e has already activated. Perform the additional check, assuming your Digimon still has \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon that gained \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from another card\u2019s effect, and which also gained \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from this card\u2019s inherited effect. I attack an opponent's Digimon with it, and perform a security check with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. The first card checked has a \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) [Security] effect, which trashes the top card of my attacking Digimon, turning it into a Digimon without [Free] in its traits or [Imperialdramon].   This causes the Digimon to also lose \uff1cPiercing\uff1e. Do I still perform the second check?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The attack continues, but the turn doesn't switch over yet.   If the memory gauge is still at 1 or more on your opponent\u2019s side after the attack has ended and all effects triggered by it have been activated, only then does the turn end.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving with this card's [When Attacking] effect, paying the digivolution cost moves the memory gauge to 1 or more on my opponent\u2019s side. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the time to trigger [When Attacking] effects has already passed, so the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with [EX1-035 Kabuterimon] and digivolve into this card with its [When Attacking] effect. Can I then digivolve again during the same attack with this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \u201cThis Digimon can digivolve,\u201d so you can choose not to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a card in hand with [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in its traits, does this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect force me to digivolve when attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore its digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into a Digimon card with [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in its traits in my hand with this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect, can I ignore that card's digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It doesn't matter which of your Digimon is the one deleting the opponent's Digimon in battle and surviving. As long as it has [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in its traits, you can unsuspend this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon's effect unsuspend this Digimon when any of my Digimon with [Insectoid] or [Ancient Insect] in their traits deletes an opponent's Digimon in battle and survives?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It\u2019s not referring to this card\u2019s name, but the name of the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \u201cthe same name as this Digimon\u201d refer to Digimon with the name [Keramon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It\u2019s not referring to this card\u2019s name, but the name of the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \u201cthe same name as this Digimon\u201d refer to Digimon with the name [Kurisarimon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may,\u201d so you can choose not to activate it.   However, after revealing cards from the top of your deck, you must perform the rest of the effect to the best of your ability.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect when digivolving?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may,\u201d so you can choose not to activate it.   However, after revealing cards from the top of your deck, you must perform the rest of the effect to the best of your ability.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect when digivolving?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may,\u201d so you can choose not to activate it.   However, after revealing cards from the top of your deck, you must perform the rest of the effect to the best of your ability.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect when digivolving?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn't count Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect activate when an opponent\u2019s Digimon in their breeding area digivolves into a level 5 or higher Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It\u2019s not referring to this card\u2019s name, but the name of the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \u201cthe same name as this Digimon\u201d refer to Digimon with the name [Infermon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this Digimon is deleted before its effect can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent digivolves one of their Digimon into a level 5 or higher Digimon, and deletes this Digimon with its [When Digivolving] effect. Do I gain 1 memory from this Digimon's [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn\u2019t activate for Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is in my breeding area. If I digivolve it into a Digimon card with [Etemon] in my hand, is the memory cost of the digivolution reduced by 1?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple Digimon are deleted simultaneously, you can't draw more than 1 card per turn with this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a single effect deletes 2 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon, do I draw 2 cards with this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack my opponent when I don't have a Digimon with [Myotismon] in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect only prevents you from declaring an opponent's Digimon as the target of the attack. If this Digimon is blocked, conduct the battle between the two Digimon as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon while I don't have a Digimon with [Myotismon] in play, and it\u2019s blocked by an opponent\u2019s Digimon. What happens?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect return this card to its owner's hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must return a card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When activating this card\u2019s inherited effect, am I required to return a level 4 or lower Digimon card from my trash to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may,\u201d so you can choose not to activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect when digivolving?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect doesn\u2019t activate for Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon is in my breeding area. If I digivolve it into a Digimon card with [Myotismon] in my hand, is the memory cost of the digivolution reduced by 1?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card is no longer in play at the end of the attack, so the [End of Attack] effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon and flip over [BT2-105 Spider Shooter] during the security check. The \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) trashes this card. Does this card\u2019s [End of Attack] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect can only play cards whose names are specifically [Agumon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Deletion] effect play an [Agumon Expert] or an [Agumon - Bond of Bravery] from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Attacking] effect play a purple level 4 or lower Digimon card with \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e as its inherited effect from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if multiple Digimon are deleted simultaneously, you can't draw more than 1 card per turn with this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon's [On Play] effect deletes 4 of my opponent's Digimon. Does this Digimon\u2019s [Your Turn] effect cause me to draw 4 cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If your [Diaboromon] was deleted by a [When Attacking] effect, your [Diaboromon] Token will have already lost \uff1cBlocker\uff1e by the time you reach blocker timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon and a [Diaboromon] Token in my battle area. My opponent attacks with a Digimon, and deletes this Digimon with a [When Attacking] effect. Can I block the attack with my [Diaboromon] Token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The [Security] effect activates as soon as the card is flipped during the security check, which means you can play the Token regardless of the battle's outcome.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play a Token with this card\u2019s [Security] effect at the end of the battle even if this card loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The Token is played first. Once all [Security] effects and effects triggered by battle have been activated, proceed to the next security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is the Token played off this Digimon\u2019s [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You can't hatch a Digi-Egg card, however.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my level 5 or higher Digimon with a digivolution card is deleted. Can I suspend this Tamer and gain 1 memory with this card's [All Turns] effect even if my breeding area isn't empty?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it deletes a single Digimon that fulfils both conditions.",
      "question": "Q: Does this card delete 1 Digimon that has both \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and 1 Digimon with 6000 DP or less each?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent loses the 2 memory. The memory marker will be moved 2 spaces towards you every time your opponent attacks with a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card, do I lose 2 memory every time my opponent attacks with a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cAll of your opponent\u2019s Digimon,\u201d so any Digimon that enter the battle area after you use this card are still affected.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card. During my opponent\u2019s next turn, if they play a new Digimon or move a Digimon from their breeding area to their battle area, will those Digimon have \u201c[When Attacking] Loses 2 memory\u201d from this card\u2019s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if you have 1 or more memory, the attack with \uff1cBlitz\uff1e still takes place during your opponent's turn, which means that this card's effect is still active, and your opponent still loses 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card. During my opponent\u2019s next turn, they attack me with their Digimon's \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect while I have 1 or more memory. Does my opponent still lose 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can trash a red Digimon card to reduce the digivolution cost.   The card you can trash with this effect must match the color of the Digimon performing the digivolution in your battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I digivolve a red Digimon into a white Digimon card. What color card can I trash from my hand to reduce the memory cost of the digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect can't reduce digivolution costs of Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I\u2019m digivolving a Digimon in my breeding area. Can I reduce the digivolution cost by 4 with this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During the turn I use this card, if I have a blue Digimon in my battle area with an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon is also treated as red,\u201d can I trash a red Digimon card in my hand to reduce the digivolution cost by 4?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You don't trash the card in your hand with this effect until you digivolve. [BT7-085 Takuya Kanbara]\u2019s [Main] effect reads, \u201cYou may place 5 cards with [Hybrid] in their traits from your trash under this Tamer in any order,\u201d and is used to digivolve into [EmperorGreymon]. As such, you place the cards under [Takuya Kanbara] before you begin digivolving, at which point you can trash a card in your hand with this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, I activate [BT7-085 Takuya Kanbara]\u2019s [Main] effect. Can I use this card's effect specifically to trash cards with [Hybrid] in their traits from my hand, so that I can place them under [Takuya Kanbara] using its effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The card you trash can match any one of the Digimon\u2019s colors.   For example, when digivolving a blue/green Digimon, you can trash either a blue or a green card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving from a multicolor Digimon, what color cards can I trash with this card\u2019s effect to reduce the digivolution cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The card you trash can match any of the colors of either Digimon. For example, when DNA digivolving a blue Digimon and green Digimon, you can trash either a blue or green card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I reduce the memory cost of a DNA digivolution with this card's effect?   If I can, what color cards can I trash with this card\u2019s effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this card, can I reduce the digivolution cost of my digivolving Digimon by trashing 1 Digimon card in the hand with the same color when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. An Option card\u2019s [Security] effect is not considered to be the same thing as using an Option card, so it activates normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, then attack my opponent. If an Option card with a [Security] effect is flipped over during the security check, does its effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Activating \uff1cDelay\uff1e on an Option card that was already placed in your battle area is not considered to be the same thing as using an Option card, so it activates normally.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent uses this card and passes the turn back to me. Can I activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e on an Option card that was already placed in my battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX1-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Cards that meet all of the conditions below and have unique card numbers can be placed in this card\u2019s Digivolution cards with this card's [On Play] effect. -The cards must be in your hand or trash. -The cards must have [Cyborg] in their traits. -The cards must be red or black Digimon cards. -The cards must be level 5 Digimon cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can you explain in detail which cards I can place in this card\u2019s digivolution cards with this card\u2019s [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cYou may trash,\u201d so you can choose not to trash any cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card is deleted, can I choose not to trash 2 of its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When you use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast]\u2019s effect, it changes the cost paid to the number of cards in your security stack, but doesn't change the cost of the card itself. As such, the game considers you to have used an Option card with a cost of 5, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 card in my security stack. If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast], can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that use Option cards without paying their costs are skipping the costs entirely, not changing them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use an Option card with a cost of 2 or more by an effect that reads, \u201cUse an Option card without paying its cost.\u201d Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when my opponent suspends a Digimon by blocking?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card is a Digi-Egg card, so it goes in your Digi-Egg deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card go in my deck, or my Digi-Egg deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It\u2019s placed in your breeding area as a level-less Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I hatch this card during my breeding phase, do I place it in my breeding area, or my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve it into other cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can be moved from your breeding area to your battle area like any other Digimon.  Level 2 Digimon don't have DP, and therefore can't be moved to your battle area. This card has DP, which means it can be moved to your battle area without digivolving it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my breeding area, how do I move it to my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t activate effects in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my breeding area, can I activate its [Main] effect to place my [ADR-02 Searcher] in its digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  \u201cThis Digimon can also attack unsuspended Digimon\u201d is an effect that only affects the Digimon that has it, so this card's \u201cThis Digimon [...] isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\u201d effect can\u2019t be used to prevent the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can it be attacked by my opponent\u2019s Digimon with an effect that reads \u201cThis Digimon can also attack unsuspended Digimon\u201d?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card can be deleted as a result of battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is in my battle area. If an opponent\u2019s Digimon attacks it, and this card\u2019s DP is less than or equal to the opponent\u2019s Digimon, is this card deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this card is affected by effects you activate. [1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this Digimon affected by effects like \u201cDelete 1 of your Digimon,\u201d or \u201cSuspend 1 of your Digimon\u201d that I activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, since this card is a Digi-Egg card, note that if this card would be moved to your hand, deck, or security stack, it\u2019s instead placed at the bottom of your Digi-Egg deck face down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is in my battle area, can my own effects delete it or move it to my hand/deck/security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play two cards with [D-Reaper] in their traits, can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect for the first card, and activate it for the second?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT8-071 Psychemon]\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t target Digimon themselves, so you can\u2019t activate this card's effect to reduce the play cost of cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has [BT8-071 Psychemon] in play. Can this Digimon\u2019s [Your Turn] effect still reduce the play cost of cards with [D-Reaper] in their traits when I would play them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card is a Digi-Egg card, so if it would be moved to your security stack, it\u2019s instead placed at the bottom of your Digi-Egg deck face down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use [BT4-105 Tactical Retreat!] on this card, can I place it on top of my security stack face down?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I specify my opponent\u2019s [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] as the target of an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It\u2019s only this Digimon that isn't affected. The other Digimon will be affected as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an effect that targets multiple Digimon is also targeting my opponent's [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper], is the effect canceled, preventing it from affecting the other targeted Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You will only place the topmost [ADR-02 Searcher] in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. All of [ADR-02 Searcher]\u2019s digivolution cards are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have an [ADR-02 Searcher] with 1 or more digivolution cards in play. If I place it in this Digimon's digivolution cards with this card's [Main] effect, do I also get to place [ADR-02 Searcher]\u2019s digivolution cards under it as well?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can activate in such cases if you declare to trash 8 cards and then trash 7 cards except for [X Antibody].[1]",
      "question": "Q: There are 8 digivolution cards under this card, and [BT9-109 X Antibody] is the bottom card. Does the \"you may trash 7 or more digivolution cards from the bottom of 1 of your [Mother D-Reaper]s to set this Digimon's play cost to 0\" effect activate when my [EX2-055 Reaper] is played?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Growlmon] or [Takato Matsuki] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Growlmon] or [Takato Matsuki], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] and 1 [Takato Matsuki] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. In this case, you must add both 1 card with [Growlmon], and 1 [Takato Matsuki] to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with [Growlmon] and [Takato Matsuki] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It adds 1000 to the maximum DP you can choose with all of your effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect add 1000 to the maximum DP I can choose with other effects, or just the effects on the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  If you have a red Tamer in play, you can choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 8000 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is this card\u2019s [When Attacking] \u201cChoose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 6000 or less and delete them\u201d effect also affected by its \u201cadd 2000 to the maximum DP you can choose with DP-based deletion effects\u201d effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \u201cadd 2000 to the maximum DP you can choose with DP-based deletion effects\u201d effect also raise the maximum DP I can choose with other deletion effects besides those on this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If no Digimon was deleted by this effect\u201d refers to a state in which, when resolving this Digimon\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, your opponent doesn't have a Digimon with 10000 DP or less in play, or you try to delete an opponent's suitable Digimon can't be deleted with the effect. Essentially, if you didn't delete a Digimon by \u201cDelete 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 10000 DP or less,\u201d follow the instructions listed after \u201cIf no Digimon was deleted by this effect...[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect reads \u201cDelete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 10000 DP or less. If no Digimon was deleted by this effect...\u201d What situations does \u201cIf no Digimon was deleted by this effect\u201d refer to, specifically?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If there\u2019s a valid target in play, you must choose it with the effect.  You can't choose to NOT activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 10000 DP or less in play. Can I choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon with this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect so we both trash the top 5 cards of our deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can choose your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 10000 DP or less as a target, even if the chosen Digimon has an effect that prevents it from being deleted, in order to get the \u201cif no Digimon was deleted by this effect\u201d part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 10000 DP or less and an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent\u2019s effects,\u201d and another Digimon with 10000 DP or less but no effect. Can I intentionally have this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect target the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion to have us both trash the top 5 cards of our decks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [EX2-008 Guilmon]\u2019s [On Play] effect reveals this card from my deck, can I add it to my hand as a card that has [Gallantmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The Digimon chosen as a target for this effect is not deleted, and the Digimon that activates \uff1cDecoy (nocategory)\uff1e (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) is deleted by the effect of \uff1cDecoy (nocategory)\uff1e (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) and not this effect. As such, the condition is satisfied for \"if no Digimon was deleted by this effect,\" and both players will trash the top 5 cards of their decks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I try to delete an opponent's Digimon with this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect, and my opponent activates \uff1cDecoy (nocategory)\uff1e (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) to prevent the chosen Digimon from being deleted. If the Digimon that activated \uff1cDecoy (nocategory)\uff1e (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) is deleted, does the \u201cif no Digimon was deleted by this effect\u201d part of this card's effect still activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [ChaosGallantmon] name.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [ChaosGallantmon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [ChaosGallantmon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect can only increase the number of cards in your security stack to 5 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 5 cards in my security stack. Can I still <Recovery +1 (Deck)> with this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Kyubimon], [Taomon], or [Sakuyamon] or [Rika Nonaka] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Kyubimon], [Taomon], or [Sakuyamon] or [Rika Nonaka], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. If both a card with [Kyubimon], [Taomon], or [Sakuyamon] and [Rika Nonaka] are among the cards revealed, you must add both to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with [Kyubimon], [Taomon], or [Sakuyamon] and [Rika Nonaka] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When you use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast]\u2019s effect, it changes the cost paid to the number of cards in your security stack, but doesn't change the cost of the card itself. As such, the game considers you to have used an Option card with a cost of 5, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 card in my security stack. If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast], can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that use Option cards without paying their costs are skipping the costs entirely, not changing them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use an Option card with a cost of 2 or more by an effect that reads, \u201cUse an Option card without paying its cost.\u201d Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When you use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast]\u2019s effect, it changes the cost paid to the number of cards in your security stack, but doesn't change the cost of the card itself. As such, the game considers you to have used an Option card with a cost of 5, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 card in my security stack. If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast], can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that use Option cards without paying their costs are skipping the costs entirely, not changing them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use an Option card with a cost of 2 or more by an effect that reads, \u201cUse an Option card without paying its cost.\u201d Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a [Shu-Chong Wong], can I digivolve one of my [Lopmon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this card evolves under the effect \"While my \"Shu-Chong Wong\" is present, my \"Lop Mon\" can evolve to this card in my hand at an evolution cost of 3, ignoring the evolution requirements\", can I use effects such as \"EX1-071 Sixty percent Shourei! etc., can I minus the cost of digivolves?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[3]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the effect to digivolve my Digimon from my \"Lopmon\" in the Battle Area to this card in my hand while I have my \"Shu-Chong Wong\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When you use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast]\u2019s effect, it changes the cost paid to the number of cards in your security stack, but doesn't change the cost of the card itself. As such, the game considers you to have used an Option card with a cost of 5, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 card in my security stack. If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast], can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that use Option cards without paying their costs are skipping the costs entirely, not changing them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use an Option card with a cost of 2 or more by an effect that reads, \u201cUse an Option card without paying its cost.\u201d Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. When you use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast]\u2019s effect, it changes the cost paid to the number of cards in your security stack, but doesn't change the cost of the card itself. As such, the game considers you to have used an Option card with a cost of 5, allowing you to activate this card\u2019s inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 1 card in my security stack. If I use [BT7-100 Qualialise Blast], can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Effects that use Option cards without paying their costs are skipping the costs entirely, not changing them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use an Option card with a cost of 2 or more by an effect that reads, \u201cUse an Option card without paying its cost.\u201d Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card also trigger when the opponent's Digimon activates a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and suspends?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card also trigger when the opponent's Digimon activates a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and suspends?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it works.",
      "question": "Q: Does the inherited effect of this card also trigger when the opponent's Digimon activates a \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and suspends?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They're trashed.  Only this card will be placed in your Digimon's digivolution cards by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card\u2019s [End of Attack] effect, I place this Digimon under one of my other Digimon as its bottom digivolution card. What happens to the digivolution cards under this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [End of Attack] effect place this card under one of my Digimon that doesn't have a level?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate both.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has two inherited effects. If this card becomes a digivolution card, can I activate both effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's Japanese [End of Attack] effect was corrected so that the target is \"your other Digimon.\"  Please see the notices regarding changes to the rules/rulings on the official website.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Attack] effect on this Digimon itself to place this card under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you have 4 or more Tamers in play, you can only gain 1 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 black Tamers in play, can I gain 2 memory from this card\u2019s inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you don't have any Tamers in play, \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still activates as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has gained \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from an effect. I have no Tamers in play, and this card attacks and deletes an opponent\u2019s Digimon in battle and survives. Do I perform a security check due to \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If your Digimon is blocked by an opponent\u2019s Digimon, the two Digimon battle as normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, what happens?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) an opponent\u2019s Digimon when it unsuspends during my opponent\u2019s unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you choose one of those Digimon to \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards).[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my opponent\u2019s unsuspend phase, more than one of my opponent's Digimon become unsuspended. Do I choose which Digimon to \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) with this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent\u2019s Digimon becomes unsuspended, can I choose not to activate this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect to \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) that Digimon in order to preserve the effect\u2019s [Once Per Turn] limit?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) activates even if the opponent's Digimon that becomes unsuspended is level 3 or has no digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent unsuspends a Digimon that has no digivolution cards or is level 3. Can I choose not to activate the \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) from this card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have no Tamers in play, the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect still activate even if I have no Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You can activate the same [When Digivolving] effect as many times as you have Tamers in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple Tamers in play, can I activate the same [When Digivolving] effect multiple times with this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [Beelzemon] or [Ai & Mako] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [Beelzemon] or [Ai & Mako], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. In this case, you must add both 1 card with [Beelzemon], and 1 [Ai & Mako] to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with [Beelzemon] and [Ai & Mako] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the top of your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An effect that reads, \u201cReveal a card from your deck\u201d reveals this card and trashes it. Does this card's \u201cWhen this card is trashed from your deck\u201d effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This effect specifies a specific card number (EX2-039 Impmon), so as long as the effect is from a card with a different card number, the effect will activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the effect of [BT2-068 Impmon] trashes this card from my deck, does this card\u2019s \u201cWhen this card is trashed from your deck\u201d effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Both players decide which cards to trash from their own hands.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player decides which cards are trashed from hand by this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It activates after you draw.  [When Digivolving] effects trigger after a player finishes drawing the digivolution bonus card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activate before or after drawing the digivolution bonus card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If you have 5 or fewer cards in hand, you don't trash any cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect work when I have 5 or fewer cards in hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the top of your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An effect that reads, \u201cReveal a card from your deck\u201d reveals this card and trashes it. Does this card's \u201cWhen this card is trashed from your deck\u201d effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the effect can be activated both [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking].  You can activate it as a [When Digivolving] effect when you digivolve this Digimon, then reactivate it as a [When Attacking] effect by attacking with this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has an effect that activates at both [When Digivolving] and [When Attacking] timings. What does this mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a specific rule that allows you to include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"You can include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck\" has been changed to \"(Rule) You can include up to 50 copies of cards with this card's card number in your deck\")"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The inherent rule is that you can have up to 50 of these cards in your deck.[3]",
      "question": "Q: What are the <Rules> specific to this card? (*This card's \"Rule: Up to 50 cards with the same card number as this card may be placed in the deck. is changed to \"<Overflow X> You can put up to 50 cards with the same card number as this card in your deck. changed to \"Rule: You can put up to 50 cards with the same card number as this card in your deck.)"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a card with [D-Reaper] in its traits or [ADR-02 Searcher] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include either a card with [D-Reaper] in its traits or [ADR-02 Searcher], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 card [...] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add both a card with [D-Reaper] in its traits and [ADR-02 Searcher] to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with [D-Reaper] in its traits and [ADR-02 Searcher] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, I add to my hand whenever possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this card add the target card to the hand whenever possible if it is among the cards revealed from the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If you do, place all revealed cards at the bottom of your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s effect when I don't have a [Mother D-Reaper] in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be activated. The [Main] effect of this card can be activated even when \"Mother De Reaper\" is not present.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Main] effect be activated when my \"Mother De Reaper\" is not in the Battle Area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's effect plays a Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card\u2019s [Opponent's Turn] effect gives your opponent\u2019s attacking Digimon <Security Attack -1> before the second security check, so the second security check does not occur, and the attack ends.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent\u2019s Digimon with <Security Attack+1> attacks me directly, and this card is flipped over during the first security check and played in my battle area by its [Security] effect. If I have a [Mother D-Reaper] with 6 or more digivolution cards in play, can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect prevent my opponent's second security check?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. From the time it plays by this effect, it is treated as a normal Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Are Digimons played by the effect of this card treated as Security Digimon in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates \u226aSecurity Attack-1\u226b on the attacking opponent's Digimon by this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect before the second check, so the second check is not performed and the attack is over.[2]",
      "question": "Q: \u226aAn opponent's Digimon with \"Security Attack +1\" attacked a player, and this card was turned over on the first check and played in the Battle Area under the [Security] effect. If there is my \"Mother De Reaper\" with 6 or more digivolution cards, can this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect prevent the opponent's second check?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Cards that don't have levels can't be digivolved from, and you can't digivolve into this card. (Other than through special digivolutions.)[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card doesn't have a level. Can I still digivolve into it and into other cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reads \u201cyou may trash 7 or more digivolution cards from the bottom of 1 of your [Mother D-Reaper]s,\u201d but can I choose to trash 8 or more digivolution cards when playing this card.?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can activate in such cases if you declare to trash 8 cards and then trash 7 cards except for [X Antibody].[1]",
      "question": "Q: There are 8 digivolution cards under [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper], and [BT9-109 X Antibody] is the bottom card. Does the \"you may trash 7 or more digivolution cards from the bottom of 1 of your [Mother D-Reaper]s to set this Digimon's play cost to 0\" effect activate when this card is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. If you can destroy at least 7 cards from the bottom of the digivolution cards, excluding cards that cannot be destroyed, the play cost you pay will be 0.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I am in a situation where I have 8 cards, including one BT9-109 X antibody, as the digivolution card for my EX2-007 Mother De Reaper. When I play this card, can I activate the first effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card's effect reads \"when [...] would digivolve into,\" so the effect interrupts the digivolution when it activates. Therefore, it activates first and gives that Digimon \uff1cBlitz\uff1e even if the digivolution later fails.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon would digivolve into a Digimon with [Gallantmon], if I can no longer pay the digivolution cost due to the inherited effect on my opponent's [EX3-016 SnowAgumon] or [EX3-019 Paledramon] and the digivolution fails, does the Digimon from the attempted digivolution still gain the [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect from this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate for Digimon in breeding areas.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s effect when a Digimon in my breeding area digivolves into a level 5 or level 6 card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can't continue the digivolution, and the level 6 Digimon card returns to your hand. The level 5 Digimon is deleted and no digivolution cost is paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my level 5 Digimon would digivolve into a level 6 and I delete that level 5 Digimon with this card's effect, what happens?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card can only be activated when you attack with a card explicitly named [Beelzemon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with my [Beelzemon Blast Mode]. Can I activate this card\u2019s [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used [ST14-02 Impmon] to attack, and its [When Attacking] effect digivolved it into [Beelzemon] from my trash. At such times, can I use this card's effect to again digivolve [Beelzemon] into [Beelzemon: Blast Mode] in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect doesn't read \u201cyou may,\u201d so if a Digimon with 3000 DP or less is in play, you must choose it as part of the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has a Digimon with 3000 DP or less in play, can I choose not to delete an opponent\u2019s Digimon intentionally but still \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve into a Digimon card with a special digivolution costing 3 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads \u201cYou may digivolve 1 of your Digimon,\u201d so you can\u2019t use it to DNA Digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to DNA Digivolve into a Digimon card with a DNA Digivolution costing 3 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads \u201cYou may digivolve 1 of your Digimon,\u201d so you can\u2019t use it to digivolve a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve one of my Tamers into a Digimon that can digivolve from Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can't ignore digivolution requirements unless some other effect that permits you to do so.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I ignore digivolution requirements when digivolving by the effect of this card, as long as the cost is 3 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a card in my hand with an effect that reads \u201c1 of your Digimon may digivolve into this card in your hand for a digivolution cost of 3.\u201d Can I use this card\u2019 to digivolve into it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, those effects are only active when the digivolution is taking place, which means they reduce the digivolution cost after a player has announced a digivolution. As such, at the time this card's effect is activated, the digivolution cost hasn't been reduced, and you can't choose the card with this card\u2019s effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate effects that reduce digivolution costs like <Digisorption> or [EX1-071 Win Rate: 60%!] to reduce the digivolution cost of a card in my hand from 4 or more to 3 or less, and then use this card to digivolve into it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if the card has a digivolution requirement with a cost of 3, if you want to digivolve off the requirement with a cost of 4, you can\u2019t use this card to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon card with multiple digivolution requirements: one with a digivolution cost of 3, and one with a digivolution cost of 4. Can I use this card to digivolve into that Digimon card and apply the requirement with a cost of 4?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the top of your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An effect that reads, \u201cReveal a card from your deck\u201d reveals this card and trashes it. Does this card's \u201cWhen this card is trashed from your deck\u201d effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After revealing cards from my deck with this card\u2019s effect, can I choose the card I digivolve into from among them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I ignore digivolution requirements when digivolving by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to digivolve into a Digimon card with a special digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \u201cYou may,\u201d so you can choose not to digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card and reveal a Digimon card I can digivolve into, can I intentionally choose not to digivolve into it and add it to my hand instead?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the cards weren't being flipped over by a security check, so their [Security] effects don't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do cards trashed from my opponent\u2019s security stack by this card's [When Attacking] effect activate their [Security] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has 1 or more cards in their security stack. I attack my opponent with this Digimon and its [When Attacking] effect trashes their last security cards, leaving them with zero cards in their security stack. If the attack isn't blocked and my attack is successful when they have zero cards in their security stack, do I win the game?"
    }
  ],
  "EX2-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from the top of your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An effect that reads, \u201cReveal a card from your deck\u201d reveals this card and trashes it. Does this card's \u201cWhen this card is trashed from your deck\u201d effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if both Digimon are deleted simultaneously, the effects activate one at a time. When the first Salamon's effect activates, you add 1 card to your security stack, bringing the total up to 4.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If that Digimon is already unsuspended, does an effect that reads \"unsuspend 1 of your Digimon\" activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [Dragonkin] is included.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"[Dragon], [saur] or [Ceratopsian] in one of its traits\" mean that this effect's targets include [Dragonkin] in addition to [Dragon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [Dragonkin] is included.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"[Dragon], [saur] or [Ceratopsian] in one of its traits\" mean that this effect's targets include [Dragonkin] in addition to [Dragon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with the [Rock Dragon], [Earth Dragon], [Bird Dragon], [Machine Dragon], or [Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait or a [Hina Kurihara] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include 1 card with the [Rock Dragon], [Earth Dragon], [Bird Dragon], [Machine Dragon], or [Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait or a [Hina Kurihara], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card [...] and 1 [Hina Kurihara] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with the [Rock Dragon], [Earth Dragon], [Bird Dragon], [Machine Dragon], or [Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait and a [Hina Kurihara] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to DNA digivolve, and this caused the memory gauge to move to my opponent's side. This brought the end of the turn. Can I use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the target original \"1 of your other Digimon\" for this effect does not have to be purple.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into a level 4 purple Digimon, does my other Digimon have to be purple?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [Dragonkin] is included.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"[Dragon], [saur] or [Ceratopsian] in one of its traits\" mean that this effect's targets include [Dragonkin] in addition to [Dragon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot unsuspend a Digimon if this card is not deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is chosen to be deleted by [BT5-106 Demonic Disaster], if it uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion do I still get to unsuspend a Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As the requirement of \"when this Digimon attacks and deletes an opponent's Digimon and survives the battle\" of \uff1cPiercing\uff1e was not met, it does not activate.[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e attacked my Digimon, and my Digimon lost the battle. I then activate my Digimon's [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. What happens to my opponent's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, because the Digimon will still have \uff1cPiercing\uff1e and it deleted a Digimon battle and survived it will trigger.[2]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e gained from [BT8-103 Lightning Blade] and battles a Digimon with equal DP. I activate its [All Turns] effect to prevent it from being deleted. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it lost \uff1cPiercing\uff1e before the timing it would trigger and if it doesn't trigger it cannot activate.[3]",
      "question": "Q: This card has \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from [EX1-008 MetalGreymon] in its digivolution cards, this card attacks a Digimon with equal DP and uses its [All Turns] effect to prevent its deletion by trashing [EX1-008 MetalGreymon]. Does \uff1cPiercing\uff1e still trigger?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It performs \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e 3 times on the same Digimon. So you must do as much as you can.[4]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  3\uff1e on 1 of my opponent's Digimon, or does it perform \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e 3 times on the same Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e will be activated three times. Even if the top card becomes a Tamer or Option card, the top card will continue to be trashed by \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e.[5]",
      "question": "Q: If I place 3 cards under this Digimon for its [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect and target a Digimon for \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e that has a Tamer or Option card as its topmost digivolution source, will this effect \uff1cDe-Digivolve\uff1e past the Tamer or Option card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [Dragonkin] is included.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"[Dragon], [saur] or [Ceratopsian] in one of its traits\" mean that this effect's targets include [Dragonkin] in addition to [Dragon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the  \"1 of your blue Digimon\" that you select with this card's [On Play] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"that Digimon\" on this card refer to the \"1 of your blue Digimon\" or does it refer to this card when played from digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the inherited effect activates for each of the 2 Digimon, so the digivolution cost increases by a total of 2.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 Digimon in this card's digivolution cards, and my opponent's Digimon digivolves with no digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution cost only increases by 1. This card's inherited effect reads \"When an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards would digivolve,\" so even in the case of a DNA digivolution where there are 2 of the target opponent's Digimon, the digivolution cost only increases by 1 with this effect because the digivolution only occurs once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: 2 of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards DNA digivolve when my Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution cost increases by 1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: 1 of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards and 1 of my opponent's Digimon with digivolution cards DNA digivolves when my Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution cost increases by 1. [BT4-011 Agunimon]'s effect reads \"You may Digivolve this card from your hand onto one of your red Tamers as if the Tamer is a level 3 Digimon,\" so the Tamer is considered to be a Digimon without digivolution cards, and the digivolution cost increases by 1 due to this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's red Tamer digivolves into a [BT4-011 Agunimon] when my Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. [BT4-011 Agunimon]'s effect reads \"You may Digivolve this card from your hand onto one of your red Tamers as if the Tamer is a level 3 Digimon,\" so a Tamer with cards under it is considered to be a Digimon with digivolution cards. [1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 1 when my opponent digivolves a red Tamer with cards under it into a [BT4-011 Agunimon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution fails, and the revealed card to digivolve into is returned to its owner's hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon with no digivolution cards digivolves and the digivolution cost increases due to this card's inherited effect, what happens if I can't pay the digivolution cost as a result?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the  \"1 of your blue Digimon\" that you select with this card's [On Play] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"that Digimon\" on this card refer to the \"1 of your blue Digimon\" or does it refer to this card when played from digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the inherited effect activates for each of the 2 Digimon, so the digivolution cost increases by a total of 2.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 Digimon in this card's digivolution cards, and my opponent's Digimon digivolves with no digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the digivolution cost only increases by 1. This card's inherited effect reads \"When an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards would digivolve,\" so even in the case of a DNA digivolution where there are 2 of the target opponent's Digimon, the digivolution cost only increases by 1 with this effect because the digivolution only occurs once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: 2 of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards DNA digivolves when my Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution cost increases by 1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: 1 of my opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards and 1 of my opponent's Digimon with digivolution cards DNA digivolves when my Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the digivolution cost increases by 1. [BT4-011 Agunimon]'s effect reads \"You may Digivolve this card from your hand onto one of your red Tamers as if the Tamer is a level 3 Digimon,\" so the Tamer is considered to be a Digimon without digivolution cards, and the digivolution cost increases by 1 due to this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's red Tamer digivolves into a [BT4-011 Agunimon] when my Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 1?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. [BT4-011 Agunimon]'s effect reads \"You may Digivolve this card from your hand onto one of your red Tamers as if the Tamer is a level 3 Digimon,\" so a Tamer with cards under it is considered to be a Digimon with digivolution cards. [1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards. Does the digivolution cost increase by 1 when my opponent digivolves a red Tamer with cards under it into a [BT4-011 Agunimon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The digivolution fails, and the revealed card to digivolve into is returned to its owner's hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a Digimon with no digivolution cards digivolves and the digivolution cost increases due to this card's inherited effect, what happens if I can't pay the digivolution cost as a result?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, different Digimon can be chosen.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can different Digimon be chosen for the target digivolution cards to trash and the target digivolution cards that \"can't attack or block\" for this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated on an opponent's Digimon with 4 digivolution cards, is it possible to trash the 1st and 3rd digivolution cards from the top?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to unsuspend this Digimon if it was suspended by an \uff1cEvade\uff1e effect that was gained from an inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the Digimon that attacks by this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Immediately after this effect activates and you suspend 1 of your Digimon with [Dramon] by this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: At what timing does my opponent choose the Digimon that attacks by this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can. In such cases, the attack isn't performed and the effect ends due to the \"can't attack\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent choose my Digimon with a \"can't attack\" effect as the target when they activate this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, there are no target Digimon, therefore the effect ends without an attack being performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect even if there are no Digimon in my opponent's battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: When this Digimon is suspended effects and the [When Attacking] effect are triggered by a single effect, therefore they are considered to trigger simultaneously.  According to the simultaneous trigger rules, first the turn player's [When Attacking] effects will activate, then the non-turn player's \"when this Digimon is suspended\" effects will activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] to suspend my [EX3-044 Breakdramon] or [EX3-074 Examon] and had my opponent attack.  At such times, how do I process effects such as \"when this Digimon is suspended\" effects on these Digimon and [When Attacking] effects on the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can activate the effect itself twice, but after the attack declaration is made and effects such as [When Attacking] effects have activated for your opponent's 1st Digimon, the 2nd card's effect activation timing will occur before the counter timing.  However, since the 1st Digimon is already attacking, its attack will continue and an attack declaration can't be made for the 2nd card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 of this card, can I activate the [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect on both and have 2 of my opponent's Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The attack declaration is made for this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] effect before the suspended [EX3-074 Examon]'s effect, therefore [EX3-074 Examon] is still suspended at that time and can be an attack target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent used this card's [Start of Opponent's Main Phase] to suspend their [EX3-074 Examon].  [EX3-074 Examon]'s effect reads \"when this Digimon becomes suspended, unsuspend it, and suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon.\" Can I attack my opponent's [EX3-074 Examon] before that effect unsuspends it?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate. This card's [On Deletion] effect only places a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from your hand in the battle area when you don't already have a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Deletion] effect to place a [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the battle area. Does [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons]'s \"[Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, place this card in your battle area.\" effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:Ancient AquabeastCategory:AquabeastCategory:AquaticCategory:Sea Animal\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Aqua]\u00a0in any of its traits\" (\u6c34\u68f2), does it include traits other than [Aqua] (\u6c34\u68f2)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a yellow card with with the [Angel], [Cherub], [Throne], [Authority], [Seraph], or [Virtue]\u00a0trait or a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include a yellow card with the [Angel], [Cherub], [Throne], [Authority], [Seraph], or [Virtue]\u00a0trait or a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand? (2022/07/22)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 yellow card [...] and 1 card with [Four Great Dragons] in its traits among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a yellow card with the [Angel], [Cherub], [Throne], [Authority], [Seraph], or [Virtue]\u00a0trait and a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means you can look at all of the cards in your security stack, without revealing them to your opponent. You then choose 1 card to add to your hand, and you reveal that card to your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"search your security stack\" in this card's [On Play] effect mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a yellow card with the [Angel], [Cherub], [Throne], [Authority], [Seraph], or [Virtue]\u00a0trait or a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include a yellow card with the [Angel], [Cherub], [Throne], [Authority], [Seraph], or [Virtue]\u00a0trait or a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd [...] to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a yellow card with the [Angel], [Cherub], [Throne], [Authority], [Seraph], or [Virtue]\u00a0trait and a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a yellow card with [Dramon] or a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include a yellow card with [Dramon] or a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait, can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd [...] to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a yellow card with [Dramon] and a card with the [Four Great Dragons]\u00a0trait are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate. This card's [When Digivolving] effect only places a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from your hand in the battle area when you don't already have a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Digivolving] effect to place a [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the battle area. Does [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons]'s \"[Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, place this card in your battle area.\" effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate. This card's [When Digivolving] effect only places a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from your hand in the battle area when you don't already have a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Digivolving] effect to place a [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the battle area. Does [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons]'s [Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, place this card in your battle area.\" effect activate? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate. This card's [On Deletion] effect only places a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from your hand in the battle area when you don't already have a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Deletion] effect to place a [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the battle area. Does [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons]'s [Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, place this card in your battle area.\" effect activate? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a green or blue card with [Dramon] or a card with [Examon] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include a green or blue card with [Dramon] or a card with [Examon], can I still add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd [...] to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a green or blue card with [Dramon] and a card with [Examon] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"when an effect suspends this Digimon\" also activate when it's suspended by an \uff1cEvade\uff1e effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"when an effect suspends this Digimon\" also activate when it's suspended by an \uff1cEvade\uff1e effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes.",
      "question": "Q: If both a card with [Vegetation]/[Plant]/[Fairy]\u00a0in any of its traits are revealed with this effect, must I add both of them to hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in any of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:VegetationCategory:Ancient PlantCategory:Carnivorous Plant\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Vegetation]\u00a0in any of its traits\" (\u690d\u7269\u578b), does it include traits other than [Vegetation] (\u690d\u7269\u578b)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"[Fairy]\u00a0in any of its traits\" includes the following traits:Category:FairyCategory:Ancient Fairy\n",
      "question": "Q: When it says \"[Fairy]\u00a0in any of its traits\" (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b), does it include traits other than [Fairy] (\u5996\u7cbe\u578b)?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as either a Digimon card with the [Rock Dragon], [Earth Dragon], [Bird Dragon], [Machine Dragon], or [Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait or a [Hina Kurihara] is among the cards revealed, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s effect reveals 4 cards. If the cards revealed only include 1 card with the [Rock Dragon], [Earth Dragon], [Bird Dragon], [Machine Dragon], or [Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait or a [Hina Kurihara], can I still add a card to my hand? (2022/07/22)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect reads \u201cAdd 1 Digimon card [...] and 1 [Hina Kurihara] among them to your hand,\u201d so you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect reveals 4 cards. If both a card with the [Rock Dragon], [Earth Dragon], [Bird Dragon], [Machine Dragon], or [Sky Dragon]\u00a0trait and a [Hina Kurihara] are among the cards revealed, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining card at the bottom of my deck? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, all of them gain \uff1cRush\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If multiple Digimon with the [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait are played at the same time. Does all of them gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only the Digimon with [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait will gain \uff1cRush\uff1e.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait and a Digimon without [D-Brigade]\u00a0trait are played by the same effect. Do both Digimon gain \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If you do not play it, you must trash it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't play the [Commandramon] revealed with this card\u2019s inherited effect, do I have to trash the [Commandramon]? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Unless you have 2 suspended Digimon for the DNA digivolution, you can't digivolve because of this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates this card's [On Play] effect. Can I DNA digivolve an unsuspended Digimon and a suspended Digimon in the next turn? (2022/07/22)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. <Digisorption> effects read \"when one of your Digimon digivolves,\" so unless the Digimon for the digivolution is in a state where it can digivolve, the effect can't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates this card's [On Play] effect. Can I use a <Digisorption> effect to suspend an unsuspended Digimon and then digivolve that Digimon in the next turn? (2022/07/22)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [BT4-011 Agunimon]'s effect reads \"You may digivolve this card from your hand onto one of your red Tamers as if the Tamer is a level 3 red Digimon,\" so it is considered to be an unsuspended Digimon and can't digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activates this card's [On Play] effect. Can I digivolve an unsuspended Tamer into a [BT4-011 Agunimon] in the next turn? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The \"When you would digivolve into this card\" effect is an effect where you return cards with [D-Brigade] to the top of your deck and reduce the digivolution cost after you reveal this card from your hand and declare a digivolution. Once you return cards, you can't cancel the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose not to digivolve after returning cards with [D-Brigade] in their traits from my trash to the top of my deck for this card's \"When you would digivolve into this card\" effect? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the purple or red cards with [Imperialdramon] or [Free] in their traits are the only cards that you add to your hand or trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I only trash a purple or red card with [Imperialdramon] or [Free] in its traits among the cards revealed from my deck by this card's [On Play] effect? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the [Your Turn] effect will not be active.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has [BT12-001 Gigimon] in its digivolution cards when it gets deleted. Can I delete a Digimon with 4000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the target original \"1 of your other Digimon\" for this effect does not have to be red.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into a level 4 red Digimon, does my other Digimon have to be red? (2022/07/22)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this is possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect to DNA digivolve, and this caused the memory gauge to move on my opponent's side. Is it possible to use this card's inherited effect to DNA digivolve again at the end of the turn? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, once the attack is declared, the attack will continue even if you lose digivolution cards in the meantime.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After declaring an attack with this Digimon, this Digimon's digivolution cards were trashed by an effect during the reaction timing window. Is the attack canceled? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate. This card's [On Deletion] effect only places a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from your hand in the battle area when you don't already have a [Trial of the Four Great Dragons] placed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Deletion] effect to place a [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons] from my hand in the battle area. Does [EX3-069 Trial of the Four Great Dragons]'s [Main] \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e. Then, place this card in your battle area.\" effect activate? (2022/07/22)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [ChaosGallantmon] name.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [ChaosGallantmon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [ChaosGallantmon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, you can't activate 2 effects at the same time, so you must activate them 1 at a time. After you suspend the first card and activate 1 of the digivolved Digimon's [On Play] effects, then you may suspend the second card and activate the second [On Play] effect. Note that if the first effect or another effect triggers an effect that deletes the digivolved Digimon or otherwise removes it from the battle area, the second effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon digivolved into a Digimon with [Rock Dragon], [Earth Dragon], [Machine Dragon], or [Sky Dragon] in its traits when I had 2 copies of this card in play. Can I suspend both copies of this card and activate the digivolved Digimon's [On Play] effects twice?(2022/07/22)"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The [On Deletion] effect is triggered afterward, so the [On Deletion] effect takes priority and activates first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon digivolved into a [EX3-012 Volcanicdramon] when I had 2 copies of this card in play. I used the effects on the first copy of this card to activate [EX3-012 Volcanicdramon]'s [On Play] effect and deleted all of my opponent's Digimon with the lowest DP. At this time, does the [On Deletion] effect of my opponent's deleted Digimon activate first or does the effect on the second copy of this card activate first? (2022/07/22)"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If one of your level 6 Digimon with [Machine] in its traits is in the battle area, you may use this Option card even when you don't have a red and black Digimon or Tamer in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"While you have a level 6 Digimon with [Machine] in its traits in play, you may use this card without meeting its color requirements.\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is still a Digimon that was played by this effect, so you delete it at the end of your opponent's turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effects read \"The Digimon played by this effect can't digivolve to level 7, and at the end of your opponent's turn, delete that Digimon.\" Do I delete that Digimon even if digivolution cards are added by an effect and then it becomes another Digimon due to an effect such as \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards)?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if the Digimon to digivolve into is level 7, DNA digivolving is not possible either.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play a Digimon, can I DNA digivolve that Digimon into a level 7 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. Suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon if you don't have any Digimon in play, and unsuspend 1 of your Digimon if your opponent doesn't have any Digimon in play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Security] effect activate if I or my opponent don't have any Digimon in the respective battle areas?"
    }
  ],
  "EX3-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. \"You may place 1 green or blue Digimon card with [Dramon] from your hand under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution card\" activates when digivolving normally or when DNA digivolving. The \"When DNA digivolving, you may play 1 green or blue Digimon card with [Dramon] and 12000 DP or less from your hand without paying the cost\" part activates only when DNA digivolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"You may place 1 green or blue Digimon card with [Dramon] from your hand under this Digimon as its bottom digivolution card\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate when DNA digivolving?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. The [On Deletion] effect activates after the card moves to your trash, therefore the Digimon where this card is a digivolution card won't be in the battle area and can't meet the condition.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is a digivolution card, does the Digimon above it meet the condition of this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't activate. \"Attack with this Digimon\" effects aren't suspending by an effect, they're suspending by an attack. Therefore, they aren't considered to be a \"When an effect suspends\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when an attack is performed using a \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. Deletion by the \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e effect isn't considered deletion by battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted by an opponent's \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e, does this card's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means when the cards in your trash and the cards in your opponent's trash add up to 20 or more cards in total. For example, the condition is met if you have 12 cards in your trash and your opponent has 8 cards in their trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"If the total number of cards in both players' trashes is 20 or more\" mean 20 or more cards in either me or my opponent's trashes?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \"for the turn\" effects persist as long as the conditions were met at the time of activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After gaining \uff1cRush\uff1e from this card's [On Play] effect, is \uff1cRush\uff1e lost if the total cards in both players' trashes is reduced to 19 or fewer cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Both players must trash 2 cards each, if possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect force both players to trash the top 2 cards of their decks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"\"you may return [...] to your hand,\"\" therefore you may choose to not return cards to your hand. However, even in such cases, both players must trash 2 cards from the tops of their decks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not return the cards to my hand for this card's [When Digivolving] effect when I have 1 [Guilmon] or 1 card with [Growlmon] in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"you may return [...] to your hand,\" therefore you may choose to not return cards to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not return the cards to my hand for this card's inherited effect when I have 1 [Guilmon] or 1 card with [Growlmon] in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect still activate for my opponent's Security Digimon and give them -4000 DP when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means every 10 cards in the total sum of cards in your trash and the cards in your opponent's trash. For example, if you have 15 cards in your trash and your opponent has 9 cards in their trash, the total would be 24. Therefore, you add 4000 to the maximum this DP-based deletion effect can delete, and you can now choose any number of your opponent's Digimon so that their DP total is 7000 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"For every 10 total cards in both players' trashes\" mean every 10 cards in either me or my opponent's trashes?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that the effect will activate at the specified timing if this card is in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does [Trash] in this card's [End of Your Turn] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \u201cyou may play,\" so you can choose not to play it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After deleting 1 of my Digimon with digivolution cards and [Gallantmon], can I choose to not play this card for this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it means every 10 cards in the total sum of cards in your trash and the cards in your opponent's trash. For example, if you have 15 cards in your trash and your opponent has 9 cards in their trash, the total would be 24. Therefore, you add 4000 to the maximum this DP-based deletion effect can delete, and you can now delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 11000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"For every 10 total cards in both players' trashes\" in this card's [On Play] effect mean every 10 cards in either me or my opponent's trashes?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. In such cases the card remains placed in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use the [Security] effect to play this card, then it was deleted during that same turn. In such cases, can I return this card from my trash to my hand at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon isn't deleted by this card's [On Play][When Attacking] effect, can I specify 1 of my opponent's suspended Digimon and prevent it from unsuspending during my opponent's next unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Since the [Security] effect didn't activate, the battle proceeds normally. At the end of the battle, this card is trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card is flipped over upon a security check from an opponent's Digimon's attack in a state where a \"your opponent's [Security] effects don't activate\" effect has activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also activate when an opponent's Digimon with the [Blue Flare]/[Twilight]\u00a0trait is played during my turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If Digimon with the [Blue Flare] and [Twilight]\u00a0traits are played by separate effects, this card's effect will separately trigger for each trait. Because of the rule that states that an effect triggered afterward will take precedence for activation, for the situation stated in your question, \"\"return 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements from your trash to your hand\"\" will activate by playing the Digimon with the [Twilight]\u00a0trait, but because the effect is a [Once Per Turn] effect, \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e doesn't activate by playing the Digimon with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my turn, a card with the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait was played and this card's effect was triggered. If a card with the [Twilight]\u00a0trait is played by another effect before this card's effect activates, can I perform both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and \"return 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements from your trash to your hand\" in this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has the [Blue Flare]\u00a0trait, so do I get \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e from this card's own effect when this card is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can perform both.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I perform both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and \"return 1 Digimon card with DigiXros requirements from your trash to your hand\" in this card's effect when a card with both the [Blue Flare] and [Twilight]\u00a0traits is played during my turn?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either [Kiriha Aonuma] or 1 blue or black card with DigiXros requirements, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both [Kiriha Aonuma] and 1 blue or black card with DigiXros requirements, can I add 1 card to my hand and trash the rest?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent's target Digimon that was specified when the effect activated will continue to have the \"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\" effect until the end of your opponent's turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"I used this card's [On Play] effect to give 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon with the lowest level \"\"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory.\"\". Then, that opponent's Digimon digivolved and another Digimon became their Digimon with the lowest level. What happens to the \"\"[When Attacking] Lose 2 memory\"\" effect?\""
    }
  ],
  "EX4-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The \"can't attack\" effect won't end until the end of your opponent's turn, even if the digivolution cards increase to 4 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"I chose 1 of my opponent's Digimon with 3 or fewer digivolution cards as the target for \"\"can't attack until the end of your opponent's turn\"\" in this card's inherited effect. Then, that opponent's Digimon digivolved and its digivolution cards increased to 4 or more. What happens to the \"\"can't attack until the end of your opponent's turn\"\" effect?\""
    }
  ],
  "EX4-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack. The effect reads \"\"all of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon,\"\" therefore the effect will no longer affect Digimon that become level 5 or higher after the effect activates. On the other hand, Digimon will be affected by the effect if they become level 4 or lower or a level 4 or lower Digimon is newly played on the battle area after the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After this card's [On Play] effect was used to prevent a level 4 or lower Digimon from attacking, the Digimon digivolved and became level 5 or higher. Can this Digimon attack?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return an opponent's level 4 Digimon to its owner's hand when my opponent had 7 cards in their hand. My opponent now has 8 cards in their hand, so does the rest of the effect after \"Then, if your opponent has 8 or more cards in their hand\" also activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The card revealed from your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is the card placed on top of my security stack by this card\u2019s effect the Digimon played by my opponent or the card revealed from my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: You can activate the effect, but you can't add cards to your security stack, therefore the revealed card can't be added to your security stack and is trashed by the rules.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect when [BT9-103 Kongou]'s effect is preventing cards from being added to my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [EX2-045 Calumon] is a card with no level, so it isn't considered to have the same level even though it's the same card, and you can't use this card's effect to reveal it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to reveal [EX2-045 Calumon] from my hand when my opponent plays a Lv.- [EX2-045 Calumon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Kyubimon] name.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [Kyubimon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Kyubimon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. A Digimon targeted by this effect will be affected until the timing specified in the effect, even if its DP increases to 7000 or more after the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"My opponent used this card's [When Digivolving] effect to prevent my Digimon with 6000 DP or less from attacking or blocking. If that Digimon's DP increased to 7000 or more by an effect afterwards, can it attack or block?\""
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect on an opponent's Digimon with 8000 DP and its DP is reduced by -2000 so that it becomes 6000 in a situation where I have a blue or yellow Tamer in play or I have a card with the [Armor Form]\u00a0trait in my trash, can I choose that Digimon as the target for the effect that prevents 1 Digimon from attacking or blocking?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play, and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]. Can I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Taomon] name.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [Taomon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Taomon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]\u2019s cost has been changed to 1, so using it isn\u2019t considered to be using an Option card with a cost of 2 or more.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 8 or more yellow Tamers in play and use [BT2-099 Glorious Burst], does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card is treated as having [Sakuyamon] and it's a level 6 card with a name other than [Sakuyamon], therefore it can digivolve using [EX4-072 Digital Translator]'s effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use [EX4-072 Digital Translator]'s effect to digivolve [Sakuyamon] into this card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has [Sakuyamon].[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"This card/Digimon is also treated as having [Sakuyamon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Sakuyamon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a 2-color green card or a Tamer card with [Henry Wong], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a 2-color green card and a Tamer card with [Henry Wong], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Terriermon] name.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [Terriermon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Terriermon].\")"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Players should reference \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Terriermon].\"     Cards with the \"this card/Digimon is also treated as [Terriermon]\" text are treated as if they have the other text.[2]",
      "question": "Q: This card has two different texts with the same card number: \"This card/Digimon is also treated as [Terriermon]\" and \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Terriermon].\" Which should I reference?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a 2-color green card or a Tamer card with [Shu-Chong Wong], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a 2-color green card and a Tamer card with [Shu-Chong Wong], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What can be the target of \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) in this card's [End of Attack] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can't perform a security check even if you gain \uff1cPiercing\uff1e after deleting your opponent's Digimon in battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An effect suspended another Digimon when I attacked my opponent's Digimon using my Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and only my Digimon survived. Does this Digimon gain \uff1cPiercing\uff1e by this card's inherited effect and allow me to check my opponent's security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct. A Lv.4 Digimon is required for both \"\"w/[Gargomon] in name\"\" and \"\"2-color w/green.\"\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \"3 from Lv.4 w/[Gargomon] in name or 2-color w/green\" special digivolution to digivolve from a \"Lv.4 Digimon w/[Gargomon] in name\" or \"2-color Lv.4 Digimon w/green\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct. A Lv.5 Digimon is required for both \"\"w/[Rapidmon] in name\"\" and \"\"2-color w/green.\"\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \"4 from Lv.5 w/[Rapidmon] in name or 2-color w/green\" special digivolution to digivolve from a \"Lv.5 Digimon w/[Rapidmon] in name\" or \"2-color Lv.5 Digimon w/green\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a Digimon card with [Greymon] or a Digimon card with [Gabumon], [Garurumon], or [Omnimon], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a Digimon card with [Greymon] and a Digimon card with [Gabumon], [Garurumon], or [Omnimon], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the top of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a Digimon card with [Garurumon] or a Digimon card with [Agumon], [Greymon], or [Omnimon], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a Digimon card with [Garurumon] and 1 Digimon card with [Agumon], [Greymon], or [Omnimon], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the top of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to play a [EX4-062 Kiriha Aonuma & Nene Amano] from my hand without paying the cost?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. [EX4-062 Kiriha Aonuma & Nene Amano] is a card that's also treated as [Nene Amano], therefore the \"If you don't have [Nene Amano] in play\" condition isn't met and the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] effect activate when I have [EX4-062 Kiriha Aonuma & Nene Amano] in play?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also includes the [Greymon] name.  This card can be chosen for text that specifies cards with [Greymon].  This card can't be chosen for text that specifies cards with the name [Greymon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"This card/Digimon is also treated as having [Greymon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Greymon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If this card's effect causes \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e to be lost before the 2nd security check, it isn't performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \"My opponent's Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e attacks me and 1 card is removed from my security stack by the security check. If I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to \uff1cDe-Digivolve  X\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash up to X cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards) that opponent's Digimon and it loses \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, is the 2nd security check performed?\""
    }
  ],
  "EX4-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. [EX2-045 Calumon] is a card with no level, so it isn't considered to have the same level even though it's the same card, and you can't use this card's effect to trash it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to trash [EX2-045 Calumon] from my hand when an opponent's Lv.- [EX2-045 Calumon] is deleted?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a purple Digimon card with [Ravemon] or [Bird] or [Avian] in one of its traits or a [Keenan Crier], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a purple Digimon card with [Ravemon] or [Bird] or [Avian] in one of its traits and 1 [Keenan Crier], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I or my opponent choose the card to be deleted from their hand when I activate this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates. Deletion by the \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e effect isn't considered deletion by battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted by an opponent's \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e, does this card's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I or my opponent choose the card to be trashed from their hand when I activate this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Digivolving] effect gave my level 5 Digimon the \"[On Deletion] You may play this card without paying the cost\" effect. If it later digivolves, becomes level 6 or higher, and is then deleted, does this [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect is a \"\"would\"\" effect, so its activation comes first and interrupts [BT11-109 Astral Snatcher]'s effect that places this card in digivolution cards. Therefore, you play 1 [BlitzGreymon] and 1 [CresGarurumon] from the digivolution cards without paying the costs, then place this Digimon at the bottom of your security stack face down. [BT11-109 Astral Snatcher]'s effect that places a card as the bottom digivolution card under another Digimon will fail because its target has been removed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When [BT11-109 Astral Snatcher]'s effect places this card in another Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s [All Turns] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If you and your opponent have a total of 2 or more Digimon in play, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate if there are 2 or more Digimon in the battle areas including my opponent's Digimon, rather than just my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Even if you have multiple Tamers with cards under them, you can only use 1 card from under 1 of them when you choose cards for a DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiple Tamers with cards under them, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to perform a DigiXros for each of my Tamers using a card from under each one?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Kiriha Aonuma] and [Nene Amano] names.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Tamer is also treated as [Kiriha Aonuma]/[Nene Amano]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [Kiriha Aonuma] and [Nene Amano].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of my purple Digimon with [Ravemon] or [Bird] or [Avian] in one of its traits is deleted by an effect, do I perform both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and gain 1 memory from this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \uff37hen my opponent has \uff17 cards in their hand, this card\u2019\uff53 effect returned their Lv.4 or lower Digimon to their hand. Since they now have 8 or more cards, does the part of the effect after \"Then, if your opponent has 8 or more cards in their hand\" activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This [Main] effect activates again for each color your Digimon have, and you get to choose the target for each activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [Main] effect two or more times, can I give -6000 DP to different opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they're treated as activating at the same timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [Main] effect two or more times, are they treated as activating at separate timings?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Main] effect activate three times when I have 1 2-color Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, multiple instances of the same color count as 1 color. Therefore, for the situation stated in your question, red, blue, and black would count as 3 colors, so the effect would activate four times.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a red/blue Digimon and a red/black Digimon, do they count as 4 colors and make this card's [Main] effect activate five times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, this effect activates multiple times, so you can choose different targets each time it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [Main] effect two or more times, can I activate the effect for different opponent's Digimon each time?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that uses this card chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses 1 of each player's Digimon with the highest play cost for this card\u2019s effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card when my opponent has no level 3 Digimon, can I still activate the effect that places this card in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you gain 2 memory. This effect makes your opponent choose between trashing an Option card from their hand or losing 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent doesn't trash an Option card from their hand for this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect, does my opponent gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means a level 6 Digimon card whose name partially contains the name of the chosen Digimon. For example, if you choose [WarGreymon], you can ignore the digivolution requirements and digivolve it into a level 6 Digimon card that includes [WarGreymon] as part of its name, such as [WarGreymon (X Antibody)], [BlackWarGreymon], or [BlackWarGreymon (X Antibody)].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"a level 6 Digimon card in your hand with a different name that includes the chosen Digimon's name\" on this card mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be digivolved.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose [Sakuyamon] for this card's [Main] effect, can I digivolve that Digimon into EX4-030 [Kuzuhamon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose EX4-030 [Kuzuhamon] for this card's [Main] effect, can I digivolve that Digimon into [Sakuyamon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also includes the [Plug-In] name.  This card can be chosen for text that specifies cards with [Plug-In].[3]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"this card is also treated as having [Plug-In]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as having [Plug-In].\")"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You delete the one with the lowest play cost from among your opponent's Digimon and Tamers. If multiple Digimon and/or Tamers have the lowest play cost, the player of this card chooses from among them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I choose 1 Digimon with the lowest play cost or 1 Tamer with the lowest play cost to delete for \"among your opponent's Digimon and Tamers, delete 1 with the lowest play cost\" in this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. For every level 6 or higher digivolution card trashed, this effect deletes 1 of your opponent's Digimon or Tamers in order starting with the lowest play cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Attacking] effect to trash 2 level 6 or higher digivolution cards. If my opponent has 1 Digimon with a play cost of 3 and 1 Digimon with a play cost of 4, can I delete both of them?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to trash 3 level 6 or higher digivolution cards, do I trash the top 2 cards of my opponent's security stack after deleting 3 of their Digimon and/or Tamers with the lowest play costs?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. This effect requires you to choose at least 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 6 or less whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to choose 0 for the play cost total without deleting an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX4-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. If a card is played at the same time as deletion by DP becoming 0, the [On Play] effect is triggered, but it can't activate because the card is deleted before it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I played a Digimon with 5000 DP or less in a state where my opponent used this card's [When Digivolving][On Deletion] effect to give all of my Digimon -5000 DP. Can I activate my played Digimon's [On Play] effect before it's deleted by its DP becoming 0?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must activate it whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [End of Attack] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [End of Attack] effect also activate when my opponent has no Digimon in play?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-001": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when a digivolution card or the top card of the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is placed in this Digimon's digivolution cards by an effect such as [EX5-007 Coronamon]'s inherited effect. It doesn't include cases where a card becomes a digivolution card through digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when an effect places the top card of this Digimon in its digivolution cards\" mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that you place the top card of the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards as the bottom digivolution card.  For example, if you have a level 4 Digimon with just this card in its digivolution cards, you place that level 4 Digimon card under this card. This will turn this Digimon into a level 3 Digimon with the level 4 Digimon card as a digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"by placing the top card of this Digimon [...] as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card\" in this card's inherited effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  A record of activation remains for the inherited effect's [Once Per Turn] even if this card stops being a digivolution card, so it can't be activated twice in the same turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's inherited effect placed a stacked card under this Digimon's digivolution cards and increased my memory by 2 when another copy of this card was in this card's digivolution cards.  Can this be repeated to give me infinite memory?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards revealed for this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect include only either 1 card with the [Light Fang]\u00a0trait or 1 card with the [Night Claw]/[Galaxy]\u00a0trait, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect include both a card with the [Light Fang]\u00a0trait and a card with the [Night Claw]/[Galaxy]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't.  This card's effect reads \"when this card would be [...] digivolved into,\" therefore the effect doesn't activate for digivolutions from this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has 3 or more digivolution cards and I have a Digimon with the [Light Fang]/[Night Claw]/[Galaxy]\u00a0trait, is the digivolution cost still reduced by 2 when digivolving this Digimon into a Digimon card in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect delete an opponent's Digimon with the [Deva]\u00a0trait or 6000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's [Your Turn] effect triggers \"when a card is removed from your opponent's security stack,\" therefore it will trigger/activate when the 1st security check is performed, even if there are no targets. Because it's a [Once Per Turn] effect, it can't trigger when the 2nd security check is performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: In a state where my opponent had no Digimon, I used this Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e to attack, [BT3-036 Ankylomon] was flipped over for the 1st security check, and the [Security] effect played it as an opponent's Digimon at the end of the battle. When the 2nd security check is performed, can this card's [Your Turn] effect delete my opponent\u2019s [BT3-036 Ankylomon]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to add a card to my hand when only 1 card with [Garurumon] is among the 4 revealed cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 4 cards revealed for this card's effect include 1 each of a card with [Garurumon], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to add 2 cards with [Garurumon] to my hand when 2 cards with [Garurumon] and 1 card with [X Antibody] are among the 4 revealed cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that you place the top card of the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards as the bottom digivolution card.  For example, if you have a level 4 Digimon with just this card in its digivolution cards, you place that level 4 Digimon card under this card. This will turn this Digimon into a level 3 Digimon with the level 4 Digimon card as a digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"by placing the top card of this Digimon [...] as this Digimon's bottom digivolution card\" in this card's inherited effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  A record of activation remains for the inherited effect's [Once Per Turn] even if this card stops being a digivolution card, so it can't be activated twice in the same turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's inherited effect placed a stacked card under this Digimon's digivolution cards and increased my memory by 2 when another copy of this card was in this card's digivolution cards.  Can this be repeated to give me infinite memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to return this Digimon itself to the hand and gain 2 memory?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck instead of the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by returning 1 of your Digimon to the hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to return my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] from the battle area to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your token is chosen as the target to return to the hand for this card's effect, it will ultimately be removed from the game instead of being returned to the hand according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by returning 1 of your Digimon to the hand\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the hand, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the hand\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to return my token that was played as a Digimon from the battle area to the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed for this card's effect include only either 1 card with the [Light Fang]\u00a0trait or 1 card with the [Night Claw]/[Galaxy]\u00a0trait, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed for this card's effect include 1 card with the [Light Fang]\u00a0trait and 1 card with the [Night Claw]/[Galaxy]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect return 2 non-Digi-Egg cards from the trash to the bottom of the deck, but then allow the deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't.  This card's effect reads \"when this card would be [...] digivolved into,\" therefore the effect doesn't activate for digivolutions from this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon has 3 or more digivolution cards and I have a Digimon with the [Night Claw]/[Light Fang]/[Galaxy]\u00a0trait, is the digivolution cost still reduced by 2 when digivolving this Digimon into a Digimon card in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the Option card you use has a cost of 1 or more, this card's [Your Turn] effect activates regardless of the actual cost paid. However, if some effect (like [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]'s \"Reduce the memory cost of this card in your hand by 1 for each yellow Tamer you have in play\" effect) reduces the card's cost to 0 when it's in your hand instead of reducing the cost when using it, then this card's [Your Turn] effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play an Option card without paying its cost by activating an effect that reduces the cost of an Option card with a cost of 1 or more or an effect that uses an Option card without paying its cost, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  If you don't perform the action specified for \"by X\" in such an effect, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't trash 2 cards in my hand, can the part after \"then\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect is a [Once Per Turn] effect, so it can only activate once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect activates when digivolving, does it activate again in the same turn when attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. They can't suspend by effects regardless of whether they were activated by you or your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect prevent my opponent's Digimon from suspending even when I activate an effect such as a \"suspend 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect targets \"all of their Digimon with no digivolution cards,\" therefore even if your opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards later enters the battle area, they are still affected by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards enters the battle area after this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect activates, can that Digimon suspend?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can now suspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon gains digivolution cards through digivolution or some other method after this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect activates, can that Digimon now suspend?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon card in my trash with a level that's different from all of my opponent's Digimon, can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to return that card to the bottom of the deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Digimon without a level can't be targeted by effects that reference levels.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to return a Digimon card with no level to the bottom of the deck, can I delete my opponent's Digimon with no level?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.  This card's effect targets \"all of their Digimon,\" therefore opponent's Digimon that later enter the battle area are also affected by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon enters the battle area after this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates, does that Digimon gain \"[When Attacking] Lose 4 memory\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must reveal the card to your opponent before adding it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] effect to add a card with [Leomon] from my security stack to the hand, do I have to reveal the added card to my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's [On Play] effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's inherited effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this effect. You can only digivolve this card into an applicable Digimon card with [Leomon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve it into a Digimon card with [Leomon] in my hand regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect to trash the top card of my security stack when this Digimon is already unsuspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's inherited effect mean?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect gives \uff1cSecurity A. -2\uff1e to all of your opponent's Digimon with levels greater than or equal to the total cards in both players' security stacks.  For example, if the total cards in both players' security stacks is 6, then all of your opponent's level 6 and higher Digimon will get \uff1cSecurity A. -2\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"total cards in both players' security stacks\" in this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the number of security cards decreases, does the level for the targets for \uff1cSecurity A. -2\uff1e in this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect also decrease at that time?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means the total number of cards in both you and your opponent's security stacks.  For example, if you have 3 cards in your security stack and your opponent has 2 cards in their security stack, the total security cards will be 5 cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"the total cards in both players' security stacks\" mean?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as the Option card you use has a cost of 1 or more, this card's [Your Turn] effect activates regardless of the actual cost paid. However, if some effect (like [BT2-099 Glorious Burst]'s \"Reduce the memory cost of this card in your hand by 1 for each yellow Tamer you have in play\" effect) reduces the card's cost to 0 when it's in your hand instead of reducing the cost when using it, then this card's [Your Turn] effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play an Option card without paying its cost by activating an effect that reduces the cost of an Option card with a cost of 1 or more or an effect that uses an Option card without paying its cost, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon's DP is increased/reduced by another effect, does this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect target my opponent\u2019s Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon\u2019s DP after it's increased/reduced?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that the effect's play cost reduction of 4 can be further reduced by 3 if the conditions are met, so you can play 1 green Digimon card from your hand with the play cost reduced by 7.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"if a card with [Leopardmon] or [X Antibody] is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, further reduce it by 3\" in this card's [When Digivolving][Main] effect mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  Even if there are multiple digivolution cards that meet the conditions, this effect can only further reduce the cost by a maximum of 3.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a total of 2 or more cards with [Leopardmon] and/or [X Antibody] are in this Digimon's digivolution cards, can this card's effect further reduce the cost by 3 for each of those cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, an [On Deletion] effect activates after the card is moved to the trash. Therefore, the card is first sent to the trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to return this card to the hand, does it mean that this card isn't sent to the trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be activated. Until the first occurrence of the first process is resolved, all immediate/interruptive effects can be activated only once each. In this situation, until the first Sukamon A deletion resolves, each of the \"When X would\" effects can only be activated once, so Sukamon A that has already been activated cannot be activated again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: There are \"Sukamon\" A and \"Sukamon\" B in the Battle Area, both of which have this card as their digivolution card. When \"Sukamon\" A was about to be deleted, it tried to delete \"Sukamon\" B with this card's inherited effect. On the other hand, when \"Sukamon\" B is about to be deleted, it tried to delete \"Sukamon\" A with this card's inherited effect. In this case, can \"Sukamon\" A activate this card's inherited effect again?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger at the same time at the start of your opponent's main phase, and an attack is only performed for the effect that activated first.  Specifically, after activation has ended for an effect such as the [When Attacking] effect on the Digimon whose effect activated first, and before the counter timing occurs, the effect would activate for the 2nd Digimon that was pending activation, but since the 1st Digimon is already attacking, the effect ends without an attack made. As a result, only the Digimon whose effect was activated first can attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates twice and 2 of my opponent's Digimon gain the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] This Digimon attacks\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-051": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card without the same name as any of the cards among all your Digimon/Tamers in the battle area, Option cards placed by effects, and cards in your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"without the same name as the cards in your battle area or trash\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect doesn't reference digivolution cards or cards under a Tamer.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect also reference whether the card names are the same or not for the digivolution cards under my Digimon in the battle area or cards under my Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [On Play] effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  This card's effect plays a Digimon into the breeding area instead of hatching it. Therefore, the \"Digimon can't attack the turn they came into play\" rule still applies.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon is moved to the battle area by an effect during the same turn that it was played into the breeding area by this card's effect, can that Digimon attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they don't activate.  Cards in the breeding area can't be referenced unless specified otherwise by effect text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do \"when your (or your opponent's) Digimon is played\" effects activate for Digimon played into the breeding area by this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"can't be played by effects\" effect affects a player when it activates, therefore the act of playing a Digimon itself won't be possible, whether in the breeding area or the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to play a Digimon into the breeding area if a \"Digimon can't be played by effects\" effect has been activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It activates when the security card revealed by a security check is a Digimon card with the [Deva]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's attacking Digimon has the [Deva]\u00a0trait, does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's effect reads \"play it,\" therefore you must activate it when the card revealed for a security check is a Digimon card with the [Deva]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the card revealed for a security check is a Digimon card with the [Deva]\u00a0trait, can I choose to not activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect and not play that Digimon, but still battle with my opponent's attacking Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent declares an attack on this Digimon, can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to place a card with [Etemon] from my hand on top of my security stack but choose to not switch the target of attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect to switch the target of an opponent's Digimon's attack to my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.  If a card moves to an area other than the trash before a triggered [On Deletion] effect activates, that [On Deletion] effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate \uff1cFortitude\uff1e before the [On Deletion] effect when this Digimon is deleted, can I still activate the [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also trigger when one of my effects plays an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also trigger when one of my opponent's effects plays my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be treated as the opponent's Digimon. You can choose appropriate targets for this effect, such as the target of attack for your Digimon, or target your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect plays a [Fujitsumon] Token to my opponent's battle area, which player's Digimon does it become?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can only play the token in your battle area if there are currently 4 or more Digimon in the battle areas without including the token.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are 4 or more total Digimon including the [Fujitsumon] Token played when using this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect, can you play it to your battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens aren't sent to the trash when deleted, but [On Deletion] effects on tokens will activate as if the token was a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: [Fujitsumon] Tokens have an [On Deletion] effect, but because tokens are removed from the game when deleted instead of being placed in the trash, does this mean that the effect doesn't activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also trigger when one of my effects plays an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect also trigger when one of my opponent's effects plays my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a [Dobermon] with [BT10-011 Canoweissmon] and [Gammamon] with an [On Play] effect in its digivolution cards digivolves into this card, does this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate the [On Play] effect on both this card and the [Gammamon] digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect reads \"your opponent plays,\" therefore you must play a card when possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent activates this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect and I have a card that can be played from my trash, can I choose to not play it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Level 4 or lower.  If the same reference to an \"X\" trigger condition being performed is made for an effect when it has a \"when X\" trigger condition, the state when the effect has triggered will be referenced. In this case, your opponent's Digimon was level 4 when this card's [All Turns] effect triggered, therefore you can play a level 4 or lower Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's level 4 Digimon was played by an effect, then this card's [All Turns] effect and another effect triggered simultaneously. I activated the other effect, then the level of the Digimon that was played by an effect increased from 4 to 5.  If I then activate this card's [All Turns] effect, what levels of Digimon can I play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If the same reference to an \"X\" trigger condition being performed is made for an effect when it has a \"when X\" trigger condition, the state when the effect has triggered will be referenced.  In this case, your opponent's Digimon was level 4 when this card's [All Turns] effect triggered, therefore you can play a level 4 or lower Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent's level 4 Digimon was played by an effect, then this card's [All Turns] effect and another effect triggered simultaneously. I activated the other effect, then the Digimon that was played by an effect was removed from the battle area.  If I then activate this card's [All Turns] effect, can I play a Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a [Cerberusmon] with [BT10-011 Canoweissmon] and [Gammamon] with an [On Play] effect in its digivolution cards digivolves into this card, does this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate the [On Play] effect on both this card and the [Gammamon] digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that when you use this effect to play 1 purple Digimon card from your trash with the play cost reduced by 3, you can further reduce it by 1 for each card trashed from your hand.  For example, if you used this effect to trash 2 cards from your hand, you can play 1 purple Digimon card from your trash with its play cost reduced by 5.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"for each card trashed by this effect, further reduce it by 1\" in this card's [When Digivolving][Main] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. That's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't trash any cards from my hand, can I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving][Main] effect to play a purple Digimon card from my trash with its play cost reduced by 3?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card\u2019s [When Digivolving][Main] effect to trash a purple Digimon card from my hand, can I choose that card as the card to play from my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Even if a single effect plays multiple Digimon at the same time, you can only use this effect to delete 1 of your opponent's level 5 or lower Digimon, or use it to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e once.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a single effect plays 2 or more of my Digimon at the same time, can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to delete 2 of my opponent's level 5 or lower Digimon, or use it to \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e twice?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate when this card's effect itself plays a card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"then, delete 1 of your opponent\u2019s lowest level Digimon\" in this card's [On Play][When Digivolving] effect activate even if my opponent doesn't have as many or more total Digimon and Tamers as me?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  The 2nd [All Turns] effect on EX1-073 [Machinedramon] can interrupt both deletions performed by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I play this card when my opponent only has 1 EX1-073 [Machinedramon] in the battle area. At this time, I use \"delete 1 of your opponent's highest level Digimon\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, and the 2nd [All Turns] effect on my opponent's EX1-073 [Machinedramon] interrupts it and prevents the deletion.  If I then use this card's \"delete 1 of your opponent's lowest level Digimon\" effect, can the 2nd [All Turns] effect on my opponent's EX1-073 [Machinedramon] again interrupt the effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the Digimon that digivolves into a Digimon card in my hand for this card's [On Play] [Main] effect be a Digimon other than the top card placed as the bottom digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You place the top card of one of your Digimon in the digivolution cards of that Digimon or another of your Digimon.  This doesn't include when the top card becomes a digivolution card through digivolution.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"when an effect places the top card of one of your Digimon in a Digimon's digivolution cards\" in this card's [Your Turn] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.  The [On Play] effect will trigger, but it can't activate because the Digimon becomes a digivolution card through DNA digivolution before the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Start of Opponent's Turn] effect to play and DNA digivolve a Digimon. In such cases, does the played Digimon's [On Play] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"return 1 Digimon card with the [Light Fang]/[Night Claw]/[Galaxy]\u00a0trait from your trash to the hand\" in this card's [Main] effect activate when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect still activates even when your opponent has no Digimon or Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has no Digimon or Tamers, does that mean that I can't activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"you may play 1 Tamer card with the [Night Claw]/[Light Fang]\u00a0trait from your hand without paying the cost\" in this card's [Main] effect activate when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon or Tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the card trashed from your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"if this effect trashed a card with the [Seven Great Demon Lords]\u00a0trait\" refer to the card trashed from my hand or my opponent's level 6 or lower Digimon that I deleted?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, \uff1cDelay\uff1e effects are \"trash this card in your battle area to activate\" effects, therefore you can choose to not trash the card in order to prevent them from activating.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an effect plays an opponent's Digimon while this card is in the battle area, do I have to activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an effect plays an opponent's Digimon into the breeding area, does this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  [Marcus Damon] is played as a Tamer by [BT13-020 ShineGreymon: Burst Mode] effect and then it's treated as being a Digimon by an effect, therefore it isn't considered to be played as a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent uses [BT13-020 ShineGreymon: Burst Mode]'s effect to play [Marcus Damon] as a Digimon, does this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e also activate when one of my effects plays an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: That's correct. This card has a \"Name: Also treated as [X Antibody]\" rule, therefore a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards isn't treated as \"1 of your Digimon without [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon has this card in its digivolution cards, does that mean that it isn't treated as \"1 of your Digimon without [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it activates even if only this card is in the digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect only activate if both [X Antibody] and a Digimon card are in the digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards would be deleted other than by one of my effects, then an effect such as \uff1cDecoy (nocategory)\uff1e (When your other nocategory Digimon would be deleted by an opponent's effect, you may delete this Digimon to prevent 1 of those Digimon's deletion) prevents it from being deleted, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If digivolution isn't performed using this card's effect, you can't place this card in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card and then place this card in digivolution cards without digivolving 1 of my Digimon without [X Antibody] in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I don't have any Digimon, can I use this card's effect to reveal a card with the [Deva]/[Four Sovereigns]\u00a0trait and declare to place it as the bottom digivolution card of my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to reveal an Option card with the [Deva]/[Four Sovereigns]\u00a0trait from my deck, can I place that card as the bottom digivolution card of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"when this card would be used, reduce the cost by 1 for each [Deva]/[Four Sovereigns]\u00a0trait card with a different name in your trash\" include this card itself when I use it?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can \"trash any 8 digivolution cards from your opponent's Digimon\" in this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect trash a total of 8 digivolution cards from multiple opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t.  If this effect is activated [When Attacking], only \"delete 1 of their Digimon with as many or fewer digivolution cards as this Digimon\" activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon attacks after DNA digivolving, does \"if DNA digivolving, trash any 8 digivolution cards from your opponent's Digimon\" in this card's [When Attacking] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"then, delete 1 of their Digimon with as many or fewer digivolution cards as this Digimon\" in this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect activate even when not DNA digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, as many as possible are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent's Digimon have less than 8 digivolution cards when this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect activates, does that mean that those digivolution cards can't be trashed?"
    }
  ],
  "EX5-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  \uff1cRaid\uff1e and \u201cthis Digimon can also attack unsuspended Digimon\u201d effects affect the attacking Digimon itself, so such effects aren't affected by \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon be attacked by my opponent\u2019s Digimon with \uff1cRaid\uff1e or a \u201cthis Digimon can also attack unsuspended Digimon\u201d effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's inherited effect to add 1 card from my security stack to the hand and then place 1 Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]/[Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait from the hand at the bottom of my security stack. At such times, is a card considered to be added to my security stack, allowing \"when a card is added to your security stack\" effects to activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's inherited effect to add 1 card from my security stack to the hand and then place 1 Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]/[Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait from the hand at the bottom of my security stack. At such times, is a card considered to be removed from my security stack, allowing \"when a card is removed from your security stack\" effects to activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must delete them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to delete all of my Digimon for this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect even when I have 0 cards in my Digi-Egg deck and can't place a card in digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they are.  When cards such as [Leviamon] and [Leviamon (X Antibody)] differ in that one has [X Antibody] and the other doesn't, you can reference the cards as if they have different names.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Leviamon] and [Leviamon (X Antibody)] are in this card's digivolution cards, are they considered \"cards with different names\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does [Gate of Deadly Sins] itself in digivolution cards also count for this card's \"if this Digimon has 5 or more digivolution cards with different names\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If multiple copies of this card are in digivolution cards, does its inherited effect overlap?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose not to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's inherited effect when a Digimon card would be played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card's inherited effect when a Digimon would be played by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to reduce the digivolution cost by 3 even if this card has 5 or more digivolution cards with different names?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 1 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 3 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 1 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 1 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 3 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 1 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 4 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 1 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 1 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 4 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 2 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 5 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 2 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 2 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 5 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 3 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 6 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 3 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 3 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 6 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use a Digimon that was played this turn or a suspended Digimon to attack with this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  The activation timing for the [Security] effect is before the battle with the Security Digimon, so even if a [RagnaLoardmon] with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted in battle, the [Security] effect can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a [RagnaLoardmon] with this card in digivolution cards is deleted in battle against a Security Digimon, does that Security Digimon's [Security] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is no longer affected.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect prevent my opponent's effects from affecting this Digimon even when my opponent has 0 security cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  When played from digivolution cards, both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and \"gain 1 memory\" can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I gain \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e with this card's [On Play] effect even when this card is played from digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must return your Digimon to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect also return my Digimon to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Each Digimon is returned to its respective owner's hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon and my opponent's Digimon are returned to the hand by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, which player's hand are they returned to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect return all other level 4 or lower Digimon to the hand even when I don't place my other Digimon as the bottom digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include only either a Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]\u00a0trait or a card with the [Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]\u00a0trait and a card with the [Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-018": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"when you would play this card\" effect also activate when this card would be played by an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Even if the part after the conditions specified with \"by X\" in an effect can't be resolved, the effect can still activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to place 1 of my level 6 Digimon on top of my security stack even when I don't have [Lucemon: Chaos Mode] in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to place 1 of my level 6 Digimon on top of my security stack but choose to not digivolve this Digimon into [Lucemon: Chaos Mode] in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect include only either a card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]/[Fallen Angel]\u00a0trait or a [Mirei Mikagura], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect include both a card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]/[Fallen Angel]\u00a0trait and a [Mirei Mikagura], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you don't meet the conditions specified for \"by X\" in such an effect, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 0 security cards or if I don't add the top or bottom card of my security stack to the hand for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I activate the part of the effect after \"then\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can place 1 [Sanzomon], 1 [Sagomon], or 1 [Cho-Hakkaimon] under this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place 1 each of [Sanzomon], [Sagomon], and [Cho-Hakkaimon] for this card's DigiXros requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The \"if DigiXrosing\" part of the effect can only activate when DigiXrosing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If DigiXrosing when this card would be played, can I also activate the part after \"if DigiXrosing\" in this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect when this Digimon attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect or inherited effect to give 1 of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  Because a Digimon also leaves the battle area when it's placed in digivolution cards for a DigiXros, the effect triggers and activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when this card is in the battle area and would be placed in another Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards for a DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  You must choose all of the cards to place when you declare the DigiXros. After choosing them, the chosen cards are placed under the card to DigiXros. This card's [All Turns] effect triggers and activates when the chosen cards would be placed, so after activation has occurred, you can't re-do your choices for the cards to place for the DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I chose this card as a target for a DigiXros. Then, I used this card's [All Turns] effect to return a yellow Digimon card to the hand. At such times, can the card returned to the hand be placed for the DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can place 1 [Sanzomon], 1 [Gokuumon], or 1 [Cho-Hakkaimon] under this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place 1 each of [Sanzomon], [Gokuumon], and [Cho-Hakkaimon] for this card's DigiXros requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The \"if DigiXrosing\" part of the effect can only activate when DigiXrosing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If DigiXrosing when this card would be played, can I also activate the part after \"if DigiXrosing\" in this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect when this Digimon attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect or inherited effect to give 1 of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  Because a Digimon also leaves the battle area when it's placed in digivolution cards for a DigiXros, the effect triggers and activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when this card is in the battle area and would be placed in another Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards for a DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  You must choose all of the cards to place when you declare the DigiXros. After choosing them, the chosen cards are placed under the card to DigiXros. This card's [All Turns] effect triggers and activates when the chosen cards would be placed, so after activation has occurred, you can't re-do your choices for the cards to place for the DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I chose this card as a target for a DigiXros. Then, I used this card's [All Turns] effect to return a yellow Digimon card to the hand. At such times, can the card returned to the hand be placed for the DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can place 1 [Gokuumon], 1 [Sagomon], or 1 [Cho-Hakkaimon] under this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place 1 each of [Gokuumon], [Sagomon], and [Cho-Hakkaimon] for this card's DigiXros requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The \"if DigiXrosing\" part of the effect can only activate when DigiXrosing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If DigiXrosing when this card would be played, can I also activate the part after \"if DigiXrosing\" in this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect when this Digimon attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect or inherited effect to give 1 of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  Because a Digimon also leaves the battle area when it's placed in digivolution cards for a DigiXros, the effect triggers and activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when this card is in the battle area and would be placed in another Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards for a DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  You must choose all of the cards to place when you declare the DigiXros. After choosing them, the chosen cards are placed under the card to DigiXros. This card's [All Turns] effect triggers and activates when the chosen cards would be placed, so after activation has occurred, you can't re-do your choices for the cards to place for the DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I chose this card as a target for a DigiXros. Then, I used this card's [All Turns] effect to return a yellow Digimon card to the hand. At such times, can the card returned to the hand be placed for the DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can place 1 [Sanzomon], 1 [Gokuumon], or 1 [Sagomon] under this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place 1 each of [Sanzomon], [Gokuumon], and [Sagomon] for this card's DigiXros requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. The \"if DigiXrosing\" part of the effect can only activate when DigiXrosing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If DigiXrosing when this card would be played, can I also activate the part after \"if DigiXrosing\" in this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect when this Digimon attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect or inherited effect to give 1 of my Digimon \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  Because a Digimon also leaves the battle area when it's placed in digivolution cards for a DigiXros, the effect triggers and activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when this card is in the battle area and would be placed in another Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards for a DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  You must choose all of the cards to place when you declare the DigiXros. After choosing them, the chosen cards are placed under the card to DigiXros. This card's [All Turns] effect triggers and activates when the chosen cards would be placed, so after activation has occurred, you can't re-do your choices for the cards to place for the DigiXros.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I chose this card as a target for a DigiXros. Then, I used this card's [All Turns] effect to return a yellow Digimon card to the hand. At such times, can the card returned to the hand be placed for the DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you can't add cards from your security stack to the hand, you can't activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect when I have 0 security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect does not allow you to attack with this Digimon if it is in a state where it can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this Digimon to attack with this card's [All Turns] effect if it digivolved from a Digimon that was played this turn or a suspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and attack, or you must neither gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e nor attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When a card is removed from my security stack, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to gain \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e without attacking?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player chooses the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used [BT16-024 MagnaAngemon]'s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into this card, then I placed a card from my hand at the bottom of my security stack. At such times, does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect or its [All Turns] effect activate first?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't play a Digimon card, can the part after \"then\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" refers to when that Digimon is placed in the trash other than as a result of a battle, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area other than by [...] a battle\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, all of those Digimon are prevented from leaving.  This card's [All Turns] effect affects all Digimon without having to choose them.  In such cases, the effect triggers once when multiples of your Digimon with the [Angel], [Archangel], or [Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait would leave the battle area at the same time other than by one of your effects or a battle, and by trashing the top card of your security stack, all of those Digimon are prevented from leaving.[3]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when multiples of my Digimon with the [Angel], [Archangel], or [Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait would leave the battle area at the same time other than by one of my effects or a battle, are all of those Digimon prevented from leaving?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can play just one of them if only one or the other is in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do both 1 [Sanzomon] and 1 [Gokuumon], [Sagomon] or [Cho-Hakkaimon] have to be in this Digimon's digivolution cards in order to play them for this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect changes your Digimon's <Security A. -> effects to <Security A. +>.  For example, a Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e will be changed to have \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, and a Digimon with \uff1cSecurity A. -2\uff1e will be changed to have \uff1cSecurity A. +2\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of effect is this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect changes them to 2 instances of \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, not \uff1cSecurity A. +2\uff1e.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon has 2 instances of \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e, does this card's [Your Turn] effect change them to \uff1cSecurity A. +2\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can a Digimon with either <Security A. +> or <Security A. -> be a target for this card's [End of Opponent's Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be played as long as it is a level 3 card with the [Beast]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can my other Digimon that was returned to the hand by this card's inherited effect be played by this inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. The effect only targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have 2 or more other Digimon, can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect give both of my opponent's 2 Digimon -4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't play a Digimon card from my hand, can the part after \"then\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include only either a Tamer card or Option card with [Diaboromon] in its text or 1 card with the [Unidentified]\u00a0trait, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a Tamer card or Option card with [Diaboromon] in its text and a card with the [Unidentified]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 1 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 3 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 1 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 1 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 3 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 1 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 3 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 1 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 1 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 3 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 1 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 4 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 1 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 1 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 4 Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to digivolve into [Diaboromon] in the hand regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 2 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 5 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 2 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 2 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 5 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  However, in such cases the \"can't attack\" effect prevents making the attack.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose an opponent's Digimon with a \"can't attack\" effect as the target when I activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the start of your opponent's main phase, the effects gained from this card's effect are triggered at the same time, and your opponent determines which one activates first.  After effects such as [When Attacking] have activated, and before the counter timing occurs, it is time to activate the effect of the 2nd Digimon that was pending activation. However, since the 1st Digimon is already attacking, the effect ends without an attack made.  As a result, only the Digimon whose effect was activated first can attack.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [Main] effect activates twice and 2 of my opponent's Digimon gain the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] This Digimon attacks\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon with a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect can also be chosen as a target for this effect, therefore your opponent's Digimon will lose the \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect as soon as it becomes your opponent's turn, then it will be affected by this card's effect.  As a result, the attack occurs at the start of the main phase.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [Main] effect is activated on an opponent's Digimon with an \"[Opponent's Turn] This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I trash this card itself from digivolution cards for this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's 1st [All Turns] effect to activate a [When Digivolving] effect that isn't an inherited effect on one of this Digimon's digivolution cards when an opponent's Digimon is played?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The activation conditions include paying 3 cost and placing this card as 1 of your [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or 1 of your level 6 Digimon's bottom digivolution card, therefore the effect can't be activated just by paying 1 cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to pay 3 cost even when I don't have any [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait or level 6 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Will a [RagnaLoardmon] with this card as a digivolution be deleted by an effect that deletes a Digimon when activated by my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This effect activates upon the counter timing after [When Attacking] effects have already activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon attacks, can this card's inherited effect end the attack before [When Attacking] effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. After the battle is resolved, the timing for activation of effects during the counter timing has already passed, so the effect can't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon attacks, if this card's inherited effect activates after comparing DP for the battle, can it end the attack at that timing?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The attack is considered to occur, therefore processing such as [When Attacking] effects is still performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card\u2019s inherited effect activates, is an attack considered to have never occurred?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  <Blast Digivolve> is performed at the end of the counter timing. If you activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect, the attack will end before [Counter] effects trigger during the counter timing, therefore <Blast Digivolve> can no longer be performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use <Blast Digivolve> to digivolve my Digimon if I activate this card's inherited effect and end the attack from an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [End of Attack] effects activate if I activate this card's inherited effect and end the attack from an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent has 5 or fewer cards in their hand, which player gains \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e from this card\u2019s [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include only either a card with the [Fallen Angel]/[Demon Lord]\u00a0trait or a purple Option card, can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal for this card's [On Play] effect include both a card with the [Fallen Angel]/[Demon Lord]\u00a0trait and a purple Option card, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if you add 2 cards to your hand, you only trash 1 card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I add both a card with the [Fallen Angel]/[Demon Lord]\u00a0trait and a purple Option card to my hand for this card's [On Play] effect, do I trash 2 cards in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.  Until the end of your opponent's turn, 1 of their Digimon gains that effect, so the [End of Attack] effect will activate even if the affected Digimon digivolves or de-digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon affected by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect attacked the opponent player, then a [Security] effect gave this Digimon \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) and trashed it. Does the [End of Attack] effect activate in such cases?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect triggers simultaneously with [When Attacking] effects. The turn player's effects will resolve first, then this effect will resolve, then the attack will end.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon attacks, can this card's inherited effect end the attack before [When Attacking] effects activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. After the battle is resolved, the timing for activation of effects has already passed, so the effect can't activate.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When an opponent's Digimon attacks, can I activate this card's inherited effect after comparing DP for the battle and end the attack at that timing?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The attack is considered to occur, therefore [When Attacking] effects and other processes are still performed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's inherited effect activates, is an attack considered to have never occurred?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  <Blast Digivolve> is performed at the end of the counter timing. If you activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect, the attack will end before [Counter] effects trigger during the counter timing, therefore <Blast Digivolve> can no longer be performed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use <Blast Digivolve> to digivolve my Digimon if I activate this card's inherited effect and end the attack from an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do [End of Attack] effects activate if I activate this card's inherited effect and end the attack from an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player gains <Recovery +1 \u226aDeck\u226b> for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can be chosen as a target for the effect, but the \"if this effect didn't delete\" effect will activate without your opponent's Digimon being deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is activated when my opponent only has a Digimon with a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect in their battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This effect reads \"you may play,\" so if you perform the conditions specified for \"by X,\" you may choose whether or not to activate the effect shown in text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon would leave the battle area, can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to return 1 [Lucemon] from its digivolution cards or my trash to the bottom of the deck, but choose to not play 1 [Lucemon: Satan Mode] or 1 level 6 [Seven Great Demon Lords]\u00a0trait Digimon card from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-056": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash other than as a result of a battle, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This Digimon hasn't yet been sent to the trash because this effect activates when this Digimon would leave the battle area, so you can't choose it from the trash as the card to place as the bottom digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to place this Digimon itself as the bottom digivolution card of my [Gate of Deadly Sins] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-057": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon with a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect can also be chosen as a target for this effect, therefore your opponent's Digimon will be affected by this card's effect as soon as it loses the \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect.  As a result, it's deleted at the [End of Your Turn] timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is given to a Digimon that activated a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects until the end of your opponent's turn\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash other than as a result of a battle, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area other than by [...] a battle\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to delete an opponent's level 5 or lower Digimon and prevent this card from leaving the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If the card deleted has no level, you can't trash any cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect deletes an opponent's Digimon with no level (such as a \"Lv.-\" Digimon), can I use this effect to trash cards from my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash other than as a result of a battle, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area other than by [...] a battle\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This Digimon hasn't yet been sent to the trash because this effect activates when this Digimon would leave the battle area, so you can't choose it from the trash as the card to place as the bottom digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to place this Digimon itself as the bottom digivolution card of my [Gate of Deadly Sins] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-059": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to play a purple Tamer card from my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It means that you reduce the maximum for the play cost of the card that can be played by this effect by 1 for each card in your opponent's hand.  For example, if your opponent has 4 cards in their hand, you would reduce 10 by 4, resulting in a maximum play cost of 6, meaning that you can play 1 purple card with a play cost of 6 or less without paying the cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"for each card in your opponent's hand, reduce this effect's play cost maximum by 1\" in this card's [All Turns] effect mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash other than as a result of a battle, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area other than by [...] a battle\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This Digimon hasn't yet been sent to the trash because this effect activates when this Digimon would leave the battle area, so you can't choose it from the trash as the card to place as the bottom digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to place this Digimon itself as the bottom digivolution card of my [Gate of Deadly Sins] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers and activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st [All Turns] effect trigger when this card itself is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area other than by battle\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash other than as a result of a battle, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area other than by [...] a battle\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This Digimon hasn't yet been sent to the trash because this effect activates when this Digimon would leave the battle area, so you can't choose it from the trash as the card to place as the bottom digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's 2nd [All Turns] effect to place this Digimon itself as the bottom digivolution card of my [Gate of Deadly Sins] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's DNA digivolution can only be performed using a combination of 1 level 6 yellow or black Digimon and 1 level 6 green or purple Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When DNA digivolving into this card, can I DNA digivolve using a level 6 yellow Digimon and a level 6 black Digimon, or using a level 6 green Digimon and a level 6 purple Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's <Partition (yellow/black Lv.6 & green/purple Lv.6)> effect can only play a combination of 1 level 6 yellow or black Digimon and 1 level 6 green or purple Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's <Partition (yellow/black Lv.6 & green/purple Lv.6)> effect to play a level 6 yellow Digimon and a level 6 black Digimon or a level 6 green Digimon and a level 6 purple Digimon from digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-063": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It references the Digimon after it digivolves.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect reference the card for the Digimon before or after it digivolves?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this card's [Your Turn] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve into a Digimon card with the [Beastkin]/[Holy Beast]/[Cherub]\u00a0trait in the hand regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve a Digimon other than my Digimon that was suspended by an effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to play a Digimon from digivolution cards when my Digimon with the[Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and [EX6-042 RaijiLudomon] in its digivolution cards would be deleted, can I then use [EX6-042 RaijiLudomon]'s inherited effect to prevent the deletion?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the Digimon card placed from the hand as the bottom digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"the placed card\" in this card's [Main] effect refer to the Digimon card with [Aqua] or [Sea Animal] in one of its traits placed from my hand as the bottom digivolution card, or does it refer to my blue Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to place this card in the battle area without placing 1 Digimon card with the [Angel]/[Archangel]/[Three Great Angels]\u00a0trait from the hand at the bottom of my security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card to place this card in the battle area without placing 1 [Seven Great Demon Lords]\u00a0trait Digimon card from my hand or trash as the bottom digivolution card of my [Gate of Deadly Sins] in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: A Digimon with a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect can also be chosen as a target for this effect, therefore your opponent's Digimon will be affected by this card's effect as soon as it loses the \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect.  As a result, it's deleted at the [End of Your Turn] timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if this card's [Main] effect is given to a Digimon that activated a \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects until the end of your opponent's turn\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card when my opponent has 4 or fewer cards in their hand and they don't trash 1 card in their hand, does the \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with as high or higher a level as the number of cards in their hand\" effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can\u2019t ignore the requirements specified for DNA digivolution when using this card's [Main] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to DNA digivolve using 1 of my Digimon that isn't specified for DNA digivolution and a card in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they are.  When cards such as [Leviamon] and [Leviamon (X Antibody)] differ in that one has [X Antibody] and the other doesn't, you can reference the cards as if they have different names.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [Leviamon] and [Leviamon (X Antibody)] are in this card's digivolution cards, are they considered \"cards with different names\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It activates if 4 or more cards are first placed for the [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect. Even if you have 4 or more [Seven Great Demon Lords]\u00a0trait cards with different names in digivolution cards, the effect won't activate unless you first place 4 or more cards for the [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"if 4 or more were placed\" in this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect mean that the effect activates if I first place 4 or more cards for the [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect? Or does it activate if 4 or more [Seven Great Demon Lords]\u00a0trait cards with different names are in digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you activate this effect, you must return 7 [Seven Great Demon Lords]\u00a0trait cards with different names from this Digimon's digivolution cards to the bottom of the deck in order to delete 7 of your opponent's Digimon or Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I return 1 to 7 [Seven Great Demon Lords]\u00a0trait cards with different names from this Digimon's digivolution cards to the bottom of the deck, can I use this card's 2nd [When Attacking] effect to delete the same number of my opponent's Digimon or Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Deleting 7 of your opponent's Digimon or Tamers is mandatory for this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's 2nd [When Attacking] effect to trash 7 cards from my opponent's security stack without deleting their Digimon or Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If it isn't deleted, then the number of security cards trashed isn't reduced by 1.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I would use this card's 2nd [When Attacking] effect to delete 7 of my opponent's Digimon or Tamers, if an opponent's Digimon isn't deleted due to an \"isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect or other reason, does that mean that the number of security cards trashed isn't reduced by 1 for that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX6-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this card's [Your Turn] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to digivolve into [Angewomon] or [LadyDevimon] in the trash regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated this card's [Your Turn] effect when I played [ST10-04 Gatomon]. At such times, I want to digivolve [ST10-04 Gatomon] into  [Angewomon] or [LadyDevimon] with the cost reduced by 1, but can I use [ST10-04 Gatomon]'s [Your Turn] effect to reduce the digivolution cost again by 2?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in the hand that doesn't have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to DNA digivolve using Digimon cards in the hand that aren't specified in [DNA Digivolution]?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose either your Digimon or an opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose either my Digimon or an opponent's Digimon for this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't gain the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect give it the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait when it's in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: 5 cards.  BT10-077 [MadLeomon]'s [Opponent's Turn] effect trashes cards equal to the number of cards added.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent activates BT10-077 [MadLeomon]'s [Opponent's Turn] effect when I used this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to draw 5 cards from the top of my deck, how many cards do I trash from my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Your opponent can't play Digimon with 6000 DP or less, and they can't move Digimon with 6000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect prevent my opponent from playing or moving any Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This card's [When Digivolving] effect prevents your opponent from playing or moving Digimon with 6000 DP or less. EX5-058 [Octomon]'s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is an effect where you play a token, therefore you aren't prevented from playing it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During a turn when this card's [When Digivolving] effect has activated, can I use EX5-058 [Octomon]'s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to play a [Fujitsumon] Token into my opponent's battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be moved.  This card's [When Digivolving] effect also prevents effects from moving Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent use P-143 [Drimogemon]'s [End of Your Turn] effect to move it from the battle area to the breeding area during their next turn after this card's [When Digivolving] effect has activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't place it for that DigiXros.  You declare the DigiXros at the same time as when you choose the cards to place for the DigiXros. Once placed, additional cards to place can't be chosen.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated this card's [All Turns] effect when this card in the battle area was placed for a DigiXros. Can I place the card that was played by this [All Turns] effect for that DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents costs from being reduced when play costs are to be paid. This effect affects both players.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"players can't reduce play costs\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  \"Play this card without paying the cost\" effects aren't effects that reduce the play cost.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"players can't reduce play costs\" effect has activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, play costs can't be reduced.  A \"players can't reduce play costs\" effect isn't an effect that affects cards that activate play-cost-reducing effects, it's an effect that affects players. Therefore, the target players can't reduce play costs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"players can't reduce play costs\" effect has activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, DigiXrosing is possible.  However, it isn't possible to reduce play costs through DigiXrosing. Therefore, a player can't declare to play a card in a state where its play cost can't be paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"players can't reduce play costs\" effect has activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If cards that are targets of this effect are revealed from the deck, do I have to add as many cards to my hand as possible?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  If an effect's trigger conditions are met when the effect is gained, that effect will trigger.  In this case, your opponent no longer has Digimon with digivolution cards at the same timing as when your opponent's Digimon is deleted in battle, therefore you can activate \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacked, an opponent's Digimon with digivolution cards was deleted in the battle, and after that battle, my opponent doesn't have any Digimon with digivolution cards.  This Digimon gains \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from this card's inherited effect at such times, but does the \uff1cPiercing\uff1e trigger simultaneously?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This card's [Your Turn] effect affects all of your Digimon with the [NSp]\u00a0trait, not your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to prevent attacks by all of my Digimon with the [NSp]\u00a0trait from being blocked by my opponent's Digimon that aren't affected by Digimon effects and have \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be suspended.  This card's [Opponent's Turn] effect affects all of your opponent's Digimon with as many or fewer digivolution cards as this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in the battle area with 1 digivolution card under it.  If an opponent's Digimon with 1 digivolution card under it later has 2 or more digivolution cards through digivolution or other process during their turn, can I suspend that opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a card with the [Puppet]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's [On Deletion] effect can play a play cost 4 or lower Digimon card that has the [NSp]\u00a0trait or a play cost 4 or lower yellow Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What Digimon cards can be played using this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they trigger simultaneously.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's <Overclock ([Puppet]\u00a0trait)> to attack by deleting a [Familiar] Token, do this card's [When Attacking] effect and the [Familiar] Token's [On Deletion] effect trigger simultaneously?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a card with [Avian] or [Bird] in any of its traits?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.  The processing for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect includes choosing 1 of your opponent's Digimon, suspending the chosen Digimon, and giving the chosen Digimon \"that Digimon can't unsuspend until the end of their turn.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon chosen for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect can't be suspended, does it still gain \"that Digimon can't unsuspend until the end of their turn\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can DNA digivolve using a level 6 green or yellow Digimon and a level 6 black or blue Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What DNA digivolution combinations are possible with this card's DNA digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's deleted.  Deletion when DP becomes 0 is due to the rule processing, not an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect prevent it from being deleted even if this card's DP becomes 0 due to an opponent's effect during my opponent's turn?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can choose 3 cards with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait to return to the top of the deck from your hand, trash, or both.  For example, you can choose 3 cards from your hand or choose a combination of 1 card from your hand and 2 cards from your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to only choose cards from my hand or trash when I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to return 3 cards with the [Three Musketeers]\u00a0trait to the top of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-049": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can digivolve it.  Digimon that aren't affected by effects aren't affected by this card's [When Digivolving] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve a level 4 or lower Digimon that isn't affected by effects in the battle area during their next turn after this card's [When Digivolving] effect has activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can digivolve it.  This card's [When Digivolving] effect only affects your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon in the battle area. It doesn't affect Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve a level 4 or lower Digimon in the breeding area during their next turn after this card's [When Digivolving] effect has activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't digivolve it.  This card's [When Digivolving] effect also affects Digimon that were played after it activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent digivolve a level 4 or lower Digimon that was played after this card's [When Digivolving] effect has activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't place it for that DigiXros.  You declare the DigiXros at the same time as when you choose the cards to place for the DigiXros. Once placed, additional cards to place can't be chosen.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated this card's [All Turns] effect when this card in the battle area was placed for a DigiXros. Can I place the card that was played by this [All Turns] effect for that DigiXros?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a card with the [Dark Dragon]/[Evil Dragon]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't end that attack.  If the \"by doing X\" condition isn't met, the rest of the effect isn't processed. In this case, if you can't delete 1 of your other Digimon, then you can't end the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I tried to delete 1 of my other Digimon using this card's inherited effect when an opponent's Digimon attacked, but I couldn't delete the other Digimon due to another effect. Can I end that attack at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After this effect activates, the current timing makes a transition to the end of attack timing. For example, if this effect activates during the attack declaration timing, it will make a transition to the end of attack timing. A transition to the counter timing or block timing won't occur, and the attack won't succeed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"end that attack\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can end such attacks.  \"End that attack\" effects are effects that change the timing, they don't affect an attacking Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can an \"end that attack\" effect end an attack by a Digimon that isn't affected by effects?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-054": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't end that attack.  If the \"by doing X\" condition isn't met, the rest of the effect isn't processed. In this case, if you can't delete 1 of your other Digimon, then you can't end the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I tried to delete 1 of my other Digimon using this card's inherited effect when an opponent's Digimon attacked, but I couldn't delete the other Digimon due to another effect. Can I end that attack at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After this effect activates, the current timing makes a transition to the end of attack timing. For example, if this effect activates during the attack declaration timing, it will make a transition to the end of attack timing. A transition to the counter timing or block timing won't occur, and the attack won't succeed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"end that attack\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can end such attacks.  \"End that attack\" effects are effects that change the timing, they don't affect an attacking Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can an \"end that attack\" effect end an attack by a Digimon that isn't affected by effects?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-058": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can give that effect to such Digimon, but Digimon that aren't affected by effects won't be affected by it, therefore the gained effect won't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to give \"[End of Attack] Delete this Digimon\" to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  If this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect gives \"[End of Attack] Delete this Digimon\" to a Digimon, then it triggers, that Digimon's player will be the player considered to have triggered/activated that effect, therefore <Partition> won't trigger.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to give \"[End of Attack] Delete this Digimon\" to a Digimon, then it's deleted, does <Partition> on that Digimon trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it leaves the battle area.  If the \"by doing X\" condition isn't met, the rest of the effect isn't processed.  In such cases, this card leaves the battle area if the deletion isn't possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attempted to delete 1 of my other Digimon using this card's 1st [All Turns] effect when this card would leave the battle area other than in battle, but I couldn't delete that Digimon due to another effect. Does this card leave the battle area at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  As soon as the player chooses to activate an [X Per Turn] effect, it will count toward 1 use of [X Per Turn]. In this case, as soon as you attempt to delete another Digimon using this card's 1st [All Turns] effect, it will count toward [1 Per Turn], and the effect won't trigger again during that turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I tried to delete my opponent's EX7-061 [Lilithmon (X Antibody)] using this card's 1st [All Turns] effect.  At such times, if my opponent tries to delete this card using the 1st [All Turns] effect on the chosen EX7-061 [Lilithmon (X Antibody)], does this card\u2019s 1st [All Turns] effect trigger again?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  \uff1cVortex\uff1e triggers simultaneously with [End of Your Turn] effects, therefore you can choose the activation order of these effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to unsuspend my Digimon with the [Vortex Warriors]\u00a0trait, can I then activate \uff1cVortex\uff1e on that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  \uff1cVortex\uff1e triggers simultaneously with [End of Your Turn] effects, therefore you can choose the activation order of these effects.  In this case, you can activate \uff1cVortex\uff1e and make an attack declaration, this card's effect that triggered simultaneously will activate, then the counter timing will occur.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate \uff1cVortex\uff1e on my Digimon with the [Vortex Warriors]\u00a0trait, then activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The part of the effect after \"then\" will be processed regardless of whether or not you trash digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I didn't trash digivolution cards of my opponent's Digimon with this card's [Main] effect, can I process the part of the effect after \"then\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can give that effect to such Digimon, but Digimon that aren't affected by effects won't be affected by it, therefore the gained effect won't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to give \"[End of Your Turn] Delete 1 of your Digimon\" to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.  After this card's [Main] effect gives \"[End of Your Turn] Delete 1 of your Digimon\" to a Digimon, then it triggers, that Digimon's player will be the player considered to have triggered/activated that effect, therefore <Partition> won't trigger.[2]",
      "question": "Q: After this card's [Main] effect gives \"[End of Your Turn] Delete 1 of your Digimon\" to a Digimon, then that effect deletes a Digimon, does <Partition> on that Digimon trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "EX7-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't ignore its color requirements.  The breeding area can't be referenced unless the effect specifies the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's 1st effect to ignore this card's color requirements while I have a Digimon with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect even if my opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards are deleted at the same timing?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect even if my opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards are deleted at the same timing?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can suspend either player's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can suspend either player's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't attack.  If a \"can\" or \"may\" effect activates at the same timing as a \"can't\" effect, the \"can't\" effect takes precedence.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in the battle area, and it's suspended.  Can my opponent's BT8-018 [Marsmon] attack their unsuspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can.  This card's [Opponent's Turn] effect only allows suspended Digimon to be chosen as the attack target upon the attack declaration.  After attacking a suspended Digmon, it will be possible to use \uff1cRaid\uff1e to switch the target of the attack to an opponent's unsuspended Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in the battle area, and it's suspended.  If my opponent's Digimon attacks my suspended Digimon, can my opponent use \uff1cRaid\uff1e on the attacking Digimon to switch the target of the attack to my unsuspended Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in the battle area, and it's suspended.  If an opponent's Digimon isn't affected by effects, can it attack Digimon other than suspended Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t trigger.  Only effects with the [Breeding] icon trigger and activate in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card is in the breeding area and would digivolve into a Digimon card with the [Ice-Snow]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  For this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, you chose 1 of your opponent's Digmon with no digivolution cards to gain \"can't suspend or activate [When Digivolving] effects.\"  The effect will continue affecting the chosen Digimon even if it later gets a digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to give \"can't suspend or activate [When Digivolving] effects\" to 1 of my opponent's Digmon with no digivolution cards.  If that Digimon later gains digivolution cards after being affected by that effect, can it suspend or activate [When Digivolving] effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  If an effect's trigger conditions are met when the effect is gained, that effect will trigger.  In this case, your opponent no longer has Digimon with digivolution cards at the same timing as when your opponent's Digimon is deleted in battle, therefore you can activate \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacked, an opponent's Digimon with digivolution cards was deleted in the battle, and after that battle, my opponent doesn't have any Digimon with digivolution cards.  This Digimon gains \uff1cPiercing\uff1e from this card's inherited effect at such times, but does the \uff1cPiercing\uff1e trigger simultaneously?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents [When Digivolving] effects on cards from activating.  Triggered [When Digivolving] effects can no longer activate when a card digivolves or when effects such as \"activate that card's [When Digivolving]\" effect\" activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The effect can activate if it's triggered upon the [When Attacking] timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used a card affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" to attack.  Can I activate that card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects,\" can it activate its own [When Digivolving] effect using an effect such as \"activate 1 of that card's [When Digivolving] effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects,\" can another card's [When Digivolving] effect be activated using an effect such as \"activate 1 of that card's [When Digivolving] effects as an effect of this card\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \"activate 1 of that card's [When Digivolving] effects as an effect of this card\" on a card that isn't affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" to activate the [When Digivolving] effect on another card that's affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects,\" can I process just the \"by doing X\" condition in its [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't count.  The effect can't activate upon the [When Digivolving] timing, therefore it doesn't count as an instance of that effect's [X Per Turn].[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card digivolved into a card that has a [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] effect while \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" was activated.  Does that count as an instance of that effect's [X Per Turn] even if that effect can't be activated upon the timing when that card digivolved?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 1 or further to the left on your side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"if you have 1 or more memory\" refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 1 or further to the left on your side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"if you have 1 or more memory\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't attack.  This card's [All Turns] effect will activate as soon as you have 1 or more memory, therefore none of your opponent's Digimon can suspend, and they can't attack unless they can suspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card in the battle area.  An opponent's Digimon digivolved into a Digimon card that has \uff1cBlitz\uff1e, and I now have 1 or more memory. Can that Digimon use \uff1cBlitz\uff1e to attack at such times?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card itself is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when a card digivolves into this card itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player can choose the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Your Turn] effect to DNA digivolve, then I attacked using that Digimon.  At such times, in what order can I activate that Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect and [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I place either my Digimon or an opponent's Digimon as the bottom security card for this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 1 or further to the left on your side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"if you have 1 or more memory\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 1 or further to the right on your side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"while you have 1 or less\" memory refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents [On Play] effects on cards from activating.  Triggered [On Play] effects can no longer activate when a card is played or when effects such as \"activate that card's [On Play]\" effect\" activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The effect can activate if it's triggered upon the [When Attacking] timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used a card affected by \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects\" to attack.  Can I activate that card's [On Play] [When Attacking] effect at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects,\" can it activate its own [On Play] effect using an effect such as \"activate 1 of that card's [On Play] effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects,\" can another card's [On Play] effect be activated using an effect such as \"activate 1 of that card's [On Play] effects as an effect of this card\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \"activate 1 of that card's [On Play] effects as an effect of this card\" on a card that isn't affected by \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects\" to activate the [On Play] effect on another card that's affected by \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects,\" can I perform just the \"by doing X\" condition in its [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't count.  The effect can't activate upon the [On Play] timing, therefore it doesn't count as an instance of that effect's [X Per Turn].[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card digivolved into a card that has an [On Play] [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] effect while \"none of your opponent's Digimon can activate [On Play] effects\" was activated.  Does that count as an instance of that effect's [X Per Turn] even if that effect can't be activated upon the timing when that card is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents Digimon from being affected by effects.  For example, your Digmon won't suspend if it's chosen for a \"suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon\" effect, and its DP won't be reduced if it's chosen for a \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -3000 DP\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be chosen.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card that has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect be chosen for an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  However, it won't be affected by it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card that has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect be given an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As soon as it gains the \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, it will no longer be affected.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by an effect, then it later gains an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, what happens to the effect that was affecting it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be affected by the effect as soon as it can be affected by effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, it gains an effect, then it later loses the \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, what happens to the effect that it gained?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t trigger.  If an effect is given to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects, it won't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card that has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect was given an effect that triggers at a timing such as [When Attacking].  Will the effect trigger if that card later meets the trigger conditions?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: With this effect, your opponent's memory will no longer increase by any effects except Tamer effects. This effect affects the opponent player.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"your opponent can't gain memory other than by Tamer effects\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  When an effect is activated on a card that's treated as both a Digimon and a Tamer, the effect is treated as both a Digimon effect and a Tamer effect, therefore you can gain memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I gain memory using an effect on a Tamer that's treated as a Digimon with X000 DP due to an effect while my opponent has \"your opponent can't gain memory other than by Tamer effects\" activated?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 1 or further to the left on your side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"if you have 1 or more memory\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents [When Digivolving] effects on cards from activating.  Triggered [When Digivolving] effects can no longer activate when a card digivolves or when effects such as \"activate that card's [When Digivolving]\" effect\" activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The effect can activate if it's triggered upon the [When Attacking] timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used a card affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" to attack.  Can I activate that card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect at such times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects,\" can it activate its own [When Digivolving] effect using an effect such as \"activate 1 of that card's [When Digivolving] effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects,\" can another card's [When Digivolving] effect be activated using an effect such as \"activate 1 of that card's [When Digivolving] effects as an effect of this card\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \"activate 1 of that card's [When Digivolving] effects as an effect of this card\" on a card that isn't affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" to activate the [When Digivolving] effect on another card that's affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects,\" can I process just the \"by doing X\" condition in its [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't count.  The effect can't activate upon the [When Digivolving] timing, therefore it doesn't count as an instance of that effect's [X Per Turn].[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card digivolved into a card that has a [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] [Once Per Turn] effect while \"can't [...] activate [When Digivolving] effects\" was activated.  Does that count as an instance of that effect's [X Per Turn] even if that effect can't be activated upon the timing when that card digivolved?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Once you activate the effect on the Option card you used with this card's [Your Turn] effect, then you process the part of the effect after \"if this effect used.\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to use an Option card, when is the part of the effect after \"if this effect used\" processed?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can suspend either player's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to suspend either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can suspend either player's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-041": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect suspend a different card from the one that's given \"can't unsuspend until the end of their turn\"?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-042": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect even if my opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards are deleted at the same timing?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-043": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can suspend either player's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't activate it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card\u2019s inherited effect even if my opponent's Digimon and the Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards are deleted at the same timing?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can suspend either player's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-045": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can use \uff1cPiercing\uff1e to perform a security check.  As soon as this card deletes an opponent's Digimon in battle, the \uff1cPiercing\uff1e gained from this card's [Your Turn] effect and the deleted Digimon's [On Deletion] effect will trigger simultaneously, then the turn player's \uff1cPiercing\uff1e will activate first.  When \uff1cPiercing\uff1e activates, \"perform check before End of Attack timing\" processing will be pending, and the check will be performed immediately before the End of Attack timing, even if \uff1cPiercing\uff1e is lost after activation.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has no Digimon with as much or more DP as this card in the battle area.  I used this card to attack an opponent's Digimon, and the opponent's Digimon is deleted in the battle.  Then, if an [On Deletion] effect on the deleted opponent's Digimon activates and my opponent now has a Digimon with as much or more DP as this Digimon, can I use the gained \uff1cPiercing\uff1e to perform a security check?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, a 2nd security check can't be performed using that \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.  The \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e gained from this card's [Your Turn] effect is lost as soon as your opponent has a Digimon with as much or more DP as this card, therefore you can't use the gained \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e to perform a security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has no Digimon with as much or more DP as this card in the battle area.  This card performs a security check, the [Security] effect on the 1st card checked activates, and my opponent now has a Digimon with as much or more DP as this card.  Can I then use the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e gained from this card's [Your Turn] effect to perform a 2nd security check?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-050": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It can play 1 [Mineral]\u00a0trait Digimon card with a play cost of 5 or less, or it can play 1 [Rock]\u00a0trait Digimon card with a play cost of 5 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards can be played using this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player can choose the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Multiple effects trigger when this card digivolves. In what order do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect trashes an Option card that was placed by a \"place this card in the battle area\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does the \"trash 1 Option card in your opponent's battle area\" effect do, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-053": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It can play 1 [Mineral]\u00a0trait Digimon card with a play cost of 8 or less, or it can play 1 [Rock]\u00a0trait Digimon card with a play cost of 8 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards can be played using this card's [On Deletion] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-055": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect to trash a total of 3 digivolution cards from my multiple different Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.  The conditions for this [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect require you to trash the specified number of digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I trash just 2 digivolution cards for the conditions of this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to place Digi-Egg cards with the [Mineral]/[Rock]\u00a0trait from my trash as digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If this card's [End of Your Turn] effect activates, you must place at least 1 card in digivolution cards.  However, if you choose to not activate this effect, it won't activate and you don't place any cards in digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [End of Your Turn] effect but choose to not to place cards with the [Mineral]/[Rock]\u00a0trait from my trash as this Digimon's bottom digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-060": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when this card itself is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger when a card digivolves into this card itself?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't attack. A new attack declaration can't be made during an attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card attacks, and I use its [When Attacking] effect to play an [NSo]\u00a0trait Digimon.  If I then use this card's [Your Turn] effect to DNA digivolve using 2 of my Digimon, can I use that Digimon to attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player can choose the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Your Turn] effect to DNA digivolve, then I attacked using that Digimon.  At such times, in what order can I activate that Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect and [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-061": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 1 or further to the left on your side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"if you have 1 or more memory\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can play 1 level 4 or lower Digimon card with the [DS]\u00a0trait, 1 level 4 or lower Digimon card with the [Mollusk]\u00a0trait, or 1 level 4 or lower Digimon card with the [Crustacean]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards can be played using this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can play 1 level 4 or lower Digimon card with the [DS]\u00a0trait, 1 level 4 or lower Digimon card with the [Mollusk]\u00a0trait, or 1 level 4 or lower Digimon card with the [Crustacean]\u00a0trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What cards can be played using this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-062": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \"\u30fb1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -2000 DP for the turn\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to give the same Digimon -2000 DP multiple times?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \"\u30fb1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -2000 DP for the turn\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to give different Digimon -2000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't deleted yet.  This card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates \"\u30fb1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -2000 DP for the turn\" 4 times, then all Digimon with 0 DP are deleted at the same timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I activated \"\u30fb1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -2000 DP for the turn\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect once, and the DP of the opponent's Digimon was reduced to 0.  Is that Digimon deleted before the effect activates 3 more times?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-064": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  Even if you use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to reduce the DP of an opponent's Digimon to 0, it isn't yet deleted at that time. After you play EX8-062 [Piedmon ACE] from your trash and this effect is resolved, then all Digimon with 0 DP are deleted at the same timing.  Digimon with a DP of 0 are deleted after playing EX8-062 [Piedmon ACE], then EX8-062 [Piedmon ACE]'s [All Turns] effect will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Digivolving] effect to reduce the DP of an opponent's Digimon to 0, then I played EX8-062 [Piedmon ACE].  Does that EX8-062 [Piedmon ACE]'s [All Turns] effect trigger at such times?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-065": [
    {
      "answer": "A: EX8-014 [MasterTyrannomon]'s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates first.  As soon as your [Tyrannomon] attacks, the [Your Turn] effects on the 2 copies of this card trigger simultaneously.  The effect on the 1st copy of this card is used to digivolve into EX8-014 [MasterTyrannomon], then EX8-014 [MasterTyrannomon]'s [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect is newly triggered, therefore that effect activates first due to the derived triggering rule.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 2 copies of this card in the battle area.  My [Tyrannomon] attacks, and I activate the effect on the 1st copy of this card to digivolve it into EX8-014 [MasterTyrannomon].  At such times, does the [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect on the 2nd copy of this card or EX8-014 [MasterTyrannomon] activate first?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-067": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to place Digi-Egg cards with the [Mineral]/[Rock]\u00a0trait from my trash as digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-068": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it's met.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is the \"while you have no face-up security cards\" condition met when I have 0 cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you can't add a card from your security stack to your hand, therefore you only place this card in your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card\u2019s [Main] effect when I have 0 cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 1 or further to the left on your side.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"if you have 1 or more memory\" refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is not deleted.  This card's [All Turns] effect will activate as soon as you have 1 or more memory, therefore none of your Digimon with the [DS]\u00a0trait will be deleted in battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card placed face-up in my security stack.  An opponent's Digimon digivolved, and I now have 1 or more memory.  If my opponent's digivolved Digimon activates an effect and my Digimon with the [DS]\u00a0trait attacks at such times, can this card's [All Turns] effect prevent my Digimon from being deleted in that battle?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-069": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is the \"while you have no face-up security cards\" condition met when I have 0 cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you can't add a card from your security stack to your hand, therefore you only place this card in your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card\u2019s [Main] effect when I have 0 cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Even \uff1cAlliance\uff1e is lost, the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and added DP remain.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have just this card placed face-up in my security stack.  I used my Digimon with the [NSp]\u00a0trait to attack, and I activated the \uff1cAlliance\uff1e gained from this card's [All Turns] effect.  If this card is then trashed by the 1st [All Turns] effect on my opponent's BT18-055 [AncientTroymon], what happens to the \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e and added DP gained from \uff1cAlliance\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-071": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is the \"while you have no face-up security cards\" condition met when I have 0 cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you can't add a card from your security stack to your hand, therefore you only place this card in your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card\u2019s [Main] effect when I have 0 cards in my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They become face-up security cards that remain revealed.  Other than rules that specify face-up security cards, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to cards placed face up in the security stack by effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The check is performed with the card left revealed.  Other than rules for cards left revealed, the rules apply in the same manner as standard security checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens upon a security check for a security card that is placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does a card's [Security] effect trigger upon a security check with that card placed face-up?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Any face-up cards are placed face down, then you shuffle the cards.  After shuffling, all cards are left face-down.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I shuffle a security stack that includes security cards placed face-up?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player can choose the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Multiple effects trigger when this card digivolves. In what order do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If your opponent has a Digimon with 10000 DP or less, you must choose that card and delete it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 10000 DP or less.  Can I meet the \"if this effect didn't delete\" condition in this card's [When Digivolving] [End of Attack] effect by not choosing a card to delete?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 10000 DP or less.  Can I meet the \"if this effect didn't delete\" condition in this card's [When Digivolving] [End of Attack] effect by choosing an opponent's Digimon with 10000 DP or less and an effect that prevents deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to when the memory gauge is at 0 or further to the right.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What position on the memory gauge does \"while you have 0 or less\" memory refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect prevents Digimon from being affected by effects.  For example, your Digmon won't suspend if it's chosen for a \"suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon\" effect, and its DP won't be reduced if it's chosen for a \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -3000 DP\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be chosen.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card that has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect be chosen for an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  However, it won't be affected by it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can a card that has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect be given an effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: As soon as it gains the \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, it will no longer be affected.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card is affected by an effect, then it later gains an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, what happens to the effect that was affecting it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It will be affected by the effect as soon as it can be affected by effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, it gains an effect, then it later loses the \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect, what happens to the effect that it gained?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t trigger.  If an effect is given to a Digimon that isn't affected by effects, it won't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A card that has an \"isn't affected by [...] effects\" effect was given an effect that triggers at a timing such as [When Attacking].  Will the effect trigger if that card later meets the trigger conditions?"
    }
  ],
  "EX8-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can suspend either player's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to suspend either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  A \"by doing X\" condition can't be met if only some of the required actions are performed.  The conditions for this card's 1st effect require you to suspend the specified number of Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the conditions for this card's 1st effect to just suspend 1 Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when this card itself is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon is played?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-002": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  At the start of your main phase, the [Start of Your Main Phase] effect on 2 of this Digimon simultaneously trigger, then the player determines the activation order. However, because your hand increases to 8 cards from \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e on the 1st Digimon, the effect's conditions aren't met for the 2nd Digimon, so the effect doesn't activate. As a result, you only draw 1 card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are 7 cards in my hand and I have 2 of this Digimon at the start of my main phase, can I draw a total of 2 cards from both instances of this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Upon the attack declaration, the inherited effects on the 2 copies of this card simultaneously trigger, then the player determines the activation order. However, because your hand increases to 8 cards from \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e on the 1st card, the effect's conditions aren't met for the 2nd card, so the effect doesn't activate. As a result, you only draw 1 card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 7 cards in my hand upon an attack by my Digimon with 2 of this card in its digivolution cards, can I draw a total of 2 cards from both instances of this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is not deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Attacking] effect prevent deletion in battles against Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Deletion by \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e is deletion by an effect, not deletion in battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Attacking] effect prevent deletion even when my opponent's deleted Digimon has \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Upon the attack declaration, the inherited effects on the 2 copies of this card simultaneously trigger, then the player determines the activation order. However, because your hand increases to 8 cards from \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e on the 1st card, the effect's conditions aren't met for the 2nd card, so the effect doesn't activate. As a result, you only draw 1 card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 7 cards in my hand upon an attack by my Digimon with 2 of this card in its digivolution cards, can I draw a total of 2 cards from both instances of this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I trash 2 blue cards in my hand, can I use this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect to trash 1 card under each of 2 of my opponent's Digimon/Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Attacking] effect activates once from an attack, then this Digimon is unsuspended by an effect, attacks again, and the effect activates again in the same turn, does this Digimon gain 2 total instances of \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e, resulting in 2 additional security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can now attack.  This card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect targets \"none of their Digimon with no digivolution cards,\" therefore Digimon that no longer meet the conditions can no longer be effect targets.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent activated this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect. If my Digimon without digivolution cards then gains digivolution cards by digivolving or other method, can it now attack?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If this Digimon is in the battle area at the end of an attack, you must activate the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I have to activate this card's [End of Attack] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The digivolution cost is only reduced by 2 when it would digivolve into a card with [Angoramon] in its text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to reduce the digivolution cost by 2 when my Digimon with [Angoramon] in its text would digivolve into a Digimon card without [Angoramon] in its text?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  As soon as the digivolution is complete, this card becomes a digivolution card, and its effects can no longer activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon would digivolve into a Digimon card with the [Angoramon] in its text, I used this card's effect to suspend this Digimon and reduce the digivolution cost by 2. At such times, can I use this card's \"when this Digimon becomes suspended\" effect to give this Digimon \uff1cRush\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect give 1 on my Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e even when my opponent has no Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-013": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The top card is returned to the hand and all of the cards under it are trashed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Attacking] effect to play a Digimon card with [Angoramon] in its text. What happens if it digivolves and has a card on top of it at the end of my opponent's turn?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [All Turns] effect to delete this Digimon and prevent my Digimon with [Gammamon] in its text from leaving the battle area when this Digimon and my Digimon with [Gammamon] would leave the battle area at the same time due to a single effect?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to the four card categories: Digi-Egg cards, Digimon cards, Tamer cards, and Option cards.  You declare 1 of these categories at the start of your opponent's turn for this card's effect, your opponent reveals the top card of their deck, and if the revealed card is in the declared category, this Digimon will be unaffected by effects from cards in the declared card category.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"declare 1 card category\" in this card's [Start of Opponent's Turn] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be declared.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [Start of Opponent's Turn] effect declare card categories that do not go into the deck, such as Digi-Egg cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's affected by such effects.  Inherited effects on Tamer cards in digivolution cards of Digimon are treated as Digimon effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I declared Tamer cards for this card's [Start of Opponent's Turn] effect, and a Tamer card was revealed from the deck.  In such cases, is this Digimon unaffected by inherited effects on Tamer cards in digivolution cards of my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I declared Digimon cards for this card's [Start of Opponent's Turn] effect. If a Digimon card is revealed from the deck, is this Digimon unaffected by [Security] effects activated by Security Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] is chosen as the target to place in the security stack, it will ultimately be placed at the bottom of the Digi-Egg deck instead of the security stack according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by placing 1 Digimon on top of its owner's security stack\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the security stack, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the security stack\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] from the battle area to the security stack, reveal all cards in my opponent's security stack, and place 1 card among them at the top of my opponent's deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If your token is chosen as the target to place in the security stack, it will ultimately be removed from the game instead of being placed in the security stack according to the rules, but it meets this card's \"by placing 1 Digimon on top of its owner's security stack\" condition. A card isn't actually added to the security stack, therefore effects such as \"when a card is added to the security stack\" don't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return my token played as a Digimon from the battle area to the hand, reveal all cards in my opponent's security stack, and place 1 card among them at the top of my opponent's deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose my [EX2-007 Mother D-Reaper] or token that is treated as a Digimon in the battle area as the target for this card's [When Digivolving] effect, it isn't placed in the security stack. In such cases, do \"when a card is removed from the security stack\" effects trigger because a card wasn't added to the security stack even though it normally should have been added?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. It gains inherited effects.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Due to this card's [Start of Opponent's Turn] effect, this card no longer gets Digimon effects. At this time, does it no longer get the inherited effects of Digimon cards in this card's digivolution sources?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is not affected by them.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Due to this card's [Start of Opponent's Turn] effect, this card is no longer affected by Digimon effects. At this time, is this card not affected by the effects of my other Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this is a standard digivolution requirement for a Digimon card.  It references the number of your security cards, but it's not an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is \"[Digivolve] While you have 2 or fewer security cards, [Agumon]: Cost 3\" a digivolution requirement added by an effect while I have 2 or fewer security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Digivolution is possible as long as you have 2 or fewer security cards when you use <Blast Digivolve>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use <Blast Digivolve> to digivolve my [Agumon] into this card in the hand when I have 2 or fewer security cards and an opponent's Digimon attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  Digivolution from [Agumon] isn't possible because the digivolution requirements aren't met when you use <Blast Digivolve>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon attacks when I have 2 or fewer security cards, then an effect adds a card to my security stack so my security stack has 3 or more cards when I use <Blast Digivolve>, can my [Agumon] digivolve into this card in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  Digivolution from [Agumon] is possible as long as the digivolution requirements are met when you use <Blast Digivolve>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon attacks when I have 3 security cards, then an effect removes a card from my security stack so my security stack has 2 or fewer cards when I use <Blast Digivolve>, can my [Agumon] digivolve into this card in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect such as P-103 [Offense Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e that digivolves a Digimon, can my [Agumon] digivolve into this card in the hand when I have 2 or fewer security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect allows you to choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to the same as this Digimon's DP or less, then you delete all of them.  For example, if this Digimon has 14000 DP when its [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect activates, you can choose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose DP adds up to a total of 14000 or less, such as 1 with 10000 DP and 1 with 4000 DP, or 2 of their Digimon with 7000 DP each, then you delete them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"[On Play] [When Digivolving] Delete your opponent's Digimon up to a total DP equal to this Digimon's DP\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose any targets as long as their total DP adds up to a value less than or equal to this Digimon's DP. However, you must choose at least 1 of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP is equal to or less than this Digimon's DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I intentionally choose targets whose total DP adds up to a lower value than this Digimon's DP?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this is a standard digivolution requirement for a Digimon card.  It references the number of your security cards, but it's not an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is \"[Digivolve] While you have 2 or fewer security cards, [Gabumon]: Cost 3\" a digivolution requirement added by an effect while I have 2 or fewer security cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Digivolution is possible as long as you have 2 or fewer security cards when you use <Blast Digivolve>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use <Blast Digivolve> to digivolve my [Gabumon] into this card in the hand when I have 2 or fewer security cards and an opponent's Digimon attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  Digivolution from [Gabumon] isn't possible because the digivolution requirements aren't met when you use <Blast Digivolve>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon attacks when I have 2 or fewer security cards, then an effect adds a card to my security stack so my security stack has 3 or more cards when I use <Blast Digivolve>, can my [Gabumon] digivolve into this card in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Digivolution from [Gabumon] is possible as long as the digivolution requirements are met when you use <Blast Digivolve>.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If an opponent's Digimon attacks when I have 3 security cards, then an effect removes a card from my security stack so my security stack has 2 or fewer cards when I use <Blast Digivolve>, can my [Gabumon] digivolve into this card in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use an effect such as P-103 [Offense Training]'s \uff1cDelay\uff1e that digivolves a Digimon, can my [Gabumon] digivolve into this card in the hand when I have 2 or fewer security cards?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Option cards that reduce the cost upon use don't change the card's original cost, therefore you can't use this card's effect to place such a card on top of your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to place a card on top of my security stack, can I place an Option card with an original cost of 6 or more that has its cost reduced upon use?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If the cost of an Option card consistently changes when it's in the hand and becomes 5 or less due to that card's effect, you can use this card's effect to place it on top of your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to place an Option card on top of my security stack, can I place an Option card that had its cost reduced to 5 or less by a \"reduce the cost of this card in the hand by 1\" effect on a card such as BT2-099 [Glorious Burst] or BT8-097 [Crimson Blaze]?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both \"suspend 1 Digimon, and 1 of your Digimon gets +3000 DP until the end of your opponent's turn\" and the \"return 1 of your opponent's suspended Digimon to the bottom of the deck\" effect when activating this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon while it's suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it unsuspends.  After it suspends, it's no longer affected by your opponent's effects, so it can now unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is affected by a \"can't unsuspend\" effect from an opponent's Digimon, does it unsuspend during my unsuspend phase?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) applies when a card from the battle area or from under a card is placed into another area. In this case, it doesn't apply because a card from the battle area is placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) apply when I use this card's [All Turns] effect to place this card in the digivolution cards of the played [Guilmon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Such effects increase the maximum value shown for DP-based deletion effects.  For example, while \"[Your Turn] Add 1000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activated, \"[When Digivolving] Delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 3000 DP or less\" will allow you to delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does an \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" effect do?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't be increased.  You can't increase the maximum of a DP-based deletion effect that doesn't show a numerical value.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If \"add X000 to the maximum your DP-based deletion effects can delete\" is activating, can the maximum be increased for an effect such as \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" that references a Digimon's DP for deletion?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect adds the upper limit of the value texted in the DP deletion effect. For example, while \"[On Opponent's Turn] Upper limit of DP deletion effect you activate +1000.\" is active, \"[When Digivolving] Delete an opponent Digimon with a DP of 3000 or less.\" will cause the opponent Digimon with a DP of 4000 or less to be deleted.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"DP deletion effect limit +X000\" mean?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it cannot be added. You cannot add the upper limit of a DP deletion effect for which no numerical value is texted.[2]",
      "question": "Q: While the \"DP Deletion Effect Limit + X000\" effect is active, can I add an upper limit to the effect of \"Deletes opponent's Digimon whose DP is less than or equal to this Digimon's DP.\" Can I add an upper limit to the effect of deletion by referring to the Digimon's DP, such as \"This Digimon's DP is less than or equal to the opponent's Digimon's DP."
    }
  ],
  "LM-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Main] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [Main] effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect if I don't have any red Digimon cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must perform \"return 1 red Digimon card from your trash to the top of the deck\" whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to play a red Digimon card with 2000 DP or less from my trash without returning a Digimon card from my trash to the top of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Main] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [Main] effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect if I don't have any blue Digimon cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must perform \"return 1 blue Digimon card from your trash to the top of the deck\" whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to play a blue Digimon card with 2000 DP or less from my trash without returning a Digimon card from my trash to the top of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Main] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [Main] effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect if I don't have any yellow Digimon cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must perform \"return 1 yellow Digimon card from your trash to the top of the deck\" whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to play a yellow Digimon card with 2000 DP or less from my trash without returning a Digimon card from my trash to the top of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Main] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [Main] effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect if I don't have any green Digimon cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must perform \"return 1 green Digimon card from your trash to the top of the deck\" whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to play a green Digimon card with 2000 DP or less from my trash without returning a Digimon card from my trash to the top of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Main] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [Main] effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect if I don't have any black Digimon cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must perform \"return 1 black Digimon card from your trash to the top of the deck\" whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to play a black Digimon card with 2000 DP or less from my trash without returning a Digimon card from my trash to the top of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-032": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [Main] effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [Main] effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect if I don't have any purple Digimon cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You must perform \"return 1 purple Digimon card from your trash to the top of the deck\" whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to play a purple Digimon card with 2000 DP or less from my trash without returning a Digimon card from my trash to the top of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: To meet color requirements, normally you must have a Digimon or Tamer in your area that's the same color as the corresponding Option card. However, with this effect, this card's color requirements are met when you have a black Digimon or Tamer in the area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's 1st effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the color requirements are met when you have a black Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st effect mean that this card's color requirements are met even when I have a black Digimon in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: To meet color requirements, normally you must have a Digimon or Tamer in your area that's the same color as the corresponding Option card. However, with this effect, this card's color requirements are met when you have a red Digimon or Tamer in the area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's 1st effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the color requirements are met when you have a red Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st effect mean that this card's color requirements are met even when I have a red Digimon in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: To meet color requirements, normally you must have a Digimon or Tamer in your area that's the same color as the corresponding Option card. However, with this effect, this card's color requirements are met when you have a purple Digimon or Tamer in the area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's 1st effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the color requirements are met when you have a purple Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st effect mean that this card's color requirements are met even when I have a purple Digimon in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: To meet color requirements, normally you must have a Digimon or Tamer in your area that's the same color as the corresponding Option card. However, with this effect, this card's color requirements are met when you have a blue Digimon or Tamer in the area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's 1st effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the color requirements are met when you have a blue Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st effect mean that this card's color requirements are met even when I have a blue Digimon in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: To meet color requirements, normally you must have a Digimon or Tamer in your area that's the same color as the corresponding Option card. However, with this effect, this card's color requirements are met when you have a yellow Digimon or Tamer in the area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's 1st effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the color requirements are met when you have a yellow Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st effect mean that this card's color requirements are met even when I have a yellow Digimon in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "LM-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: To meet color requirements, normally you must have a Digimon or Tamer in your area that's the same color as the corresponding Option card. However, with this effect, this card's color requirements are met when you have a green Digimon or Tamer in the area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's 1st effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the color requirements are met when you have a green Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's 1st effect mean that this card's color requirements are met even when I have a green Digimon in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. \"Trash all of the digivolution cards of those Digimon\" is an explanation of what happens to the digivolution cards of the Digimon when it returns to their hand. It doesn't count as trashing digivolution for the purposes of this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: You activate an effect that reads \"Return 1 of your opponent's Digimon to their hand. Trash all of the digivolution cards of that Digimon\" to return an opponent's Digimon to their hand. When your opponent's digivolution cards are trashed as a result, can you activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-008": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only cards specifically named [Garurumon] meet the condition for this card's effect. The effect won't activate with card names such as [Garurumon (X Antibody)] that don't match, even if the name includes [Garurumon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate even if it has [Garurumon (X Antibody)] as a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "P-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect only applies if a card with the exact name [Agumon] is one of its digivolution cards. Despite [Agumon Expert], [ToyAgumon], and other Digimon cards having [Agumon], the effect doesn't apply if it isn't an exact match.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect apply if it has [Agumon Expert] or [ToyAgumon] as a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "P-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect is voluntary.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I always have to activate this card's effect when I attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 or fewer cards in my deck, can I activate this Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's When Attacking effect to trash 6 cards from the top of my deck and give this card +4000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with this card and activate its When Attacking effect to get +2000 DP. I then unsuspend this card using a card effect and attack again. Can I use the When Attacking effect again to get an additional +2000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's inherited effect when I have 2 or less non-Digi-Egg cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Cards in your trash are considered public information, so please let your opponent confirm which cards you're returning to your deck before you do so.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's inherited effect to return cards from my trash to the bottom of my deck, is my opponent allowed to check what cards I am returning to my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to return 3 non-Digi-Egg cards to the bottom of my deck but not activate \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "P-012": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Like Main effects on Option cards, you can activate these effects at any time during your main phase. However, you can't activate them to interrupt an attack or another effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: At what timing does this card's [Main] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect if I have a Digimon with [Veedramon] in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have two copies of this Tamer as well as one [Veedramon] in play in my battle area, can I active the effects of both Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have one [Veedramon] in play in my battle area, can I activate this card's effect to make a Digimon that doesn't have [Veedramon] get +1000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "P-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does a [Diaboromon] token count as 1 [Diaboromon] for this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card itself count as 1 [Diaboromon] for its effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-017": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, as long as you are able to.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I always have to activate this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-021": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a [Mimi Tachikawa] in play, can I use this card's effect to play a [Palmon] from my hand without paying its memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "P-022": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can use this card, but unless you place both [ExVeemon] and [Stingmon] at the bottom of your deck from your hand, you can't use this card's effect to play a [Paildramon] from your hand without paying its memory cost. You also can't use this card to place only [ExVeemon] or [ExVeemon] at the bottom of your deck from your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I only have either [ExVeemon] or [Stingmon] in my hand, can I use this card?"
    }
  ],
  "P-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can, but you won't be able to place any cards at the bottom of your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card if I don't have a [Patamon] in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-024": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect requires you to have a card named [Tai Kamiya] in play. [Tai Kamiya (V-Tamer)] isn't an exact match, so it can't be used to meet this card's requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card and activate its effect if I have a [P-012 Tai Kamiya (V-Tamer)] in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The card name has to be [Agumon] for you to be able to place it at the bottom of your deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to place a card that has [Agumon] (like [ToyAgumon], [Agumon Expert], or [BushiAgumon]) at the bottom of my deck to \uff1cDraw 3\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "P-026": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a suspended Digimon into this card, and paying the memory cost for the digivolution moves the memory gauge to 1 or more on the opponent's side. Before it becomes my opponent's turn, can I activate this card's <Digi-Burst> to unsuspend this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "P-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's <Digi-Burst> to use an Option card, can I activate the effect on my [BT3-096 Mimi Tachikawa]?"
    }
  ],
  "P-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If you have 3 security, you meet the conditions for both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and \"gain 1 memory,\" and activate both.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play this Digimon when I have 3 security cards, do I activate both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and the \"gain 1 memory\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-029": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving or de-digivolving, so you still have to delete this Digimon at the end of the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this Digimon's effect to digivolve it into [AncientGreymon], I digivolve (or de-digivolve) it into another Digimon. Do I still have to delete it at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They both trigger at the same time, so you can choose which order to activate them in. The one you activate first takes precedence.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this Digimon's effect to digivolve it into [AncientGreymon], I use [BT5-109 Mega Digimon Fusion!] to digivolve it into a level 7 Digimon. At the end of the turn, which effect takes precedence: This card's \"delete this Digimon at the end of the turn\" effect, or [Mega Digimon Fusion!]'s \"return the Digimon that digivolved with this effect to the bottom of its owner's deck\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving, so [AncientGreymon] is the Digimon re-played in your battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] on this Digimon, I use this Digimon's effect to digivolve it into [AncientGreymon]. When this Digimon is deleted at the end of the turn, which Digimon does [Back for Revenge!]'s effect allow me to re-play to my battle area? This card, or [AncientGreymon]?"
    }
  ],
  "P-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving or de-digivolving, so you still have to delete this Digimon at the end of the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this Digimon's effect to digivolve it into [AncientGarurumon], I digivolve (or de-digivolve) it into another Digimon. Do I still have to delete it at the end of the turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They both trigger at the same time, so you can choose which order to activate them in. The one you activate first takes precedence.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using this Digimon's effect to digivolve it into [AncientGarurumon], I use [BT5-109 Mega Digimon Fusion!] to digivolve it into a level 7 Digimon. At the end of the turn, which effect takes precedence: This card's \"delete this Digimon at the end of the turn\" effect, or [Mega Digimon Fusion!]'s \"return the Digimon that digivolved with this effect to the bottom of its owner's deck\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon carry over effects after digivolving, so [AncientGarurumon] is the Digimon re-played in your battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After using [BT3-109 Back for Revenge!] on this Digimon, I use this Digimon's effect to digivolve it into [AncientGarurumon]. When this Digimon is deleted at the end of the turn, which Digimon does [Back for Revenge!]'s effect allow me to re-play to my battle area? This card, or [AncientGarurumon]?"
    }
  ],
  "P-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. If your purple Digimon was deleted by a [When Attacking] effect, then this Digimon won't have \uff1cBlocker\uff1e when reaction timing arrives, and won't be able to activate \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to block the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon and 1 purple Digimon in play. My opponent's Digimon attacks, and its [When Attacking] effect deletes my purple Digimon. Can this Digimon now block the attack?"
    }
  ],
  "P-033": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This Digimon's effect becomes active as soon as your black Digimon reaches 13000 DP or more. Your black Digimon will conduct its battle with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this Digimon in play, and attack with a black Digimon with 12000 DP, whose [When Attacking] effect grants itself +1000 DP, bringing its total DP up to 13000. Does this Digimon's effect allow that black Digimon to have \uff1cPiercing\uff1e during the battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This Digimon's inherited effect becomes active as soon as your black Digimon reaches 13000 DP or more. Your black Digimon will conduct its battle with \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack with a black Digimon with 12000 DP, whose [When Attacking] effect grants itself +1000 DP, bringing its total DP up to 13000. If this Digimon is in its digivolution cards, does this Digimon's inherited effect allow the black Digimon to have \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e during its battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's inherited effect is a [Your Turn] effect, so your black Digimon will lose \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e as soon as it drops below 13000 DP. If the Digimon has no other effects to increase the number of security checks, the attack will end without performing any further checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is in the digivolution cards of a black Digimon with 13000 DP, which I use to attack my opponent. The first card flipped over during the security check causes the black Digimon to \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards), resulting in it having 12000 DP or less. Does the black Digimon still get extra security checks from \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "P-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. This card moving to your trash will cause you to have 7 Digimon cards with [Devimon] in your trash. As such, you will be able to activate this card's [On Deletion] effect to play a [DanDevimon] from your trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 6 cards with [Devimon] in my trash. If a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is deleted, can I use this card's [On Deletion] effect to play a [DanDevimon] from my trash without paying its memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "P-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn't fulfill color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a red Option card even if I have no other red Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if this card is in your battle area, you can activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e, regardless of color requirements. Color requirements only matter when using Option cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if I have no other red Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn't fulfill color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a blue Option card even if I have no other blue Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if this card is in your battle area, you can activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e, regardless of color requirements. Color requirements only matter when using Option cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if I have no other blue Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-037": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn't fulfill color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a yellow Option card even if I have no other yellow Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if this card is in your battle area, you can activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e, regardless of color requirements. Color requirements only matter when using Option cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if I have no other yellow Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-038": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn't fulfill color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a green Option card even if I have no other green Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if this card is in your battle area, you can activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e, regardless of color requirements. Color requirements only matter when using Option cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if I have no other green Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-039": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn't fulfill color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a black Option card even if I have no other black Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if this card is in your battle area, you can activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e, regardless of color requirements. Color requirements only matter when using Option cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if I have no other black Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-040": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Having this card in your battle area doesn't fulfill color requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I use a purple Option card even if I have no other purple Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if this card is in your battle area, you can activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e, regardless of color requirements. Color requirements only matter when using Option cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place this card in my battle area, can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect even if I have no other purple Digimon or Tamers in play?"
    }
  ],
  "P-044": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  You can choose to suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon, and it is possible to choose an opponent's Digimon with 5000 DP or less as the target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to suspend just 1 of my opponent's Digimon when they have 2 Digimon with 5000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "P-046": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  Activating \uff1cDelay\uff1e on an Option card in the battle area is not considered to be using an Option card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when \uff1cDelay\uff1e activates on an Option card placed in my battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-047": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.  In such cases, trash as many cards from your deck as is possible. Then, if you have a Tamer, this Digimon gets +3000 DP for the turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 or fewer cards in my deck, does this Digimon\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Cards in your trash are considered public information, so please let your opponent confirm which cards you're returning to your deck before you do so.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return cards from my trash to the bottom of my deck, is my opponent allowed to check what cards I am returning to my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return 3 non-Digi-Egg cards to the bottom of my deck but choose to not give this Digimon +2000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "P-048": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [When Digivolving] effect when I have 2 or less non-Digi-Egg cards in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Cards in your trash are considered public information, so please let your opponent confirm which cards you're returning to your deck before you do so.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When using this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return cards from my trash to the bottom of my deck, is my opponent allowed to check what cards I am returning to my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to return 3 non-Digi-Egg cards to the bottom of my deck but choose to not unsuspend this Digimon or 1 of my Tamers?"
    }
  ],
  "P-052": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  After this card's [When Digivolving] effect activates for a Digimon with no digivolution cards, that Digimon can't attack until the effect ends, even if it later gains a digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a target Digimon of this card's [When Digivolving] effect later gains a digivolution card, can it now attack?"
    }
  ],
  "P-066": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I add this card to my hand even if this card's [Security] effect doesn't delete an opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "P-070": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This effect reads \"you may play it without paying the cost,\" therefore you may choose to not play it. In such cases, because the effect reads \"add the remaining cards to your hand,\" you add the card to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [Security] effect reveals a black Digimon card with a play cost of 4 or less from the top of my deck, can I add it to the hand without playing it?"
    }
  ],
  "P-072": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You trash 2 cards of the same level as each other from among this Digimon's digivolution cards.  For example, by trashing 2 level 5 cards in digivolution cards, this Digimon won't be deleted or returned to hands/decks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I trash 2 cards of the same level as this card for \"you may trash 2 cards of the same level\" in this Digimon's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [MetalGreymon] name.[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [MetalGreymon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [MetalGreymon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "P-073": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You trash 2 cards of the same level as each other from among this Digimon's digivolution cards.  For example, by trashing 2 level 5 cards in digivolution cards, this Digimon won't be deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I trash 2 cards of the same level as this card for \"you may trash 2 cards of the same level\" in this Digimon's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has [WereGarurumon].[2]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"The name of this card/Digimon is also treated as [WereGarurumon]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Name: Also treated as [WereGarurumon].\")"
    }
  ],
  "P-074": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  The period starting from the use of [BT14-093 Emissary of Hope] until the digivolution is complete and you shuffle your security stack is considered checking your security stack, so it isn't affected by other cards' effects. Therefore, you can't use this card's effect to trash cards from your security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used [BT14-093 Emissary of Hope] to digivolve this Digimon into a card with the [Shaman]/[Wizard]\u00a0trait in my security stack. In such cases, can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to trash cards from my security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "P-077": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, cards revealed from your deck aren't considered to be \u201ctrashed from your deck,\u201d so this card\u2019s effect doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card was revealed by a \"reveal cards from your deck\" effect, then it was trashed. In such cases, does this card's \"when this card is trashed from your deck\" effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "P-085": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.  You can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's [On Play] effect to digivolve it into a Digimon card with [Dark Animal] or [Undead] in its traits from my trash, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "P-087": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, do I activate both \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e and and the \"gain 1 memory\" effect when activating this card's [Your Turn] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-088": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect reads \"delete,\" therefore you must choose and delete the specified number of targets whenever possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon has 12000 DP or more and my opponent has 2 or more Digimon with 6000 DP or less, can I use this card's [When Attacking] effect to delete just 1 of my opponent's Digimon with 6000 DP or less?"
    }
  ],
  "P-089": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  <Blast Digivolve> is performed at the end of the counter timing. If you activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect, the attack will end before you can activate <Blast Digivolve>, therefore it can no longer be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use <Blast Digivolve> to digivolve my Digimon if I activate this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect and end the attack from an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "P-092": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can\u2019t ignore digivolution requirements when using this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to digivolve this Digimon into [Wingdramon] in my hand regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "P-096": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's effect, can I choose Digimon cards with \uff1cSave\uff1e in its text from different sources such as from under multiple Tamers, or 1 from my trash and 1 from under a Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "P-097": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you must place all cards at the top or all cards at the bottom.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I place 3 cards at the top or bottom of my deck for this card's [On Play] effect, can I place some cards at the top and some at the bottom?"
    }
  ],
  "P-098": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. DigiXros itself is not an effect, so the effect doesn't activate for a card played by a DigiXros as a main phase action.  The effect will activate if a DigiXros is performed when a Digimon is played by an effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if 1 of my Digimon is played by a DigiXros?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it prevents that deletion.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon is affected by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, is deletion prevented when it loses in battles against my opponent's Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "P-101": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the [Cyborg] type trait.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"This card/Digimon is also treated as having the [Cyborg]\u00a0trait\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Trait: Has [Cyborg] type.\")"
    }
  ],
  "P-102": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I specify this Digimon itself as the Digimon to delete for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-103": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect but choose to not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-104": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect but choose to not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-105": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect but choose to not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-106": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect but choose to not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-107": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect but choose to not digivolve?"
    }
  ],
  "P-108": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve into a card in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't burst digivolve or DNA digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to burst digivolve or DNA digivolve into a card in my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect digivolves 1 Digimon. It doesn't digivolve Tamers.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve a Tamer into a Digimon card with a \"your Tamer is treated as a Digimon and can digivolve\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect but choose to not digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 10 or more cards in my trash. Can I use this card\u2019s \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to digivolve my [Impmon] into [BT2-111 Beelzemon] in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "P-109": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend then unsuspend this Digimon itself after playing or digivolving into it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend then unsuspend this Digimon itself after playing or digivolving into it, does this card's [All Turns] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "P-111": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. The effect only targets 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my opponent has 2 Digimon, can this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect give both of of my opponent's 2 Digimon -3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "P-112": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can add just 1 card to your hand when only 1 or the other is revealed.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck with this card's [On Play] effect don't contain both [Eosmon] and [Menoa Bellucci], do I still get to add a card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. You must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When the cards revealed from my deck with this card's [On Play] effect contain both [Eosmon] and [Menoa Bellucci], am I allowed to add just one card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's effect does not allow ignoring digivolution requirements, so you can only digivolve into a card that meets the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I use this card's inherited effect to digivolve into [Eosmon] in my hand, can it digivolve regardless of its digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "P-113": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [All Turns] effect even when an opponent's Digimon is deleted in a battle with my Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "P-114": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens are special cards that some effects put into play to represent Digimon or Tamers. You can use this card's effect to play a token that is treated as a Digimon card with the name [Diaboromon]. For a more detailed explanation of how tokens work, check the official rule manual.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What's a token?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I also activate this card's [All Turns] effect when a token is played?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"For each of your [Diaboromon]\" in this card's [All Turns] effect also count [Diaboromon] tokens?"
    }
  ],
  "P-115": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \uff1cSave\uff1e in this card's [On Deletion] effect to place this card under a Tamer with [Nene Amano] that was played by this effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-116": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I reference both me and my opponent's Digimon for this card's \"while you have [Agumon], [Pulsemon], and [Gammamon]\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"while you have [Agumon], [Pulsemon], and [Gammamon], this card costs 0\" mean that this card's cost is 0 when it's in my hand while the conditions are met?"
    }
  ],
  "P-118": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a green or blue card with 2 or more colors or a Tamer card with [Ken Ichijoji], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"green or blue card with 2 or more colors\" in this card's [On Play] effect mean that I can add a green/blue or blue/green card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a green or blue card with 2 or more colors and a Tamer card with [Ken Ichijoji], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "P-119": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a red or yellow card with 2 or more colors or a Tamer card with [Yolei Inoue], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"red or yellow card with 2 or more colors\" in this card's [On Play] effect mean that I can add a red/yellow or yellow/red card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a red or yellow card with 2 or more colors and a Tamer card with [Yolei Inoue], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "P-121": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  In such cases, you add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include only either a black or yellow card with 2 or more colors or a Tamer card with [Cody Hida], can I only add 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"black or yellow card with 2 or more colors\" in this card's [On Play] effect mean that I can add a black/yellow or yellow/black card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a black or yellow card with 2 or more colors and a Tamer card with [Cody Hida], can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "P-122": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"yellow or black card with 2 or more colors\" in this card's [On Play] effect mean that I can add a yellow/black or black/yellow card to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "P-123": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. You gain 1 memory when one of your Digimon moves from the breeding area to the battle area, regardless of whether or not you hatch in your breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect give me 1 memory when one of my Digimon moves from the breeding area to the battle area, even if I don't hatch in my breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It occurs during the breeding phase. If effects trigger during the breeding phase, the main phase will come after all effects have activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When one of my Digimon moves from the breeding area to the battle area during the breeding phase, does the hatching in the breeding area and gaining 1 memory for this card's [Your Turn] effect occur during the breeding phase or main phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I moved a Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area when this card was in my battle area and all of my Digimon's DP was reduced by activation of an effect. If that Digimon's DP becomes 0 due to the DP-reducing effect at the same time it's moved to the battle area, then it's deleted, does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate when this Digimon itself moves from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-127": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate. It only activates if you have fewer security cards than your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate if I have the same number of security cards as my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "P-129": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate. It only activates if you have more security cards than your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Start of Your Main Phase] effect activate if I have the same number of security cards as my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "P-130": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  \"Lv.-\" Digimon and Digimon cards can't be targeted by effects that reference levels.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [On Play] effect to move a \"Lv.-\" Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I moved a Digimon from the breeding area to the battle area when all of my Digimon's DP was reduced by activation of an effect. That Digimon's DP becomes 0 due to the DP-reducing effect at the same time it's moved to the battle area, then it's deleted, but does this card's [Your Turn] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "P-138": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from the deck with this card's effect include only a Digimon card with [Veedramon] or a blue Tamer card, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a Digimon card with [Veedramon] and a blue Tamer card, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "P-139": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, does this Digimon gain \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and \uff1cFortitude\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "P-140": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It's no longer affected by your opponent's effects as soon as it's suspended, so it can now unsuspend.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is unsuspended, then it's suspended by an opponent Digimon's \"Suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon. That Digimon can't unsuspend during your opponent's next unsuspend phase\" effect, is the effect that prevents unsuspending during the unsuspend phase negated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect prevent [Security] effects on my opponent's Security Digimon from affecting this Digimon when it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "P-142": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This card's [On Play] effect does not allow you to attack with Digimon that are in a state where they can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to attack using the Digimon with [Ravemon] where I placed this card in digivolution cards even when it's suspended?"
    }
  ],
  "P-143": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't processed.  In this case, \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) isn't processed because the card isn't removed from the area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a card with \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) is in this card's digivolution cards, is \nOverflow \uff1c-nocategory\uff1e (As this card moves from the field or under a card to an area other than those, lose nocategory memory.) on that card processed when this card's [End of Your Turn] effect moves it to the breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they aren't trashed.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Are digivolution cards trashed when this Digimon has digivolution cards and it's moved to the breeding area using this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If this Digimon is targeted by an effect and then moved to the breeding area, it remains targeted by the effect. However, it isn't affected by that effect. If it's moved back to the battle area using an effect such as [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]'s effect, it will be affected by that effect again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is targeted by an effect such as \"1 of your opponent's Digimon gains \uff1cSecurity A. -1\uff1e,\" then this Digimon is moved to the breeding area, what happens to the effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Even if a card is moved, once a [Once Per Turn] effect has activated, it can't be activated again.[2]",
      "question": "Q: After I activated this Digimon's [End of Your Turn] effect, I used an effect such as [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]'s effect to move this Digimon back to the battle area. Can I activate that Digimon's [End of Your Turn] effect again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't.  An effect that targets this Digimon will continue targeting it even if it's moved to the breeding area, but because it isn't affected by effects while in the breeding area, it isn't returned to the hand.[2]",
      "question": "Q: I used [BT16-085 Davis Motomiya & Ken Ichijoji]'s [Start of Your Main Phase] effect to play [BT16-040 Wormmon], it digivolved into this Digimon, then I used the [End of Your Turn] effect to move it to the breeding area. At such times, does [BT16-085 Davis Motomiya & Ken Ichijoji]'s effect return this Digimon to the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  At the end of your turn, this card's [End of Your Turn] effect and the effect given by [EX6-070 Phantom Pain] will trigger simultaneously, then if this card's effect activates first and this Digimon is moved to the breeding area, [EX6-070 Phantom Pain]'s [End of Your Turn] effect will be pending activation, but it can't activate in the breeding area.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is targeted by [EX6-070 Phantom Pain]'s [End of Your Turn] effect and then this Digimon is moved to the breeding area, does [EX6-070  Phantom Pain]'s [End of Your Turn] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it remains suspended.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is suspended when its effect moves it to the breeding area, is it still suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.  During the unsuspend phase, you unsuspend all of your Digimon and Tamers that are placed in the breeding area and battle area.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is suspended when it's moved to the breeding area, is it unsuspended during my next unsuspend phase?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't.  Digimon in breeding areas can't be chosen as attack targets.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can my opponent declare an attack with this Digimon as the target when this Digimon is suspended in the breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-144": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If a Digimon card with the [X Antibody]\u00a0trait is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, can this Digimon attack?"
    }
  ],
  "P-145": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t activate.  [EX5-070 X Antibody Proto Form]'s inherited effect will trigger/activate \"when this Digimon would leave the battle area other than by one of your effects,\" but since [EX5-070 X Antibody Proto Form] isn't in this Digimon's digivolution cards at the time of activation of the [On Deletion] effect because it's placed in your security stack before this Digimon is deleted, the \"if [X Antibody] was in this Digimon's digivolution cards\" condition isn't met, so the effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If [EX5-070 X Antibody Proto Form] is in this Digimon's digivolution cards, this Digimon would be deleted, and [EX5-070 X Antibody Proto Form]'s inherited effect places it on top of my security stack, does this Digimon's [On Deletion] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "P-146": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon with 2 copies of this card in its digivolution cards would be deleted, can I activate both instances of this card's inherited effect and place both copies at the bottom of my security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon with \uff1cBarrier\uff1e and this card in its digivolution cards would be deleted, can I activate both this card's inherited effect and \uff1cBarrier\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "P-147": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect requires you to activate a [When Digivolving] effect if present on the placed Digimon card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not activate a [When Digivolving] effect on the placed Digimon card for this card's [When Attacking] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect to place 1 level 4 card with [Pulsemon] in its text that doesn't have a [When Digivolving] effect as a digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "P-150": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have exactly 3 cards in my security stack, can I activate both the \"suspend 1 of your opponent's Digimon or Tamers\" effect and the \"1 of their Digimon or Tamers can't unsuspend until the end of their turn\" effect when activating this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-151": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  You can activate the part of the effect after \"then\" regardless of whether or not you could add a card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed for this card's [Main] effect don't include a card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait, can I still play 1 card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 3 or less from my hand without paying the cost?"
    }
  ],
  "P-152": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can digivolve from [Shoutmon] with a play cost of 4 or less or a [Dorulumon] with a play of cost 4 or less for a cost of 0.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When is digivolution possible with this card's digivolution requirements?"
    }
  ],
  "P-154": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only the Digimon where this card was placed as the bottom digivolution card is prevented from leaving the battle area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [All Turns] effect when multiples of my other Digimon with [Knightmon] in their text would leave the battle area by my opponent's effects at the same time, and I place this Digimon as 1 of those Digimon's bottom digivolution card, are all of my other Digimon with [Knightmon] in their text prevented from leaving the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "P-155": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect trashes an Option card that was placed by a \"place this card in the battle area\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does a \"trash an Option card in the battle area\" effect do, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "P-156": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to a card that has 1 of the same colors as the specified card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What colors of cards does \"the same color\" as the specified card refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose a single-color red Tamer for this card's [Main] effect, can I play a multicolor Digimon card that includes red?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I choose a red and blue 2-color Tamer for this card's [Main] effect, can I play a single-color red or blue Digimon card?"
    }
  ],
  "P-160": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The effects trigger simultaneously, so the player can choose the activation order.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Multiple effects trigger when this card attacks. In what order do they activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If an effect is lost while it's pending activation, it can no longer be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have this card and EX8-065 [Ryutaro Williams] in the battle area.  When this card attacks, I activate EX8-065 [Ryutaro Williams]'s [Your Turn] effect and digivolve this Digimon into a card in the hand.  Can I then activate this card's \uff1cRaid\uff1e or [When Attacking] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-165": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It isn't deleted at this timing, it's deleted at the end of your opponent's next turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: An opponent's Digimon attacks using an effect at the end of their turn.  Then, if this card was checked upon that Digimon's attack and this card was played using its [Security] effect, when do I delete the [Familiar] Token that was played by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-166": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This card's effect reduces the digivolution cost by 2, and the total digivolution cost reduction when combined with BT3-103 [Hidden Potential Discovered!]   is 7.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used BT3-103 [Hidden Potential Discovered!],   then I played this card.  I then used this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend 1 other Digimon.  If I use BT3-103 [Hidden Potential Discovered!]'s   effect to suspend one of my Digimon other than this card when I use the part of the effect after \"then\" to digivolve this card, how much is the digivolution cost reduced by this card's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-169": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This effect will trigger when a card is trashed from the digivolution cards of your Digimon with the [Mineral]\u00a0trait or your Digimon with the [Rock]\u00a0trait.  It doesn't require a specific card to be trashed from digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What Digimon's digivolution card being trashed will trigger this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "P-170": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to cards with the specified word or icon included in \"name, trait, effect, inherited effect, <Overflow X>, jogress, digivolution requirements, burst digivolution\". For example, a card with the text \"Knightmon\" refers to a card whose name is \"Dark Knightmon\" or whose effect says \"Knightmon\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: What do you mean by \"cards with text?\""
    }
  ],
  "P-172": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they will not be deleted at that time. After all of this card's [On Play] and [On Deletion] effects are resolved, all Digimon with DP 0 at that time will be deleted at the same time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] and [On Deletion] effects have reduced the Digimon's DP to 0. In this case, will the Digimon be deleted before the rest of this effect is processed?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-003": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the battle proceeds with +1000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attacked with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards when my opponent has just 1 unsuspended Digimon with \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. If my opponent no longer has any unsuspended Digimon after my opponent's Digimon blocks and suspends, does the battle with my opponent's Digimon proceed with the +1000 DP from this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-004": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the card number [P-009] and states that only up to 4 copies total can be included in a deck together with [P-009].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"\u203bCard Number: Also treated as [P-009]. A deck may not have more than 4 total copies of this and [P-009]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Card Number: Also treated as [P-009]. A deck may not have more than 4 total copies of this and [P-009].\")"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-005": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn\u2019t. You can only reference the top card among stacked cards for \"\"XX in its text.\"\" Therefore, this card will not be the top card when it is a digivolution card, and you can't reference its own text.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is the [Gammamon] text in this card's inherited effect itself considered to fulfill \"While this Digimon has [Gammamon] in its text\" in this card's inherited effect, and then the effect activates?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. However, because one of the cards revealed and added to your hand is a [Hiro Amanokawa] with [Gammamon] in its text, that card fulfills \"\"card with [Gammamon] in its text,\"\" so you may just add that [Hiro Amanokawa] card to your hand and return the non-[Hiro Amanokawa] card to the bottom of your deck without adding it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a [Hiro Amanokawa] with [Gammamon] in its text and a non-[Hiro Amanokawa] card with [Gammamon] in its text, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-006": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the card number [P-058] and states that only up to 4 copies total can be included in a deck together with [P-058].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"\u203bCard Number: Also treated as [P-058]. A deck may not have more than 4 total copies of this and [P-058]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Card Number: Also treated as [P-058]. A deck may not have more than 4 total copies of this and [P-058].\")"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-007": [
    {
      "answer": "A: This is a special rule for this card that always treats it as if it also has the card number [P-010] and states that only up to 4 copies total can be included in a deck together with [P-010].[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's (Rule) mean, exactly?  (*This card's \"\u203bCard Number: Also treated as [P-010]. A deck may not have more than 4 total copies of this and [P-010]\" has been changed to \"(Rule) Card Number: Also treated as [P-010]. A deck may not have more than 4 total copies of this and [P-010].\")"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-009": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. This effect can only be used to digivolve from a Digimon whose card name is [Gammamon] and also has a digivolution card with [Gammamon]. Note that digivolutions from cards with non-[Gammamon] card names are possible using digivolution requirements or this card's special digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's \"This card in your hand can digivolve onto one of your [Gammamon] that has a digivolution card with [Gammamon] for a digivolution cost of 3, ignoring this card's digivolution requirements\" mean that it can also digivolve from cards that have [Gammamon] such as [BetelGammamon], [KausGammamon], [WezenGammamon], or [GulusGammamon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they activate. This card's \"\"This Digimon gains all effects of cards with [Gammamon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards\"\" effect is an [All Turns] effect, so it will activate as soon as the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, [When Digivolving] effects are gained and will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card, do the [When Digivolving] effects on digivolution cards with [Gammamon] activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if the memory gauge is now at 1 or greater on your opponent's side, you can activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e .[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon with [Gammamon] and a [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect into this card. Can I activate the [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card's [All Turns] effect and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve one of my [Gammamon] with a digivolution card with [Gammamon] in the battle area into this card in the hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect don't affect the inherited effects of digivolution cards with [Gammamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect allow me to activate the inherited effect of a digivolution card with [Gammamon] as an effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-010": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If that inherited effect is an effect such as a [Your Turn] [All Turns] effect that increases DP upon activation after being placed in digivolution cards, you can delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to the DP after it was increased.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Digivolving] effect to place a Digimon card with an inherited effect that increases DP in this card\u2019s digivolution cards. In such cases, can I use \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" to delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to the DP after it was increased?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. This card's [Your Turn] effect reads \"\"you may unsuspend.\"\" Therefore, if you don't unsuspend this Digimon, it means you haven't yet used this [Once Per Turn] effect, and you can activate it when you delete an opponent's Digimon upon a different timing.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Digivolving] effect to delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon. At this time, can I choose to not unsuspend this Digimon for the [Your Turn] effect, and then when I later delete another opponent's Digimon in battle, etc., can I activate the effect and unsuspend this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-011": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. However, because one of the cards revealed and added to your hand is a [Kiyoshiro Higashimitarai] card with [Jellymon] in its text, that card fulfills \"\"card with [Jellymon] in its text,\"\" so you may just add that [Kiyoshiro Higashimitarai] card to your hand and return the non-[Kiyoshiro Higashimitarai] card to the bottom of your deck without adding it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a [Kiyoshiro Higashimitarai] with [Jellymon] in its text and a non-[Kiyoshiro Higashimitarai] card with [Jellymon] in its text, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-014": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I trash multiple blue cards in my hand, can I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to choose separate opponent's Digimon or Tamers and trash the cards under each one?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It refers to states where a Digimon doesn't have any digivolution cards and a Tamer doesn't have any cards placed under it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What kind of state does \"1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon or Tamers without cards under it\" in this card's [When Digivolving] effect refer to?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-015": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they do. This card's \"This Digimon gains all effects of cards with [Gammamon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards\" effect is [All Turns], so it activates as soon as digivolution is determined. Therefore, [When Digivolving] effects are gained and activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card, do the [When Digivolving] effects on digivolution cards with [Gammamon] activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if the memory gauge is now at 1 or greater on your opponent's side, you can activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e .[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon with [Gammamon] and a [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect into this card. Can I activate the [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card's [All Turns] effect and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect don't affect the inherited effects of digivolution cards with [Gammamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect allow me to activate the inherited effect of a digivolution card with [Gammamon] as an effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-016": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I trash multiple blue cards in my hand, can I use this card's [When Digivolving] [When Attacking] effect to choose separate opponent's Digimon or Tamers and trash the cards under each one?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this effect can choose any card from among the cards under that card and trash it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use \"choose 1 card under an opponent\u2019s Digimon or Tamer and trash it\" in this card's [When Digivolving][When Attacking] effect to choose any card from among the cards under the target opponent's Digimon or Tamer and trash it? Or can I only trash the bottom card?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-019": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this card's effect chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect is used to place more than one of the opponent's level 3 Digimon on top of their security stack, which player decides the order the cards are placed in?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-020": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible. However, because one of the cards revealed and added to your hand is a [Ruli Tsukiyono] card with [Angoramon] in its text, that card fulfills \"\"card with [Angoramon] in its text,\"\" so you may just add that [Ruli Tsukiyono] card to your hand and return the non-[Ruli Tsukiyono] card to the bottom of your deck without adding it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal for this card's [On Play] effect include 1 [Ruli Tsukiyono] with [Angoramon] in its text and 1 non-[Ruli Tsukiyono] card with [Angoramon] in its text, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining 2 cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-023": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they activate. This card's \"\"This Digimon gains all effects of cards with [Gammamon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards\"\" effect is an [All Turns] effect, so it will activate as soon as the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, [When Evolving] effects are gained and will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card, do the [When Digivolving] effects on digivolution cards with [Gammamon] activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if the memory gauge is now at 1 or greater on your opponent's side, you can activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e .[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon with [Gammamon] and a [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect into this card. Can I activate the [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card's [All Turns] effect and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect don't affect the inherited effects of digivolution cards with [Gammamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect allow me to activate the inherited effect of a digivolution card with [Gammamon] as an effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-025": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. At the end of your turn, all of these cards' [End of Your Turn] effects will trigger at the same time, but after you choose the activation order, declare the attack for the 1st Digimon, and effects such as [When Attacking] effects and \"\"when one of your Digimon attacks\"\" effects have finished activating, then the timing will occur for the activation of the [End of Your Turn] effects on the 2nd and other copies of this card that were pending activation. However, since the 1st Digimon is already attacking, you can't declare another attack and the effect activation will fail.  As a result, only the copy that activated first will attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have multiple copies of this Digimon, can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack using each in order?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. At the end of your turn, this card and [RB1-034 Ruli Tsukiyono]'s effects trigger at the same time, so you can attack if you first activate [RB1-034 Ruli Tsukiyono]'s effect and then unsuspend this card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used my [RB1-034 Ruli Tsukiyono]'s [End of Your Turn] effect to unsuspend this card while it was suspended.  In such cases, can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to attack?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-027": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this card's effect chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses whether to return the card revealed from my opponent\u2019s security stack by this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to the top or bottom of the security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-028": [
    {
      "answer": "A: The player that activated this card's effect chooses.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which player chooses the Digimon card to return from my opponent\u2019s trash to the bottom of the deck by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-030": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they activate. This card's \"\"This Digimon gains all effects of cards with [Gammamon] in this Digimon's digivolution cards\"\" effect is an [All Turns] effect, so it will activate as soon as the digivolution is confirmed. Therefore, [When Evolving] effects are gained and will trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When digivolving into this card, do the [When Digivolving] effects on digivolution cards with [Gammamon] activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if the memory gauge is now at 1 or greater on your opponent's side, you can activate \uff1cBlitz\uff1e .[1]",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve a Digimon with [Gammamon] and a [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect into this card. Can I activate the [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e effect through this card's [All Turns] effect and attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect don't affect the inherited effects of digivolution cards with [Gammamon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect and inherited effect allow me to activate the inherited effect of a digivolution card with [Gammamon] as an effect of this card?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-031": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I delete 1 of my Digimon whose level is less than or equal to the number of cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards for this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-034": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. At the end of your turn, this card and [RB1-025 Diarbbitmon]'s effects trigger at the same time, so you can attack if you first activate this card's effect and then unsuspend [RB1-025 Diarbbitmon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to unsuspend my [RB1-025 Diarbbitmon] while it was suspended.  In such cases, can I use [RB1-025 Diarbbitmon]'s [End of Your Turn] effect to attack?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-035": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, Lv.- Digimon don't have a level, so the \"gain 1 memory if that Digimon is level 4 or higher, and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e if it is level 3\" effect doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I suspend this Tamer when my opponent plays a Lv.- Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Both of the conditions are fulfilled, so you gain both 1 memory and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I suspend this Tamer when my opponent plays both a level 3 and a level 4 or higher Digimon at the same time?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't. You only \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e once even if multiple level 3 Digimon are played, and you similarly only gain 1 memory even if multiple level 4 or higher Digimon are played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I suspend this Tamer when my opponent plays 2 level 3 or level 4 or higher Digimon at the same time, do I gain \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e or 1 memory twice?"
    }
  ],
  "RB1-036": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If that inherited effect is an effect such as a [Your Turn] [All Turns] effect that increases DP upon activation after being placed in digivolution cards, you can delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to the DP after it was increased.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to place a Digimon card with an inherited effect that increases DP in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards. In such cases, can I use \"delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to this Digimon's DP\" to delete 1 of my opponent's Digimon with DP less than or equal to the DP after it was increased?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card has the inherited effect, \"While this Digimon has 4 or more digivolution cards, it gets +1000 DP.\" Is this card counted as part of that total?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can attack with it. But when you do, even if the memory counter moves to 1 or higher on your opponent's side, you don't switch turns until the attack is finished.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I attack with this Digimon if I don't have 2 or more memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon target itself for its own effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If your opponent doesn't block, the effect doesn't activate.  Regardless of what the target of attack is, the effect activates when a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards attacks an opponent's Digimon and has its attack target changed to an opponent's Digimon that blocks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate when I attack my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Only multiples of 2 count for this effect, so even if you have 3 digivolution cards, it only gains \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this Digimon's effect work when it has 3 digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this Tamer stack if there are multiple copies in play in my battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: During my next turn after this card's security effect was activated, does it apply to newly played Digimon and Digimon moved from the breeding area to the battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They are sent to their owner's trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the digivolution cards of a Digimon deleted by this card's main effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST1-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: They are sent to their owner's trash.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to the digivolution cards of a Digimon deleted by this card's main effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself yellow, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself yellow, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you DNA digivolve a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon in your hand that has [DNA Digivolution]. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cReveal the top 3 cards of your deck,\u201d so if you don\u2019t have 3 cards left in your deck, reveal as many as you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect force me to reveal 3 cards from the top of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cAdd 1 card...to your hand,\u201d so if you reveal a card that meets the requirements, you must add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] effect reveals cards from the top of my deck. If I reveal both yellow and purple cards, do I have to add both of them to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you DNA digivolve a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon in your hand that has [DNA Digivolution]. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into to DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself purple, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself purple, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When performing a non-DNA digivolution, only the \u201cPlace 1 yellow or purple Digimon card from your trash on top of your security stack face down\u201d part of the effect activates. The part of the effect that reads, \u201cyou may search your security stack for 1 level 5 or lower Digimon card and play it without paying its memory cost\u201d only activates when DNA digivolving.  \u201cThen, shuffle your security stack\u201d activates no matter what kind of digivolution you perform.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activate when performing a non-DNA digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect also activate when the [Security] effect of one of my Security Digimon plays it into my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, moving a Digimon from your breeding area doesn\u2019t count as playing it, so the effect doesn\u2019t activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate when [BT1-089 Mimi Tachikawa]'s effect moves a Digimon from my breeding area to my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Level 4 or lower.  If the same reference to an \"X\" trigger condition being performed is made for an effect when it has a \"when X\" trigger condition, the state when the effect has triggered will be referenced.  In this case, your Digimon was level 4 when this card's [All Turns] effect triggered, therefore you can delete a level 4 or lower Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: My level 4 Digimon was played by an effect, then this card's [All Turns] effect and another effect triggered simultaneously. I activated the other effect, then the level of my Digimon that was played by an effect increased from 4 to 5.  If I then activate this card's [All Turns] effect, what levels of Digimon can I delete?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can delete a Digimon.  If the same reference to an \"X\" trigger condition being performed is made for an effect when it has a \"when X\" trigger condition, the state when the effect has triggered will be referenced.  In this case, your Digimon was level 4 when this card's [All Turns] effect triggered, therefore you can delete a level 4 or lower Digimon.[2]",
      "question": "Q: My level 4 Digimon was played by an effect, then this card's [All Turns] effect and another effect triggered simultaneously. I activated the other effect, then my Digimon that was played by an effect was removed from the battle area.  If I then activate this card's [All Turns] effect, can I delete an opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \"Reveal the top 3 cards of your deck,\" so if possible, you must reveal 3 cards. If you have fewer than 3 cards left in your deck, reveal as many as you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect force me to reveal 3 cards from the top of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cAdd 1 card...to your hand,\u201d so if you reveal a card that meets the requirements, you must add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] effect reveals cards from the top of my deck. If I reveal a card with [Angel], [Archangel], or [Fallen Angel] in its traits, do I have to add it to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect activate when played with this card\u2019s [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.  Likewise, this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect activates before your opponent\u2019s next check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Does this Digimon\u2019s effect activate first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \"You may trash 1 card in your hand to...,\" so if you choose not to trash a card in your hand, the rest of the effect won't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect force me to reveal 3 cards from the top of my deck when digivolving?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cAdd 1 yellow and 1 purple card...to your hand,\u201d so if you reveal cards that meet the requirements, you must add them to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [When Digivolving] effect reveals cards from the top of my deck. If I reveal yellow and purple cards that both have [Angel], [Archangel], or [Fallen Angel] in their traits, do I have to add them to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.  If you choose to place an opponent\u2019s Digimon at the top of their security stack, you are in effect choosing to trash the chosen Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card\u2019s effect to place an opponent\u2019s Digimon at the top of their security stack, is that Digimon then trashed?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Due to [BT9-103 Kongou]'s effect, cards can't be placed in security stacks, therefore this card's \"place 1 of your opponent's Digimon face down at the top or bottom of your opponent's security stack\" can't be activated, and the target Digimon will be left as-is.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I use this card while my opponent has [BT9-103 Kongou]'s effect activated?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The Digimon isn\u2019t being deleted, so none of the above occurs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card\u2019s effect to place an opponent\u2019s Digimon at the top of their security stack, does that Digimon\u2019s [On Deletion] effect activate?  Additionally, do effects on other Digimon and Tamers that care about Digimon being deleted also activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST10-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to trash the top 3 cards of my deck. If a yellow or purple Digimon card is among those cards, can I then use this effect to return it from my trash to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the Digimon that has this card as it's digivolution card count itself for this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. If you have 2 or more Digimon, this effect can only get that Digimon +1000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 4 Digimon, does a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards get +2000 DP with this card's inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It negates effects that read, \u201creduce the play cost by X.\u201d When you or your opponent activates an effect like that, it won't reduce the play cost that needs to be paid. The full play cost of the card needs to be paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"Players can't reduce play costs\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"Play this card without paying the cost\" effects are not effects that reduce the play cost, so they can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can \"Play this card without paying the cost\" effects be activated if this Digimon is in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't be reduced. This card's effect does not target Digimon, so even if your opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] is in the breeding area, its effect to reduce play costs can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the play cost of a Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait be reduced due to the [Your Turn] effect of my opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] if this Digimon is in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: That's correct. Such effects can no longer reduce play costs.  This card's effect also prevents play cost-reducing effects from activating when Tamer cards are played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Digimon, can my opponent no longer use [BT14-046 Togemon]'s [Your Turn] effect or inherited effect to reduce the play cost of green Tamer cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if 2 or more Digimon with [Sistermon] are played at the same time, you only gain 1 memory by this card\u2019s effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 2 or more Digimon with [Sistermon] at the same time, do I gain 1 memory for each Digimon played?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect activates during that attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] effect plays 1 Digimon card with [Sistermon], do I get the benefits of this Digimon's [Your Turn] effect for the same attack?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this Digimon is played at the same time as another Digimon. Does this card's [Your Turn] effect trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"By trashing 1 card in your hand,\" so you may also choose to not trash a card in your hand. In such cases, you don't \uff1cDraw 2\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not activate this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"*Also treat as if name is [Sistermon Noir] and traits include [Virus]\" is a special rule for this card, not an effect. Therefore, this text also applies when the card is in your hand, breeding area, or any other area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens to \"*Also treat as if name is [Sistermon Noir] and traits include [Virus]\" on this card when it is in my hand or breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card is treated as having both the [Virus] and [Data]\u00a0traits, but only 1 at a time, so it is treated as having 3 traits in total, 1 of them together with the [Champion] and [Puppet]\u00a0traits.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card have the 4 traits, [Champion], [Puppet], [Virus] and [Data]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can choose different Digimon for each of the effects. You can choose the same Digimon or different ones.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose different Digimon for this card's effect to get +2000 DP and gain \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST12-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the cards revealed, after trashing the rest of the cards revealed, place this card in your Battle Area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If none of the cards revealed from the deck with this card's effect include [Huckmon] or the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait among them, is this card still placed in the Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: After activating this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e, can I still reduce the digivolution cost if one of my Digimon would digivolve due to an effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, even if you play 2 or more Digimon with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait at the same time with 1 effect, you can only gain 1 memory with this card's inherited effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I play 2 or more Digimon with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait at the same time, do I gain 1 memory for each Digimon played with this card's inherited effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, in that situation you can gain 2 memory in total.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 2 Digimon with this card in their digivolution cards, and play 1 Digimon with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait, can I activate both inherited effects and gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon [...] as its bottom digivolution card,\" so you may also choose to not place it as the bottom digivolution card. In such cases, it remains in the battle area as a Digimon like normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not activate this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"you may play it,\" so you may also choose to not play it. In such cases, you add it to your hand like any other card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I reveal a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect, can I choose to not play that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can't be played due to [BT9-047 Pomumon]'s effect, so you add it to your hand like any other card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I revealed a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect] when I had a [BT9-047 Pomumon]. What happens to that card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon [...] as its bottom digivolution card,\" so you may also choose to not place it as the bottom digivolution card. In such cases, it remains in the battle area as a Digimon like normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not activate this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you to DNA digivolve the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon that has a DNA digivolution requirement from your hand. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have a DNA digivolution requirement.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have a DNA digivolution requirement?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"You may play\" means you can choose to play it or not. If you don't play it, return it to the bottom of the deck with the rest of the cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I reveal a Digimon card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less with this card's [When Attacking] effect, can I choose to not play that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can't be played due to [BT9-Pomumon]'s effect, so return it to the bottom of the deck with the rest of the cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there's a [BT9-047 Pomumon] and I reveal a Digimon card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less with this card's [When Attacking] effect, what happens to that card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, [When Digivolving] \uff1cBlitz\uff1e can activate so long as the opponent somehow has 1 or more memory at the time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I DNA digivolve into this card, is it possible to attack with the \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in the [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, that's correct.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I DNA digivolve into this card and it has 8 digivolution cards, do I delete 2 of my opponent's Digimon with play costs of 20 or less and trash the top 2 cards of their security stack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's \uff1cBlitz\uff1e and \"for every 4 cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards, delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 20 or less and trash the top card of your opponent's security stack\" are a single effect, therefore if DNA digivolving, the latter part of the effect will continue to activate after the attack has been declared and won't be interrupted by another effect. After the whole effect has finished activating, the [When Attacking] effect will activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I DNA digivolve into this card, my opponent has 1 or more memory. If there is an inherited [When Attacking] effect when I attack with the \uff1cBlitz\uff1e in the [When Digivolving] effect, do I activate the [When Attacking] effect before this card's \"for every 4 cards in this Digimon's digivolution cards, delete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with a play cost of 20 or less and trash the top card of your opponent's security stack\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It negates effects that read, \u201creduce the play cost by X.\u201d When you or your opponent activates an effect like that, it won't reduce the play cost that needs to be paid. The full play cost of the card needs to be paid.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does this card's \"Players can't reduce play costs\" effect do, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"play this card without paying the cost\" effects do not reduce the play cost, so this card does not interfere with them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I omit paying the play cost by a \"play this card without paying the cost\" effect when I have this Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, \"Play this card without paying the cost\" effects are not effects that reduce the play cost, so they can activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can \"Play this card without paying the cost\" effects be activated if this Digimon is in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, they can't be reduced. This card's effect does not target Digimon, so even if your opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] is in the breeding area, its effect to reduce play costs can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the play cost of a Digimon with the [Royal Knight]\u00a0trait be reduced due to the [Your Turn] effect of my opponent's [BT13-007 King Drasil_7D6] if this Digimon is in play?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: That's correct. Such effects can no longer reduce play costs.  This card's effect also prevents play cost-reducing effects from activating when Tamer cards are played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I have this Digimon, can my opponent no longer use [BT14-046 Togemon]'s [Your Turn] effect or inherited effect to reduce the play cost of green Tamer cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon [...] as its bottom digivolution card,\" so you may also choose to not place it as the bottom digivolution card. In such cases, it remains in the battle area as a Digimon like normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not activate this card's [On Play] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"you may play it,\" so you may also choose to not play it. In such cases, you add it to your hand like any other card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I reveal a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect, can I choose to not play that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can't be played due to [BT9-047 Pomumon]'s effect, so you add it to your hand like any other card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I revealed a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect] when I had a [BT9-047 Pomumon]. What happens to that card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"By placing this Digimon under 1 of your other Digimon [...] as its bottom digivolution card,\" so you may also choose to not place it as the bottom digivolution card. In such cases, it remains in the battle area as a Digimon like normal.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose to not activate this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you to DNA digivolve the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon that has a DNA digivolution requirement from your hand. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have a DNA digivolution requirement.[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have a DNA digivolution requirement?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, the effect reads \"you may play it,\" so you may also choose to not play it. In such cases, you place it at the bottom of the deck with the rest of the cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When this card's [When Digivolving] effect reveals a card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less in my deck, can I choose to not play that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It can't be played due to [BT9-Pomumon]'s effect, so return it to the bottom of the deck with the rest of the cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there's a [BT9-047 Pomumon] and I reveal a Digimon card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less with this card's [When Attacking] effect, what happens to that card?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card's inherited effect has the [Opponent's Turn] timing, but the turns haven't changed at the end of your turn, so this card's inherited effect can't be activated and the effect of your opponent's [BT9-112 DeathXmon] can't be prevented.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my Digimon is targeted by the [End of Opponent's Turn] effect of my opponent's [BT9-112 DeathXmon] while it has this card in its digivolution cards, does this card's inherited effect prevent it from being deleted due to my opponent's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this card can only delete 1 Digimon.  If there are multiple opponent's Digimon with the highest DP, this card's player chooses 1 target among them to delete.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are multiple opponent's Digimon with the highest DP, can I delete them all with this card's [Main] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST13-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I don't play a Digimon card with the [Legend-Arms]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 7 or less from my hand with this card's [Main] effect, can I still activate the effect to place this card in my Battle Area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. Choose whether to return all revealed cards to the top of the deck, or return all revealed cards to the bottom of the deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I return some of the cards revealed with this card's \uff1cDelay\uff1e effect to the top of the deck and the others to the bottom of the deck?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it is not. The card's effect allows digivolution only into a Digimon card whose name is [Beelzemon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Is it possible to digivolve into [Beelzemon: Blast Mode] with this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [When Attacking] effect to digivolve into [Beelzemon] from my trash. At such times, can I use my [EX2-065 Ai & Mako]'s effect to digivolve again into a [Beelzemon: Blast Mode] in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Deletion] effect also include this card itself in the number of cards in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If there are targets that this Digimon can attack, such as an opponent's suspended Digimon, it will attack that target. If the only possible target is the opponent, no attack will occur because of the \"This Digimon can't attack players\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card's \"This Digimon can't attack players\" effect work if this Digimon is affected by a \"make 1 of your opponent's Digimon attack\" effect from my opponent?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it can't. The [On Deletion] effect gained from this card can only play a card whose name is [Beelzemon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the [On Deletion] effect gained from this card play [Beelzemon: Blast Mode] from my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have 9 or fewer cards in my trash, and I activate this card's [When Digivolving]?effect to trash 4 cards from my deck. If I now have 10 or more cards in my trash, do I gain 1 memory from this card's [All Turns] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the \"When this card is trashed from your deck, delete 1 of your opponent's level 3 or lower Digimon\" effect also include this card itself in the number of cards in my trash?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate this effect. \"return 1 card from your hand on top of your deck\" is not a \"by <X>, <Y>\" effect (\"by returning...\"), so you gain 1 memory even when you can't perform that action. However, if you do have cards in your hand, you must return 1 card on top of the deck.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's [Your Turn] effect and gain 1 memory even when I have 0 cards in my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST14-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can activate it because it is a different turn now.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card is trashed from my deck and placed in the battle area during my opponent's turn, can I activate \uff1cDelay\uff1e once my opponent's turn ends and it becomes my turn?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Blocking causes the attack target to be switched, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and my opponent blocks, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when an attack target is switched for a Digimon other than a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate even when my opponent only has a Digimon in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Blocking causes the attack target to be switched, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and my opponent blocks, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when an attack target is switched for a Digimon other than a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if this Digimon is blocked, the effect activates if you declared an attack against your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacked the opponent player and was blocked by an opponent's Digimon. Does this Digimon's effect activate in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \"No, you can't.  In order to play an [Agumon], the Digimon card's name can only be [Agumon].\"[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s effect to play a Digimon with [Agumon] such as [Agumon Expert] or [BushiAgumon]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Blocking causes the attack target to be switched, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and my opponent blocks, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate when an attack target is switched for a Digimon other than a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect activate when a Digimon other than this Digimon removes a card from either player's security stack?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Blocking causes the attack target to be switched, so the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I attack my opponent with one of my Digimon and they block, does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can be blocked. \uff1cBlocker\uff1e is an effect that allows the Digimon with the effect to block, so it isn't affected by \"isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effects.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon with [Greymon] isn't affected by my opponent's Digimon's effects from this card's [Main] effect, can it be blocked by an opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it isn't affected.  [Security] effects on Security Digimon are treated as Digimon effects, so the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent's Digimon\" effect prevents such effects from affecting this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When my Digimon with [Greymon] isn't affected by my opponent's Digimon's effects from this card's [Main] effect, is it affected by [Security] effects on my opponent's Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST15-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, in such cases, the attack isn't performed due to the \"this Digimon can't attack\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose an opponent's Digimon with a \"this Digimon can't attack\" effect as the target for \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\" when I activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: At the start of your opponent's main phase, the effects gained from this card's effect are triggered at the same time, and your opponent determines which one activates first. After effects such as [When Attacking] have activated, and before the counter timing occurs, it is time to activate the effect of the 2nd Digimon that was pending activation. However, since the 1st Digimon is already attacking, the effect ends without an attack made. As a result, only the Digimon whose effect was activated first can attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens if I use this card twice and 2 of my opponent's Digimon gain the \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In such cases, as soon as it becomes your opponent's turn, the target opposing Digimon loses the \"this Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect, and the attack occurs at the start of the main phase by this card's effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose an opponent's Digimon with an \"[Opponent's Turn] This Digimon isn't affected by your opponent\u2019s effects\" effect as the target for \"[Start of Your Main Phase] Attack with this Digimon\" when I activate this card's [Main] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, Digimon in breeding areas aren't checked by this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's effect activate even when my opponent only has a Digimon in their breeding area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Even if this Digimon is blocked, the effect doesn't activate if you declared an attack against your opponent.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This Digimon attacked the opponent player and was blocked by an opponent's Digimon. Does this Digimon's effect activate in such cases?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't. In order to play an [Gabumon], the Digimon card's name can only be [Gabumon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card\u2019s effect to play a Digimon with [Gabumon] such as [Gabumon - Bond of Friendship] or [Gabumon (X Antibody)]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST16-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Even if the Digimon becomes a Digimon without [Garurumon], as long as the conditions were met at the time of activation for this card's effect, the effect will persist until the end of your opponent's turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I used this card's [Main] effect to to give 1 of my Digimon with [Garurumon] \"[On Deletion] Play this card without paying the cost.\" What happens to the effect if the target Digimon later becomes a Digimon without [Garururmon] by digivolving or \uff1cDe-Digivolve  nocategory\uff1e (Trash up to nocategory cards from the top. You can't trash past level 3 cards)?"
    }
  ],
  "ST17-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.  In such cases, the attacking Digimon gets the DP of the 2 Digimon suspended for \uff1cAlliance\uff1e, and \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e is gained twice for 2 additional security checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to give \uff1cAlliance\uff1e to a Digimon that originally had \uff1cAlliance\uff1e, can that Digimon activate \uff1cAlliance\uff1e twice for 1 attack?"
    }
  ],
  "ST17-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. You must delete your own Digimon if you have a corresponding Digimon while your opponent doesn't.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If my opponent doesn't have any level 3 or lower Digimon, do I have to delete my level 3 or lower Digimon for this card's effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to delete my level 3 Digimon with [Terriermon], can I then use this effect to play that deleted Digimon card from my trash without paying the cost?"
    }
  ],
  "ST17-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's [When Digivolving] effect suspend 1 each of my opponent's Digimon and Tamers?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Digivolutions from Tamers are also no longer possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [When Digivolving] effect also prevent my opponent's Tamers from digivolving into Digimon cards in cases where Tamers can digivolve?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate the \"can't unsuspend or digivolve\" effect in this card's [When Digivolving] effect on opponent's Digimon/Tamers other than the ones suspended by this effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't unsuspend.  The target Digimon is unaffected by this card's effect during the turn it activated, but the \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent\u2019s Digimon until the end of your opponent's turn\" effect is lost when the turn switches, and then this card's effect prevents it from unsuspending.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [When Digivolving] effect is activated for an opponent's suspended Digimon with a \"this Digimon isn't affected by the effects of your opponent\u2019s Digimon until the end of your opponent's turn,\" does that Digimon unsuspend during my opponent's next turn?"
    }
  ],
  "ST17-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [When Digivolving] effect to delete my green/purple level 4 Digimon, can I then use this effect to play that deleted Digimon card from my trash without paying the cost?"
    }
  ],
  "ST17-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main] effect to place this Tamer and 1 [Gargomon] and 1 [Rapidmon] from my trash as my [Terriermon]'s bottom digivolution cards, but then choose to not digivolve that Digimon into [MegaGargomon] in the hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  This effect only allows you to place this card and 1 [Gargomon] and 1 [Rapidmon] from your trash in the digivolution cards of 1 [Terriermon].[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have multiples of [Terriermon], can I use this card's [Main] effect to place this Tamer and 1 [Gargomon] and 1 [Rapidmon] from my trash in the digivolution cards of different [Terriermon]?"
    }
  ],
  "ST17-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the cards I reveal from my deck for this card's effect include both a green Digimon card and a green Tamer card, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "ST17-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [Security] effect allow me to ignore the digivolution requirements when I digivolve 1 of my Digimon into this card at the end of the battle?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It occurs with your opponent's Digimon after \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards).  Security effects have top priority and activate when a card is flipped over for a security check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's [Security] effect gives \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards) to my opponent's attacking Digimon, does the battle with the Security Digimon occur with my opponent's Digimon before or after \uff1cDe-Digivolve  1\uff1e nocategory of your opponent's Digimon (Trash the top card. You can't trash past level 3 cards)?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This effect doesn't specify a player, so you can specify either player's Digimon as the effect's target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [When Attacking] inherited effect to suspend my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed for this card's [On Play] effect include only either 1 card with [Avian] or [Bird] in any of its traits or 1 card with the [Vortex Warriors]/[LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a card with [Avian] or [Bird] in any of its traits and a card with the [Vortex Warriors]/[LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  It triggers regardless of the player that activated the suspending effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when this Digimon is suspended by either my effect or my opponent's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  You can play it as long as the card has the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 4 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Security] effect to play a Tamer card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 4 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can't play it because Digi-Egg cards don't have play costs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Security] effect to play a Digi-Egg card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  This effect doesn't specify a player, so you can specify either player's Digimon as the effect's target.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to suspend my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  Even if you specify an already suspended Digimon as the target for a suspending effect, it isn't considered to be suspended by the effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I specify my suspended Digimon for this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect, can I resolve \"if this effect suspended your Digimon\" effects?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't trigger.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If \uff1cRaid\uff1e switches the target of attack from a player to an opponent's Digimon, does the [Your Turn] effect in this card's inherited effects trigger?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can the Digimon I specify to suspend be different from the opponent's Digimon that can't unsuspend for this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they can.  This effect doesn't specify a player, so you can specify either player's Digimon as the effect's targets.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon be specified for the Digimon that are suspended and unsuspended by this card's [When Digivolving] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it triggers.  It triggers regardless of which player's Digimon is unsuspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [All Turns] effect trigger when either my Digimon or my opponent's Digimon is unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  When using an effect that switches the target of attack after an attack declaration, you can also switch the target of attack to an opponent's unsuspended Digimon or Digimon with a \"can't be attacked\" effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to switch the target of attack to an opponent's unsuspended Digimon or Digimon with a \"can't be attacked\" effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST18-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  The part of the effect after \"then\" will activate regardless of which player's Digimon you unsuspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's [Main] effect to suspend an opponent's Digimon, can I then unsuspend 1 of my Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  If that token is a Digimon, you can \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have a Digimon with this Digimon in digivolution cards, and the only other card I have is a token, can I \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e with this card's [When Attacking] inherited effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  Even if you only reveal one of the applicable cards, you can still add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards revealed for this card's [On Play] effect include only either 1 card with the [Puppet]\u00a0trait or 1 card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait, can I just add that 1 card to my hand?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  If you have cards that are targets of this effect, you must add as many cards to your hand as possible.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the 3 cards I reveal from my deck for this card's [On Play] effect include both a card with [Puppet]\u00a0trait and 1 card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait, can I choose to only add one of them to my hand, and place the remaining cards at the bottom of my deck?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  You can play it as long as the card has the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 4 or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Security] effect to play a Tamer card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait and a play cost of 4 or less?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can't play it because Digi-Egg cards don't have play costs.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Security] effect to play a Digi-Egg card with the [LIBERATOR]\u00a0trait?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.  If there are 3 or more total Digimon between you and your opponent, you further reduce this DP-reducing effect by 3000.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect count both my Digimon and my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If the conditions are met, the -3000 DP effect will further get -3000 DP for a total reduction of -6000 DP for 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"it further gets -3000 DP\" in this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: \"When [...] would leave the battle area\" refers to when this Digimon is placed in the trash, returned to the hand/deck, placed in the security stack, moved to the breeding area, or placed under another card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"when [...] would leave the battle area\" in this card's [All Turns] inherited effect mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Tokens aren't placed in the trash when deleted, but [On Deletion] effects on tokens will activate as if the token was a Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: [Familiar] Tokens have an [On Deletion] effect, but because tokens are removed from the game instead of being placed in the trash when deleted, does this mean that the [On Deletion] effect doesn't activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.  BT11-063 [Geremon] and BT15-035 [Geremon] have a rule that also treats them as having the name [Numemon], therefore you can place them as digivolution cards under this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] [When Digivolving] effect to place a BT11-063 [Geremon] or BT15-035 [Geremon] from my trash in this card's digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you can't.  You can only specify 1 Digimon that will gain \uff1cRush\uff1e from among multiple Digimon that were played at the same time.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When effects play multiples of my Tokens and/or Digimon with the [Puppet]\u00a0trait, can I use this card's [Your Turn] effect to give \uff1cRush\uff1e to all of the played Digimon by suspending this Tamer?"
    }
  ],
  "ST19-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.  If there are 3 or more total Digimon between you and your opponent, 1 of your opponent's Digimon gets -12000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does \"if there are 3 or more Digimon\" in this card's [Main] effect count both my Digimon and my opponent's Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: If the conditions are met, the -6000 DP effect will further get -6000 DP for a total reduction of -12000 DP for 1 of your opponent's Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \"it further gets -6000 DP\" in this card's [Main] effect mean, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: It only exists when comparing the DP between two Digimon for a battle. It is not applied during the resolution \"End of battle\" or \"On Deletion\" effects that activated from that same battle.",
      "question": "Q: How long does the DP effect [ST2-01 Tsunomon] last?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The 1000 DP only exists when comparing the DP between Digimon for a battle. It is not applied during \"when X attacks\" effects.",
      "question": "Q: I attack with [BT5-111 Omnimon X-Anti-body] that has this card as a digivolution card against a 16000 DP Digimon with no sources. Can I use its effect to delete that Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This inherited effect does nothing to your opponent's Digimon if they have no digivolution cards.",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect be used to delete an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This inherited effect does nothing to your opponent's Digimon if they have no digivolution cards.",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect be used to delete an opponent's Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have less than 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect apply even if my opponent only has 1 Digimon with no digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Once that Digimon has no digivolution cards left, this card's inherited effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: One of my Digimon has this card as a digivolution card and attacks one of my opponent's Digimon that has 1 digivolution card. If this Digimon has another When Attacking effect that activates and trashes that digivolution card, does this card's inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect apply if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Your opponent has to have a Digimon in their battle area for it to activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect apply when my opponent doesn't have any Digimon in their battle area?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. In that case, it would only trash that 1 digivolution card.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this card's inherited effect be activated on an opponent's Digimon that only has 1 digivolution card?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it only unsuspends itself once per turn. In other words, it only unsuspends the first time it attacks each turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this Digimon unsuspend itself each time it attacks?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can use the effect again during your next turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this Digimon's effect only activate once per game?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: After you declare your attack, suspend the Digimon, then declare your attack target. When performing your security check or resolving a battle with your opponent's Digimon, this Digimon will already be unsuspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: At what timing does this Digimon unsuspend itself?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You only gain 1 memory no matter how many Digimon your opponent has without digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Do I gain 1 memory for each Digimon my opponent has without digivolution cards?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't check Digimon in the breeding area.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this Tamer's effect apply if my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards in their breeding area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. Your opponent has to have a Digimon in their battle area for it to activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this Tamer's effect apply when my opponent has no Digimon in their battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect of each copy activates, causing you to gain 2 memory.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I have two of this Tamer in play and my opponent has a Digimon with no digivolution cards, do I gain 2 memory from this Tamer's effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does. However, this only happens after any attacks end. If there are any attacks that are still continuing due to <Security Attack +> or other effects, those must resolve before it becomes your turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the security effect of this card causes the memory counter to move to 1 or higher on my side, does my opponent's turn end?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of my opponent's Digimon has this card's effect used on it and is suspended, can I attack that Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This card can only be used to target cards that meet its requirements upon activation. So the effect would still apply, and even though the target Digimon has gained digivolution cards, it still can't attack or block.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of my opponent's Digimon has this card's effect used on it and it digivolves and now has 1 or more digivolution cards, how does this card's effect resolve?"
    }
  ],
  "ST2-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card's effect can only be used on Digimon cards that are digivolution cards. It can't be used on Digi-Egg cards or Tamer cards in a Digimon's digivolution cards.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use the effect of this Option card to play a level 2 Digimon that is currently a digivolution card of one of my Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it is played as another Digimon, it is played unsuspended.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this Option card's effect to play a digivolution card of one of my suspended Digimon, does it come into play suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. Since it is played as another Digimon, it is not affected by any effects of the original Digimon it was under.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If one of my Digimon has an effect applied to it that lasts a turn, then I use the effect of this Option card to play one of its digivolution cards as a Digimon, does that Digimon come into play with the same effect applied to it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, since it would count as the turn they were played.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can Digimon played by this card's effect attack the turn they were played?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Since it meets the activation conditions, they all activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the DP of an opponent's Digimon is reduced to 0 and deleted, if I have multiple Digimon with this Digimon as digivolution cards, do all of their effects activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Since it meets the activation conditions, they all activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the DP of an opponent's Digimon is reduced to 0 and deleted, if I have multiple Digimon with this Digimon as digivolution cards, do all of their effects activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you have 4 or more cards in your security stack, you gain 1 memory. But you can only gain 1 memory from this effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: On attack, if I have 8 cards in my security stack, does this card's inherited effect cause me to gain 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if this Digimon's attack effect causes your memory to move to 1 or greater on your opponent's side, it doesn't become your opponent's turn until the end of the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack when I have less than 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's inherited effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 1000 DP or less and delete it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs, and the attack ends. If there are other effects to activate (When Attacking effects, etc.), the attack ends after activating them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card as a digivolution card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then that Digimon's DP is reduced to 0 and deleted by this card's inherited effect. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, blocking can only be performed in the blocker timing that occurs after all [When Attacking] effects finish resolving. As such, once a block has been declared, the window for activating this card's inherited effect has already passed, so it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card as a digivolution card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then the opponent blocks with a Digimon that has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's inherited effect to reduce the DP of the blocking Digimon to 0 and delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you do. This effect behaves the same way as an effect that reads \"If you have 3 or fewer security cards\", so the condition is checked when the effect would be activated.",
      "question": "Q: I digivolve into this card while I have 4 or more security cards. While this Digimon's [When Digivolving] effect is pending activation, one of my other effects reduces my security cards to 3 or fewer. Do I?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less, reduce its DP to 0, and delete it?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No battle occurs, and the attack ends. If there are other effects to activate (When Attacking effects, etc.), the attack ends after activating them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then that Digimon's DP is reduced to 0 and deleted by this card's effect. What happens to the attack?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. \uff1cBlocker\uff1e and other effects that activate when an opponent's Digimon attacks only activate during the reaction timing window that occurs after When Attacking effects, etc. finish activating. As such, once a block has been declared, the window for activating this card's inherited effect has already passed, so it can't be activated.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card attacks an opponent's Digimon, then my opponent blocks with a Digimon that has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. Can I use this card's effect to reduce the DP of the blocking Digimon to 0 and delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does the effect of this Tamer stack if there are multiple copies in play in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. It doesn't affect normal Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this Tamer's effect only affect Security Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, they do.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there are two copies of this card in my security stack, and both copies are activated in the same turn, do their effects stack?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 2000 DP or less, reduce its DP to 0, and delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: That Digimon can't perform security checks, so the battle ends. Even if your opponent has no cards in their security stack, you would not win the game by attacking with that Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What happens when a Digimon has a security check number of 0 because of this card's effect and it attacks a player?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: It would still check 0 cards. In order to check 1 or more security cards, that Digimon would need to gain <Security Attack +3> or higher.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's effect causes a Digimon to gain <Security Attack -3>, giving them a security check number of 0. How many security cards could that Digimon check if it gained \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST3-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to target one of my opponent's Digimon with 10000 DP or less, reduce its DP to 0, and delete it?"
    }
  ],
  "ST4-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you declared an attack against your opponent, this card's effect doesn't activate, even if they use another Digimon to block it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you declared an attack against an opponent's Digimon, this effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and use another effect to delete an opponent's Digimon card. Does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST4-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, if you declared an attack against your opponent, this card's effect doesn't activate, even if they use another Digimon to block it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this card's effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if you declared an attack against an opponent's Digimon, this effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent's Digimon using a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and use another effect to delete an opponent's Digimon card. Does this card's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST4-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if your memory counter moves to 1 on your opponent's side due to this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect, your turn doesn't end until the attack does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack if I have less than 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST4-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, [Security] effects only activate when flipped over from the security stack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's inherited effect to trash an opponent's Security Card. Does the security effect on that card activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, this effect only trashes the top card of your opponent's security stack. It doesn't win you the game if it's empty.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has an empty security stack. If I have a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and I use it to attack and delete an opponent's Digimon and survive, do I win the game?"
    }
  ],
  "ST4-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect simply prevents the Digimon from attacking or blocking. You can still attack it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon. Can I attack that Digimon if it's suspended?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, the effect persists, even if they digivolve.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, can it attack and block again?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: The effect preventing it from attacking takes priority. Your opponent's Digimon still can't attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect on an opponent's Digimon. If that Digimon activates an effect that allows it to attack other Digimon or players, what happens?"
    }
  ],
  "ST4-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I activate this card's effect when my opponent uses \uff1cBlocker\uff1e to suspend one of their Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST5-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if your opponent didn't have a Digimon in play for their entire turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if you activate effects to prevent all of your opponent's Digimon from attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. They attacked this turn, so the effect doesn't apply.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if your opponent's Digimon were all deleted in battle after attacking?"
    }
  ],
  "ST5-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate even if your opponent didn't have a Digimon in play for their entire turn?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if you use effects to prevent your opponent's Digimon from attacking?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it doesn't. They attacked this turn, so the effect doesn't apply.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect activate if your opponent's Digimon were all deleted in battle after attacking?"
    }
  ],
  "ST5-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if your memory counter moves to 1 on your opponent's side due to this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect, your turn doesn't end until the attack does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack if I have less than 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST5-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give this Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon retain effects when digivolving or de-digivolving, so \uff1cBlocker\uff1e remains.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to give a Digimon \uff1cBlocker\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, what happens to \uff1cBlocker\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST5-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to give this Digimon \uff1cReboot\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon retain effects when digivolving or de-digivolving, so \uff1cReboot\uff1e remains.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to give a Digimon \uff1cReboot\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, what happens to \uff1cReboot\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST5-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect to unsuspend a Digimon that didn't block?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, you don't lose the game when your deck is empty. You will lose the game if your deck has 0 cards in it at your next draw phase, however.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If this card's effect reduces the number of cards in my deck to 0, do I lose the game?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"purple use cost 1 option card\" or \"purple use cost 7 option card\".[1]",
      "question": "Q: Which card can be returned to your hand by this card's [On Play] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it can. Even if your memory counter moves to 1 on your opponent's side due to this Digimon's [When Attacking] effect, your turn doesn't end until the attack does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can this Digimon attack if I have less than 2 memory?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Digimon retain effects when digivolving or de-digivolving, so \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e remains.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to give a Digimon \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e. If that Digimon digivolves into a different Digimon, what happens to \uff1cRetaliation\uff1e?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it is possible.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can the effect of this card give this Digimon itself a \"road companion\"?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Even if the Digimon digivolves or degenerates, the effect it received is inherited, so the <Digivolve> is still given.[2]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon that is given \"\u9053\u9023\u308c\" by the effect of this card digivolves and becomes another Digimon, what happens to the \"\u9053\u9023\u308c\"?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-13": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's <Digi-Burst> to trash a purple level 3 Digimon card in the Digimon with <Digi-Burst>'s digivolution cards. Can I immediately use the <Digi-Burst> effect to play that Digimon without paying its memory cost?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You must fully activate this card's effect, then activate the [When Deleted] effect.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card's effect to delete one of my Digimon with a [When Deleted] effect. Can I activate the [When Deleted] effect before this card's \"delete 1 of your opponent's level 4 or lower Digimon\" effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: They activate at the same time, which means the turn player resolves their effect first.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card to delete one of my own Digimon, and an opponent's Digimon. If they both have [When Deleted] effects, which effect resolves first?"
    }
  ],
  "ST6-16": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you only have a level 3 or level 4 purple Digimon card in your trash, you can play it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect if I only have either a level 3 or level 4 purple Digimon card in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can use it. If there is only one Digimon card, either the purple Lv.3 or Lv.4 Digimon card, only the one in trash will be played.[2]",
      "question": "Q: Can I use this card's effect even if I have only one purple Lv.3 or Lv.4 Digimon card in my trash?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: One \"Purple Lv.3 Digimon card\" and one \"Purple Lv.4 Digimon card\".[3]",
      "question": "Q: Which cards can be played by this card's [Main] effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. Even if the Digimon is blocked, if you declared an attack against your opponent, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack my opponent with this Digimon. If they block it with one of their Digimon, does this Digimon's effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-03": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card is placed in your trash before the effect can activate. It\u2019s no longer in your battle area, so it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and an opponent\u2019s Digimon are deleted simultaneously. Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this Digimon to a [Gallantmon] in my hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated if my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. This card is placed in your trash before the effect can activate. It\u2019s no longer in your battle area, so it doesn't activate.[1]",
      "question": "Q: A Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards and an opponent\u2019s Digimon are deleted simultaneously. Does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No, it's treated as a normal Digimon once it comes into play.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If I use this card's effect to play this Digimon, is it treated as a Security Digimon even in my battle area?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played before your opponent's next security check.   Likewise, this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect activates before your opponent\u2019s next checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check and battles the attacking Digimon as a Security Digimon. Once the battle ends, the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?   Also, when does this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect activate?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I play this card using its [Security] effect. If the attacking Digimon has 4000 DP or less and \uff1cJamming\uff1e, can I use this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect to delete the attacking Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I attack an opponent\u2019s Digimon with a Digimon with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e that has this card in its digivolution cards. My Digimon deletes the opponent\u2019s Digimon and survives. When performing checks with \uff1cPiercing\uff1e, does this card\u2019s inherited effect grant \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: \u201cIf you don't\u201d refers to a state such as in which, when resolving this Digimon\u2019s [When Attacking] effect, your opponent doesn't have a Digimon with 4000 DP or less in play, or your opponent has a Digimon that can't be deleted with the effect. Essentially, if your opponent doesn't have a Digimon that can be deleted by \u201cDelete 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 4000 DP or less,\u201d follow the instructions listed after \u201cIf you don't\u201d.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect reads, \u201cDelete 1 of your opponent's Digimon with 4000 DP or less. If you don't...\u201d What does \u201cIf you don't\u201d refer to?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If you activate this card\u2019s [When Attacking] effect and your opponent has a Digimon with 4000 DP or less in play, you must choose that Digimon as the target of the effect. If a valid target exists, you must choose it.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 4000 DP or less in play. Can I choose not to delete my opponent\u2019s Digimon so that this Digimon gets +3000 DP?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If you chose your opponent\u2019s Digimon with 4000 DP or less as a target, it counts for this card\u2019s effect, even if the chosen Digimon has an effect that prevents it from being deleted.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a Digimon with 4000 DP or less and an effect that reads, \u201cThis Digimon can't be deleted by your opponent\u2019s effects,\u201d and another Digimon with 4000 DP or less but no effect. Can I intentionally choose the Digimon with the effect preventing deletion to have this Digimon gain +3000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. If the number of cards in your security stack is less than or equal to your opponent\u2019s at the time you use this card, the effect doesn't go away, even if your opponent loses security cards later.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card, and my opponent and I both have the same number of cards in our security stacks. Later, my opponent loses a security card. When this happens, do I remove \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e from this card\u2019s effect?"
    }
  ],
  "ST7-12": [
    {
      "answer": "A: You can choose any number of your opponent's Digimon, as long as the DP of the chosen Digimon adds up to 8000 or less. For example, you could choose 1 Digimon with 3000 DP + 1 Digimon with 5000 DP, or 2 Digimon with 2000 DP + 1 Digimon with 3000 DP.[1]",
      "question": "Q: What does \u201cChoose any number of your opponent's Digimon whose total DP adds up to 8000 or less\u201d mean, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. As long as the total DP of the chosen cards is 8000 DP or less, you can choose as many or as few cards as you like. However, note that you must choose a minimum of 1 Digimon with 8000 DP or less.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I choose fewer cards than possible, even if the DP of the chosen cards adds up to less than 8000?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. When [Golemon] is deleted, reducing the DP of your opponent\u2019s Digimon, this card\u2019s effect will have already finished activating. As such, you cannot choose additional Digimon with this card\u2019s effect midway.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent has a [BT4-066 Golemon] in play. If [BT4-066 Golemon] is chosen as part of this card\u2019s effect, [BT4-066 Golemon]\u2019s deletion will cause my opponent\u2019s black Digimon to each receive -1000 DP. Can I choose more of my opponent\u2019s Digimon with this card\u2019s effect to cover the gap to reach 8000 DP?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The inherited effect activates as soon as you have 8 cards in your hand, so the Digimon gets +1000 DP for the rest of the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in my hand. I attack with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards, and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e from the [When Attacking] effect. I now have 8 cards in my hand. Can I use this card\u2019s inherited effect during the attack to gain 1000 DP for the battle and future security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The inherited effect activates as soon as you have 8 cards in your hand, so the Digimon gets +1000 DP for the rest of the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in my hand. I attack with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards, and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e from the [When Attacking] effect. I now have 8 cards in my hand. Can I use this card\u2019s inherited effect during the attack to gain 1000 DP for the battle and future security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I digivolve this Digimon to an [UlforceVeedramon] in my hand when an effect to digivolve one of my Digimon is activated if my opponent has a level 6 or higher Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If you have this card\u2019s inherited effect activate after \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e, you'll have 8 cards in your hand at the time of activation, allowing you to return your opponent\u2019s card to their hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in my hand. I attack with a Digimon that has this card in its digivolution cards, and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e from another [When Attacking] effect. I now have 8 cards in my hand. Can I use this card\u2019s inherited effect during the attack to return 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon to its owner\u2019s hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect activate when I play this card with its [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played before your opponent's next security check.   Likewise, this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect activates before your opponent\u2019s next checks.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check and battles the attacking Digimon as a Security Digimon. Once the battle ends, the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Is this card played off its [Security] effect first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?   Also, when does this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The inherited effect activates as soon as you have 8 cards in your hand, so the Digimon gets \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e for the rest of the attack.[1]",
      "question": "Q: When I had 7 cards in my hand, I attacked with a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e activated from a [When Attacking] effect. I now have 8 cards, so does that attack perform a security check with this card's inherited effect of \uff1cSecurity A. +1\uff1e?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: If you attack with this Digimon, your opponent's Digimon can't change the target of attack by activating \uff1cBlocker\uff1e.[1]",
      "question": "Q: \u201cThis Digimon can't be blocked.\u201d How does this effect work, exactly?"
    }
  ],
  "ST8-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. If you have this card\u2019s effect activate after \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e, you'll have 8 cards in your hand at the time of activation, allowing you to unsuspend this Digimon.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I have 7 cards in my hand. I attack with this Digimon, and \uff1cDraw 1\uff1e from its [When Attacking] effect. I now have 8 cards in my hand. Does this card\u2019s effect cause this Digimon to become unsuspended?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-01": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself blue, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself blue, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-02": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \"Reveal the top 3 cards of your deck,\" so if possible, you must reveal 3 cards. If you have fewer than 3 cards left in your deck, reveal as many as you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect force me to reveal 3 cards from the top of my deck?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes. The effect reads, \u201cAdd 1 card...to your hand,\u201d so if you reveal a card that meets the requirements, you must add it to your hand.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card's [On Play] effect reveals cards from the top of my deck. If I reveal a card with [Free] in its traits, do I have to add it to my hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-04": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself green, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself green, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-05": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself green, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself green, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-06": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The effect reads, \u201cyou may,\u201d so you can choose whether to play them.\u3000However, if you choose to play them, you must play as many cards as possible.  If there are both a level 4 or lower blue Digimon card and a level 4 or lower green Digimon card in the digivolution cards, you can't choose to only play one of them.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If there\u2019s both a level 4 or lower blue Digimon card and a level 4 or lower green Digimon card in this Digimon\u2019s digivolution cards, does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect require me to play both of them?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-07": [
    {
      "answer": "A: No. The [When Attacking] effect activates before reaction timing, which is when \uff1cBlocker\uff1e triggers. By the time reaction timing occurs, this Digimon no longer has \uff1cBlocker\uff1e, so it cannot block.[1]",
      "question": "Q: My opponent attacks with a Digimon and deletes my only blue Digimon with its [When Attacking] effect. I have no other blue Digimon in play, but can I still block the attack with this Digimon?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-08": [
    {
      "answer": "A: At the end of your turn, this effect allows you DNA digivolve a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards, along with one of your other Digimon, into a Digimon in your hand that has [DNA Digivolution]. Note that this happens before it becomes your opponent\u2019s turn.[1]",
      "question": "Q: How does this card\u2019s inherited effect work, exactly?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve into a Digimon card that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution].[1]",
      "question": "Q: With this card's inherited effect, can I DNA digivolve into a Digimon card in my hand that doesn\u2019t have [DNA Digivolution]?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No. You can\u2019t ignore the digivolution requirements, so you can\u2019t DNA digivolve using Digimon that aren\u2019t specified in [DNA Digivolution].[2]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card's inherited effect allow me to DNA digivolve into a card other than the Digimon specified by [DNA Digivolution] in the hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-09": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, if a Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself blue, the effect activates.[1]",
      "question": "Q: If the Digimon with this card in its digivolution cards is itself blue, does this card\u2019s inherited effect activate?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-10": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, regardless of the battle's outcome, you get to play this Digimon at the end of the battle.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Can I play this Digimon with its [Security] effect even if it loses the battle against the attacking Digimon?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, it does.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [On Play] effect activate when played with this card\u2019s [Security] effect?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: This Digimon is played after the battle with the attacking Digimon, and before the next check is performed.  Likewise, this Digimon\u2019s [On Play] effect activates before your opponent\u2019s next check.[1]",
      "question": "Q: This card is flipped over during a security check, but the attacking Digimon still has security checks remaining. Does this Digimon\u2019s effect activate first, or do I have to wait until my opponent finishes the rest of their security checks?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-11": [
    {
      "answer": "A: When performing a non-DNA digivolution, only the \u201cSuspend 1 of your opponent\u2019s Digimon\u201d part of the effect activates. The part of the effect that reads, \u201cthat Digimon doesn't unsuspend during its owner\u2019s next unsuspend phase\u201d only activates when DNA digivolving.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s [When Digivolving] effect activate when performing a non-DNA digivolution?"
    },
    {
      "answer": "A: No, only the colors of the top card are counted. If the card is a mono-colored Digimon card, it will be counted as a single color, even if its digivolution cards are different colors.[1]",
      "question": "Q: Does this card\u2019s inherited effect also count the colors of its digivolution cards?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-14": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to suspend 1 of my opponent\u2019s Digimon. Can I then use this effect to return a different suspended Digimon to its owner\u2019s hand?"
    }
  ],
  "ST9-15": [
    {
      "answer": "A: Yes, you can.[1]",
      "question": "Q: I use this card\u2019s effect to give 1 of my Digimon +2000 DP. Can I then use this effect to give another Digimon \uff1cPiercing\uff1e?"
    }
  ]
}